<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Ekynoxe - Web development in London</title>
        <description>Mathieu Davy's one man web studio</description>
        <link>http://ww.ekynoxe.com</link>
        <atom:link href="http://ww.ekynoxe.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2014 21:32:36 +0000</pubDate>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2014 21:32:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        
            <item>
                <title>Every Day Training Camp - Pre-camp</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re on the eve of going away with Ellen to what should be an awesome week of riding, running and swimming in the sunshine of Lanzarote.
However, there&amp;rsquo;s been a few little hicups in the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-07-every-day-training-camp-pre-camp/travelling.jpg&quot; title=&quot;travelling&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[20140307]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-07-every-day-training-camp-pre-camp/travelling_r500.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;travelling&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;A month ago, I managed to get tonsillitis, which lingered on and on and on until I finally managed to get some antibiotics from my GP&amp;hellip; Last Wednesday. Training has therefore been ridiculously minimal for the last 3 weeks&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week, Ellen found out that she&amp;rsquo;s got a stress fracture in her right foot, and is now walking around in an air cast. Not that this will discourage her from riding the hills on the volcano island!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this morning I managed to crash heavily, all on my own, going to work, and my right ribs are now painful&amp;hellip; Nothing is broken, I can still move, lift and do most things, but we&amp;rsquo;ll see tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So instead of two healthy and strong athletes going for a week of proper training camp, we&amp;rsquo;re now two cripples going for rehab!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully we&amp;rsquo;ll manage to do a few of the activities planned. It seems that there&amp;rsquo;s some sunshine at least!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2014 21:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://ww.ekynoxe.com/every-day-training-camp-pre-camp</link>
                <author>hello@ekynoxe.com (Mathieu Davy)</author>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ww.ekynoxe.com/every-day-training-camp-pre-camp</guid>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>It's YOUR race</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The triathlon race season will start again soon here in the UK, and with the plethora of winter running races and other duathlons available — not to mention overseas racing — I can see a lot of my friends and twitter buddies getting in some fast action over the week-ends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, I noticed a trend lately: this also comes with plenty of them doubting themselves for the goals they have set a long way back. For most, they&amp;rsquo;ve been reasonable in setting those up, so it&amp;rsquo;s all about confidence and re-adjustment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;


&lt;p&gt;In one of his &lt;a href=&quot;http://triathlete-europe.competitor.com/tag/steven-lord&quot;&gt;latest columns in Triathlete Europe&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://triathlete-europe.competitor.com/2014/02/19/steven-lord-blog-challenges&quot;&gt;Steven Lord described the &amp;ldquo;challenges&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; that plenty of us hop-on during our athletic life, and ultimately, draws on the conclusion that those challenges are useful only if they bring a purpose to a training / racing season, and more importantly, not injure ourselves in the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe it should be the same for setting up — and reviewing — your next goals:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set them up as well as you can, based on known ability and a reasonable outcome from your training programme. You must set them high enough so that there is a chance you could not quite make them, but low enough so that the chance of failure is only that: a chance. If you can put in the correct work, you WILL achieve them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You don&amp;rsquo;t have to kill yourself to finish an event (or a training session for that matter!). Chances are that if you&amp;rsquo;re not an elite or a pro, you are in the racing to have a target to aim for and enjoy the journey. Not prize money. If your aim is to qualify for some world championship events or similar, then that qualification should carry a tag reading &amp;ldquo;possibility of not achieving&amp;rdquo;, and you should be fine with that.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t compare yourself to other, much faster athletes. Unless you compare yourself with your training buddies who you know are quite evenly matched to you. There&amp;rsquo;s no point dwelling on the fact that you&amp;rsquo;ll never be a sub 9h ironman, or a 3h marathon runner etc etc&amp;hellip; Know where you stand, and be happy with what you can achieve. Whether it&amp;rsquo;s running a 5K or finishing an ironman, you&amp;rsquo;ll be an achiever, and identical on this point.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t be afraid of changing those goals. Ever. Again: not an elite? Then complete before compete. If life or injury comes in the mix of your training, you can adjust your results prospects to something more manageable and / or more achievable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be definitely prepared for not achieving those goals. But please don&amp;rsquo;t see that as a failure. You don&amp;rsquo;t fail when you train your butt off as close to the plan as possible. You don&amp;rsquo;t fail when you miss a training session. You don&amp;rsquo;t fail when you don&amp;rsquo;t quite get under the fictitious time bar you set yourself either. You may be disappointed a little bit, but you should never be disheartened, or dejected at the sport. If you are, then it&amp;rsquo;s a sign that you&amp;rsquo;re not enjoying it any-more and you need to re-focus and dial it down. Think about the journey and what that brings you. The end goal is a mere pretext to be on the journey.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m frequently told that what I do is fast and furious, top level stuff. No. It&amp;rsquo;s not. My personal goals may not be the same than yours or other people out there, but I&amp;rsquo;m still sticking to the above points. I am a bit disappointed with myself when I can&amp;rsquo;t do a training session, but all in all I reflect on past experiences and shrug it out: because it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter! I have not reached some goals in the past, and will definitely not reach many more in the future. It&amp;rsquo;s part of the training / racing process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not convinced? Here are some personal examples:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learn lessons:&lt;/strong&gt; In July 2011, I &lt;a href=&quot;http://tri.ekynoxe.com/hillingdon-sprint-or-my-first-dnf/&quot;&gt;DNF'ed at a local race&lt;/a&gt; because my rear mech went through my rear wheel on the last lap of the bike, a mile from the finish line (Hillingdon sprint is ran in a strange swim-run-bike format). I didn&amp;rsquo;t fall, I only skidded with a locked back wheel and stopped. I obviously couldn&amp;rsquo;t ride the bike any-more, but instead of walking that remaining mile to the finish, I made the mistake to take a lift from one of the marshals. That&amp;rsquo;s my biggest mistake to date and it won&amp;rsquo;t happen again.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Revise goals:&lt;/strong&gt; In 2012 &lt;a href=&quot;/the-outlaw-triathlon-2012-the-long-walk/&quot;&gt;I raced the Outlaw&lt;/a&gt;. I had a knee injury entering the race and I knew it full well. My very initial goal before injury was to go sub 10h overall. This couldn&amp;rsquo;t happen any-more. I thought I&amp;rsquo;d then try smash the bike in a proper long time trial before checking what would be left in the tank on the &amp;ldquo;run&amp;rdquo;. The conditions on the day, and my knee, didn&amp;rsquo;t let it happen either. Then I shuffled / walked the whole marathon. Some medics and volunteers at aid stations on the run course were drawing me to ambulances as I had been walking for ages, telling me the end of the lap wasn&amp;rsquo;t far if I needed to pull out. I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to, and I didn&amp;rsquo;t. My end time wasn&amp;rsquo;t too bad, although almost 2h slower than initially planned, but that didn&amp;rsquo;t matter. I had revised my goals, and I finished!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have a plan:&lt;/strong&gt; In 2013, &lt;a href=&quot;/ironman-lanzarote-2013-race-report/&quot;&gt;I did Ironman Lanzarote&lt;/a&gt;. I didn&amp;rsquo;t have other goals than to complete in the first place, but still, I injured my left ankle in training, and I simply couldn&amp;rsquo;t run, at all, for about 7 weeks. I only resumed some running with just about month before the race. The strategy therefore had to change, and after a great bike ride, I ran / walked the marathon. Definitely not what I wanted to do, and definitely not doing well for me not wanting to look like &amp;ldquo;another one who smashed the bike and blew up on the run&amp;rdquo;. But it was the plan! The hardest bit was to explain to people on course that I was absolutely fine and walking was intentional to relieve my ankle. I ran / walked and I still finished strong.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;At the end of the day, you are probably your hardest judge and critic. I live with someone who&amp;rsquo;s the harshest on herself I have ever seen anyone be, and I know very well that it&amp;rsquo;s hard not to be like this when you&amp;rsquo;re as determined as we all are in the sport. Talk to your fellow athletes friends and club-mates, let it all out there and listen to the feedback and advice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you can compete, that&amp;rsquo;s great, but before all, make sure you complete YOUR race with what you have at the time. And be happy with the result whatever it is, because you will know you have planned to do just that.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2014 18:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://ww.ekynoxe.com/its-your-race</link>
                <author>hello@ekynoxe.com (Mathieu Davy)</author>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ww.ekynoxe.com/its-your-race</guid>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>SO46 replacement mech hanger</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week I stupidly fell with my in the corridor at home. The new floor is some kind of plastic tilling that makes walking with cleats extremely slipper. Long story short: I fell ON my bike, with a backpack, and in the process bent and cracked the mech hanger on my Old Focus Variado 2007.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is an old bike, and like with many old things, finding parts is close to impossible. The hanger reference I needed is SO46, but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find it anywhere on-line, and even the manufacturer in US sent me back to &lt;a href=&quot;http://wheelsmfg.com/derailleur-hanger-42.html&quot;&gt;Wheels Manufacturing Inc.&lt;/a&gt; to check if they could help me. Unfortunately, I had no luck anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking at several models on-line, I found a few close matches and ordered three, including one supposedly for Bianchi bikes that looked very close. Funny enough, it&amp;rsquo;s a Evans that I found what I needed, and the only one who had them in stock!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-15-so46-replacement-mech-hanger/replacement_for_SO46_choice.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Replacement choice: two WMFG and one Bianchi... for a focus Bike&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[20140215]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-15-so46-replacement-mech-hanger/replacement_for_SO46_choice_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Replacement choice: two WMFG and one Bianchi... for a focus Bike&quot; /&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;small&gt;Replacement choice&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;None of the three were a perfect fit straight away. Both the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.evanscycles.com/products/bianchi/hanger-01-02-ec009107&quot;&gt;Bianchi&lt;/a&gt; or the &lt;a href=&quot;http://wheelsmfg.com/derailleur-hanger-41.html&quot;&gt;WMFG 41&lt;/a&gt; needed their top to be milled to properly align the bolt hole with the frame, while the &lt;a href=&quot;http://wheelsmfg.com/derailleur-hanger-42.html&quot;&gt;WMFG 42&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ldquo;only&amp;rdquo; needed the ridge to be removed. While the Bianchi seemed overall a closer fit, it also seemed weaker than the other two, so I elected to take the ridge out of the WMFG42. I took about 10 minutes with a mini drill, a cutting disc and some milling heads, but it went on without much of a problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if you have a bike that needs a hanger reference SO46, you can use a &lt;a href=&quot;http://wheelsmfg.com/derailleur-hanger-42.html&quot;&gt;Wheels MFG #42&lt;/a&gt; and remove the ridge. I&amp;rsquo;m posting this here because I know that if I break it again, I&amp;rsquo;ll have a place to look back for clues as to which one to get!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-15-so46-replacement-mech-hanger/WMG42_for_SO46.jpg&quot; title=&quot;A bit of disc and milling action&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[20140215]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-15-so46-replacement-mech-hanger/WMG42_for_SO46_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A bit of disc and milling action&quot; /&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;small&gt;A bit of disc and milling action&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-15-so46-replacement-mech-hanger/WMG42_for_SO46_mounted.jpg&quot; title=&quot;As new! Well, almost.&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[20140215]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-15-so46-replacement-mech-hanger/WMG42_for_SO46_mounted_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;As new! Well, almost.&quot; /&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;small&gt;As new! Well, almost.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



</description>
                <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2014 20:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://ww.ekynoxe.com/so46-replacement-mech-hanger</link>
                <author>hello@ekynoxe.com (Mathieu Davy)</author>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ww.ekynoxe.com/so46-replacement-mech-hanger</guid>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>2014 Iceman off-road duathlon</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Race 3 of the Human race off road series was the Iceman. Held on January 25th 2014, I was expecting a lot colder conditions than at the previous races, but it was in fact quite mild, and instead of ice&amp;hellip; we had mud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-07-2014-iceman-off-road-duathlon/iceman_mud.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Iceman: Done! (photo Marsha El-Hage)&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[20131117]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-07-2014-iceman-off-road-duathlon/iceman_mud_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Iceman: Done! (photo Marsha El-Hage)&quot; /&gt;&lt;span&gt;Iceman: Done!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;small&gt;(photo Marsha El-Hage)&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;!--more--&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I was slightly disappointed that the Mudman was in fact the &amp;ldquo;Hillman&amp;rdquo;, and there was barely any mud to contend with. Not that my MTB skills at the time could have coped, but I wanted to get dirty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has now been done! Coming out of the iceman, I was properly covered in sticky black stuff, and grinning from ear to ear from having tamed a proper slippery course. 4th proper mountain bike ride at speed, and finally some deep mud!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the weather was so horrendous for the few weeks before the race with flooding everywhere, I elected to steal Ellen&amp;rsquo;s wheels, since they had Contis Mountain King on them, which, even if not proper mud tyres, would work better than my shallower studded ones.
I had a chuckle looking at them with their reflectors and chain guard, but that would prove the point that the machine doesn&amp;rsquo;t play a massive role in having a great race.
At more than 13Kg, I have a heavy entry level bike complete with reflectors and bell. It&amp;rsquo;s obviously no match for full carbon bikes like &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/JohnBrame&quot; title=&quot;John Brame on Twitter&quot;&gt;John&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; Rose Psycho Path that weighs the best part of 6Kg less (!), but I&amp;rsquo;m having fun :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the morning of the race, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t feeling that well rested after a week of hard training, but the weather helped a lot in feeling better. This time, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t windy or too cold, and the sun was making an appearance, so there would only be a lot of mud to contend with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After waving the RGActive peeps good luck for their trail run, I started the first run conservatively and not too close from the front of the pack. That was intentional so I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t get too carried away on the first lap. I felt tired on that first leg, and I my left ankle was getting a little twitchy again, so I wanted to be in control of my run. It was pretty hard to start with, with a lot of people around making it difficult to look where to land my feet. But after the first lap I settled into a nice rhythm, including the hills which I mostly walked to make sure I didn&amp;rsquo;t cramp later on in the race. There was a lot of mud and deep puddles that I initially mostly managed to avoid before being inevitably being covered in mud and not caring any-more.
Compared to the Mudman, the course this time had a nicer mix of short very steep hills and long flat-ish portions on which it was possible to recuperate a little bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took my time in T1 as usual. I&amp;rsquo;m in those races for the fun of it, and I was feeling al-right after the run &amp;ldquo;warm-up&amp;rdquo;. Strangely however the bike started with my legs screaming. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure why, maybe the lack of brick practice or the week of training, but it took me a little time to settle in any kind of pace. The going went easier and easier each lap and it was fantastic to be greeted every time by the ever cheerful &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/RGActive&quot; title=&quot;RGActive on Twitter&quot;&gt;RGActive crew&lt;/a&gt;. No D3 friends this time, but those guys more than make up for it!
There were some deep mud and water sections on/in which I had never ridden before, so I had a few hairy moments where my front or back wheel would slide away from under the bike, but I clung on and didn&amp;rsquo;t fall off this time. It was, on the whole, more technical than the previous races, but like the run, had short steep climbs and longer rolling sections.
Being less relentless than the Mudman, but having great terrain variety and still keeping a nice forest feel throughout the course, that is so far ma favourite ride of the series.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I only had to un-clip once on one of the steep hills as I was in the wrong gear when someone stopped dead in front of me. But that was almost at the top of the climb so that didn&amp;rsquo;t hinder my progress too much.
With the winter turbo training, I have now a lot more power in my legs than when the series started, and I can really feel it since I can power up hills rather than having to push the bike.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only issue I had (again) on the ride was that I was almost unable to take my bottle out of it&amp;rsquo;s cage. I really need to change that one for racing, but I don&amp;rsquo;t want to lose a bottle. Any suggestions?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the 3rd lap, although sometimes caught up in the midst of people one lap down, I kept picking up places regularly, and was feeling better and better.
T2 was a welcome short break before heading out on the final run lap, but I was quite surprised at the low number of bikes in there. There were about 25 bikes in the whole transition area when I arrived, so I wasn&amp;rsquo;t far off the front!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I felt tired on first run and couldn&amp;rsquo;t settle initially because of the amount of people around, it was a stark contrast on the last leg, and I was happy to be almost alone for the whole of the second one. Legs were now feeling fine (well, aside the normal race tightness at this stage), and I powered through that last leg, picking up everyone I had in sight. In fact, I picked up 7 places between T2 and the finish, feeling good in the process, so it proves that the strategy to start easy is paying off well!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m glad it&amp;rsquo;s over, but I enjoyed this one a lot more than the Mudman which was a little too hard for comfort at the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s now only one race left in the series, and after increasing my ranking every time through the first three races, I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to see how far up the series leader boards I can go! I&amp;rsquo;m now 17th overall, 5th in my age group, so it&amp;rsquo;s not too bad for a first dab into off-road racing so far!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;table_container&quot;&gt;
    &lt;table&gt;
        &lt;thead&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
                &lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
                &lt;th&gt;time&lt;/th&gt;
                &lt;th&gt;GPS data&lt;/th&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;/thead&gt;
        &lt;tbody&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;Run1 (10K)&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;48'33&quot;&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;run1 data&quot; href=&quot;http://connect.garmin.com/activity/435341543&quot;&gt;data&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;T1&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;1'48&quot;&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;Bike (18K)&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;1h04'37&quot;&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;bike data&quot; href=&quot;http://connect.garmin.com/activity/435341553&quot;&gt;data&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;T2&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;1'02&quot;&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;Run2 (5K)&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;23'12&quot;&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;run2 data&quot; href=&quot;http://connect.garmin.com/activity/435341565&quot;&gt;data&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;/tbody&gt;
    &lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Total: 2h19'14&quot; (20th overall, 18th male and 6th in M30-34)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;gallery&quot;&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-07-2014-iceman-off-road-duathlon/iceman_mud.jpg&quot; title=&quot;iceman_mud_r300.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[20131117]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-07-2014-iceman-off-road-duathlon/iceman_mud_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;iceman_mud_r300.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-07-2014-iceman-off-road-duathlon/MIM14_GAG_002455.jpg&quot; title=&quot;MIM14_GAG_002455_r300.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[20131117]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-07-2014-iceman-off-road-duathlon/MIM14_GAG_002455_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;MIM14_GAG_002455_r300.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-07-2014-iceman-off-road-duathlon/MIM14_GAG_002457.jpg&quot; title=&quot;MIM14_GAG_002457_r300.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[20131117]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-07-2014-iceman-off-road-duathlon/MIM14_GAG_002457_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;MIM14_GAG_002457_r300.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-07-2014-iceman-off-road-duathlon/MIM14_GAG_002458.jpg&quot; title=&quot;MIM14_GAG_002458_r300.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[20131117]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-07-2014-iceman-off-road-duathlon/MIM14_GAG_002458_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;MIM14_GAG_002458_r300.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-07-2014-iceman-off-road-duathlon/MIM14_GAG_002853.jpg&quot; title=&quot;MIM14_GAG_002853_r300.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[20131117]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-07-2014-iceman-off-road-duathlon/MIM14_GAG_002853_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;MIM14_GAG_002853_r300.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-07-2014-iceman-off-road-duathlon/MIM14_GAG_002854.jpg&quot; title=&quot;MIM14_GAG_002854_r300.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[20131117]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-07-2014-iceman-off-road-duathlon/MIM14_GAG_002854_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;MIM14_GAG_002854_r300.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-07-2014-iceman-off-road-duathlon/MIM14_GAG_002855.jpg&quot; title=&quot;MIM14_GAG_002855_r300.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[20131117]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-07-2014-iceman-off-road-duathlon/MIM14_GAG_002855_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;MIM14_GAG_002855_r300.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-07-2014-iceman-off-road-duathlon/MIM14_ROK_000192.jpg&quot; title=&quot;MIM14_ROK_000192_r300.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[20131117]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-07-2014-iceman-off-road-duathlon/MIM14_ROK_000192_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;MIM14_ROK_000192_r300.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-07-2014-iceman-off-road-duathlon/MIM14_ROK_000193.jpg&quot; title=&quot;MIM14_ROK_000193_r300.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[20131117]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-07-2014-iceman-off-road-duathlon/MIM14_ROK_000193_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;MIM14_ROK_000193_r300.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-07-2014-iceman-off-road-duathlon/MIM14_ROK_000194.jpg&quot; title=&quot;MIM14_ROK_000194_r300.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[20131117]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-07-2014-iceman-off-road-duathlon/MIM14_ROK_000194_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;MIM14_ROK_000194_r300.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-07-2014-iceman-off-road-duathlon/MIM14_ROK_001637.jpg&quot; title=&quot;MIM14_ROK_001637_r300.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[20131117]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-07-2014-iceman-off-road-duathlon/MIM14_ROK_001637_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;MIM14_ROK_001637_r300.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-07-2014-iceman-off-road-duathlon/MIM14_ROK_001638.jpg&quot; title=&quot;MIM14_ROK_001638_r300.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[20131117]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-07-2014-iceman-off-road-duathlon/MIM14_ROK_001638_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;MIM14_ROK_001638_r300.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-07-2014-iceman-off-road-duathlon/MIM14_ROK_001639.jpg&quot; title=&quot;MIM14_ROK_001639_r300.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[20131117]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-07-2014-iceman-off-road-duathlon/MIM14_ROK_001639_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;MIM14_ROK_001639_r300.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-07-2014-iceman-off-road-duathlon/MIM14_TOM_003466.jpg&quot; title=&quot;MIM14_TOM_003466_r300.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[20131117]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-07-2014-iceman-off-road-duathlon/MIM14_TOM_003466_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;MIM14_TOM_003466_r300.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-07-2014-iceman-off-road-duathlon/MIM14_TOM_003467.jpg&quot; title=&quot;MIM14_TOM_003467_r300.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[20131117]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-07-2014-iceman-off-road-duathlon/MIM14_TOM_003467_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;MIM14_TOM_003467_r300.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-07-2014-iceman-off-road-duathlon/MIM14_TOM_003468.jpg&quot; title=&quot;MIM14_TOM_003468_r300.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[20131117]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-07-2014-iceman-off-road-duathlon/MIM14_TOM_003468_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;MIM14_TOM_003468_r300.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-07-2014-iceman-off-road-duathlon/MIM14_TOM_003469.jpg&quot; title=&quot;MIM14_TOM_003469_r300.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[20131117]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-07-2014-iceman-off-road-duathlon/MIM14_TOM_003469_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;MIM14_TOM_003469_r300.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-07-2014-iceman-off-road-duathlon/MIM14_TOM_003977.jpg&quot; title=&quot;MIM14_TOM_003977_r300.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[20131117]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-07-2014-iceman-off-road-duathlon/MIM14_TOM_003977_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;MIM14_TOM_003977_r300.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-07-2014-iceman-off-road-duathlon/MIM14_TOM_003978.jpg&quot; title=&quot;MIM14_TOM_003978_r300.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[20131117]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-07-2014-iceman-off-road-duathlon/MIM14_TOM_003978_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;MIM14_TOM_003978_r300.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-07-2014-iceman-off-road-duathlon/MIM14_TOM_003979.jpg&quot; title=&quot;MIM14_TOM_003979_r300.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[20131117]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-07-2014-iceman-off-road-duathlon/MIM14_TOM_003979_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;MIM14_TOM_003979_r300.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-07-2014-iceman-off-road-duathlon/MIM14_TOM_004315.jpg&quot; title=&quot;MIM14_TOM_004315_r300.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[20131117]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-07-2014-iceman-off-road-duathlon/MIM14_TOM_004315_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;MIM14_TOM_004315_r300.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-07-2014-iceman-off-road-duathlon/MIM14_TOM_004316.jpg&quot; title=&quot;MIM14_TOM_004316_r300.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[20131117]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-07-2014-iceman-off-road-duathlon/MIM14_TOM_004316_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;MIM14_TOM_004316_r300.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;



</description>
                <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2014 23:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://ww.ekynoxe.com/2014-iceman-off-road-duathlon</link>
                <author>hello@ekynoxe.com (Mathieu Davy)</author>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ww.ekynoxe.com/2014-iceman-off-road-duathlon</guid>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>2013 mudman off-road duathlon</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;November 7th 2013: Human race off road duathlon series, race #2. 4 weeks ago was the Wildman and I thought it was hard. Pah! The Mudman was on another level. I&amp;rsquo;ve since been told that this one would be the hardest of the series, so it reassures me that the increasing difficulty isn&amp;rsquo;t a trend as the season progresses, otherwise we&amp;rsquo;d have to prepare harnesses and ropes for the last one!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-12-07-2013-mudman-off-road-duathlon/bike1-kib.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Bike: end of lap 1 (Photo Simon Kibble)&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[6423]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-12-07-2013-mudman-off-road-duathlon/bike1-kib_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Bike: end of lap 1 (Photo Simon Kibble)&quot; /&gt;&lt;span&gt;Bike: end of lap 1&lt;br /&gt;&lt;small&gt;(photo Simon Kibble)&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;!--more--&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Set on other MOD grounds than where the Wildman was, this race goes up and down a very steep ridge about 6 times on the run, and tackles it a couple of times on each lap of the bike. A course not for the faint hatred, but that many relish and come out of tired, but with the biggest grin ever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This time I had company from my D3 Club members as Sarah, Christine and Dan were there as well, most of them not having ridden an MTB for ages, Christine even claiming her old one back from her children to do the race. What a fantastic bunch I have as club mates!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class='gallery'&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-12-07-2013-mudman-off-road-duathlon/MUM13_BEL_002412.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Sarah&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[6423]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-12-07-2013-mudman-off-road-duathlon/MUM13_BEL_002412_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sarah&quot; /&gt;&lt;span&gt;Sarah&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-12-07-2013-mudman-off-road-duathlon/MUM13_BEL_002525.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Christine&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[6423]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-12-07-2013-mudman-off-road-duathlon/MUM13_BEL_002525_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Christine&quot; /&gt;&lt;span&gt;Christine&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-12-07-2013-mudman-off-road-duathlon/MUM13_BEL_002361.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Dan&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[6423]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-12-07-2013-mudman-off-road-duathlon/MUM13_BEL_002361_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Dan&quot; /&gt;&lt;span&gt;Dan&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;On my side, having re-started training properly a couple of weeks before this race, I was feeling a little more confident than on the Wildman, but I still don&amp;rsquo;t have great MTB skills, this race essentially being my second technical MTB ride ever.
I managed to fall only once on a 90deg turn on sand. The front wheel folded. Splat! No harm, just a bit of sand to remove from the brake callipers afterwards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having sweated like anything on the Wildman, and (I think) paid for it on the second run with massive cramps, I elected to go a lot lighter this time. &amp;ldquo;Only&amp;rdquo; two tri shorts for padding, compression gear to protect a bit from the splashes, and only a long sleeve and my tri top. That worked perfectly well in the Wildman, but I did underestimate the amount of heating up that would go on during the first run.
I never did proper duathlons either, so I didn&amp;rsquo;t know. Now, being a lot lighter without all those extra layers, it feels easier too!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The race was also pretty dry. It should really have been the &amp;ldquo;Hillman&amp;rdquo; rather than the Mudman. With the exception of one 50m trench filled with ankle-deep cold water, plus a couple of puddles here and there, it was all dry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started close to the front this time, but very conservatively. Having seen the gradients from transition, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t going to go nuts from the gun. There are 2 runs in a duathlon, and I now know I need to keep some energy for the second one!
I walked most of the steep uphills, and controlled well the downhills, only letting things go towards the bottom. 6, 7 times? Who knows, it was steep, and there were lots of it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-12-07-2013-mudman-off-road-duathlon/run1-kib.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Steep climbs (Photo Simon Kibble)&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[6423]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-12-07-2013-mudman-off-road-duathlon/run1-kib_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Steep climbs (Photo Simon Kibble)&quot; /&gt;&lt;span&gt;Steep climbs&lt;br /&gt;&lt;small&gt;(photo Simon Kibble)&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;So like plenty of others I took relatively my time to go up, and controlled the descents trying not to twist my ankle again.
It was with a bit of a relief that I reached T1, but frankly, I really wondered how I&amp;rsquo;d manage the second run after a 10mi bike ride over the same terrain!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bike was I think a bit more technical than the Wildman, with, in places narrow passages, series of humps like on a BMX track, little ridges of single-track in the middle of puddles of mud, all punctuated with the same up and down than on the first run.
And then there was the water&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I avoided it on the first run, but there was no other way on the bike than to ride through a 50m pond with freezing water. I had a thought or two of walking around, but then thought better of it and just went for it. Almost sprinting through it, the fat front tire was pushing the water aside a little, and I was moving fast. Only the last 5-10m was getting deeper, or with mud underneath which was slowing everything down. 3 laps = 3 ponds&amp;hellip; I would be wet!
Except the one super steep ascent I simply could not ride up, the bike was enjoyable and I liked the technicality of it. You just can&amp;rsquo;t get bored as it&amp;rsquo;s absolutely relentless!
Richie from the RGActive race team passed me on the second lap, smashing through being in his element, and getting up all hills on the bike. Kudos!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I loved the atmosphere and the support in places on the course. The RGActive guys pushing you from the hill tops, and trying to spot my fellow D3 club-mates. It&amp;rsquo;s great to have friends around!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starting my last lap of the bike, the front of the field was already on the run! At the time I thought that I was very far down the field, but in fact I wasn&amp;rsquo;t doing too bad. These guys were just tearing the course apart!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took my time in T2 and set off on the second run knowing full well what was ahead, but surprisingly my legs weren&amp;rsquo;t too bad. I ticked the miles one by one, and ran through the water this time. It didn&amp;rsquo;t matter anymore, and I knew I&amp;rsquo;d get warm again very quickly.
I caught up a lot of people on that run, and I trotted up all the hills. Didn&amp;rsquo;t walk any (I think), or very little, on this second run. It felt controlled and I although tired, I was happy and going quite well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a little left to sprint for the finish, but didn&amp;rsquo;t manage to catch the last guy I could see ahead of me. It turns out he also had some left, but it was great to have this race over! I ran faster by 20s on the second run and that made me very happy to have stuck to a conservative strategy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dan, Christine and Sarah were also happy to finish it off, Sarah taking a 2nd spot in her category (how am I not surprised about that?!), but Christine taking a tumble on the bike which bruised her a bit so she didn&amp;rsquo;t have the type of race she usually delivers. But all of us were happy and cheerful at the end. Glad this one was over!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2 more races to go in the series, see you at the Iceman on January 25th!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;table_container&quot;&gt;
    &lt;table&gt;
        &lt;thead&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
                &lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
                &lt;th&gt;time&lt;/th&gt;
                &lt;th&gt;GPS data&lt;/th&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;/thead&gt;
        &lt;tbody&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;Run1 (7.5K)&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;36'43&quot;&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;run1 data&quot; href=&quot;http://connect.garmin.com/activity/413148416&quot;&gt;data&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;T1&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;2'21&quot;&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;Bike (16K)&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;57'05&quot;&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;bike data&quot; href=&quot;http://connect.garmin.com/activity/413148430&quot;&gt;data&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;T2&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;2'19&quot;&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;Run2 (7.5K)&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;36'22&quot;&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;run2 data&quot; href=&quot;http://connect.garmin.com/activity/413148442&quot;&gt;data&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;/tbody&gt;
    &lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Total: 2h14'53&quot; (36th overall, 33rd male and 7th in M30-34)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class='gallery'&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-12-07-2013-mudman-off-road-duathlon/MUM13_PIJ_001616.jpg&quot; title=&quot;MUM13_PIJ_001616&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[6423]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-12-07-2013-mudman-off-road-duathlon/MUM13_PIJ_001616_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;MUM13_PIJ_001616&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-12-07-2013-mudman-off-road-duathlon/MUM13_PIJ_001617.jpg&quot; title=&quot;MUM13_PIJ_001617&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[6423]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-12-07-2013-mudman-off-road-duathlon/MUM13_PIJ_001617_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;MUM13_PIJ_001617&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-12-07-2013-mudman-off-road-duathlon/MUM13_PIJ_001618.jpg&quot; title=&quot;MUM13_PIJ_001618&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[6423]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-12-07-2013-mudman-off-road-duathlon/MUM13_PIJ_001618_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;MUM13_PIJ_001618&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-12-07-2013-mudman-off-road-duathlon/MUM13_CHG_002280.jpg&quot; title=&quot;MUM13_CHG_002280&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[6423]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-12-07-2013-mudman-off-road-duathlon/MUM13_CHG_002280_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;MUM13_CHG_002280&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-12-07-2013-mudman-off-road-duathlon/MUM13_CHG_002281.jpg&quot; title=&quot;MUM13_CHG_002281&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[6423]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-12-07-2013-mudman-off-road-duathlon/MUM13_CHG_002281_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;MUM13_CHG_002281&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-12-07-2013-mudman-off-road-duathlon/MUM13_CHG_002282.jpg&quot; title=&quot;MUM13_CHG_002282&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[6423]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-12-07-2013-mudman-off-road-duathlon/MUM13_CHG_002282_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;MUM13_CHG_002282&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-12-07-2013-mudman-off-road-duathlon/MUM13_BEL_002293.jpg&quot; title=&quot;MUM13_BEL_002293&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[6423]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-12-07-2013-mudman-off-road-duathlon/MUM13_BEL_002293_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;MUM13_BEL_002293&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-12-07-2013-mudman-off-road-duathlon/MUM13_BEL_002294.jpg&quot; title=&quot;MUM13_BEL_002294&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[6423]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-12-07-2013-mudman-off-road-duathlon/MUM13_BEL_002294_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;MUM13_BEL_002294&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-12-07-2013-mudman-off-road-duathlon/MUM13_BEL_002542.jpg&quot; title=&quot;MUM13_BEL_002542&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[6423]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-12-07-2013-mudman-off-road-duathlon/MUM13_BEL_002542_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;MUM13_BEL_002542&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-12-07-2013-mudman-off-road-duathlon/MUM13_BEL_002543.jpg&quot; title=&quot;MUM13_BEL_002543&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[6423]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-12-07-2013-mudman-off-road-duathlon/MUM13_BEL_002543_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;MUM13_BEL_002543&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-12-07-2013-mudman-off-road-duathlon/MUM13_BEL_002008.jpg&quot; title=&quot;MUM13_BEL_002008&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[6423]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-12-07-2013-mudman-off-road-duathlon/MUM13_BEL_002008_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;MUM13_BEL_002008&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-12-07-2013-mudman-off-road-duathlon/MUM13_BEL_002009.jpg&quot; title=&quot;MUM13_BEL_002009&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[6423]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-12-07-2013-mudman-off-road-duathlon/MUM13_BEL_002009_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;MUM13_BEL_002009&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-12-07-2013-mudman-off-road-duathlon/MUM13_CHG_001826.jpg&quot; title=&quot;MUM13_CHG_001826&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[6423]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-12-07-2013-mudman-off-road-duathlon/MUM13_CHG_001826_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;MUM13_CHG_001826&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-12-07-2013-mudman-off-road-duathlon/MUM13_CHG_001827.jpg&quot; title=&quot;MUM13_CHG_001827&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[6423]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-12-07-2013-mudman-off-road-duathlon/MUM13_CHG_001827_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;MUM13_CHG_001827&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-12-07-2013-mudman-off-road-duathlon/MUM13_CHG_003098.jpg&quot; title=&quot;MUM13_CHG_003098&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[6423]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-12-07-2013-mudman-off-road-duathlon/MUM13_CHG_003098_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;MUM13_CHG_003098&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-12-07-2013-mudman-off-road-duathlon/MUM13_CHG_003099.jpg&quot; title=&quot;MUM13_CHG_003099&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[6423]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-12-07-2013-mudman-off-road-duathlon/MUM13_CHG_003099_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;MUM13_CHG_003099&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-12-07-2013-mudman-off-road-duathlon/MUM13_CHG_003100.jpg&quot; title=&quot;MUM13_CHG_003100&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[6423]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-12-07-2013-mudman-off-road-duathlon/MUM13_CHG_003100_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;MUM13_CHG_003100&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-12-07-2013-mudman-off-road-duathlon/MUM13_BEL_002756.jpg&quot; title=&quot;MUM13_BEL_002756&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[6423]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-12-07-2013-mudman-off-road-duathlon/MUM13_BEL_002756_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;MUM13_BEL_002756&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-12-07-2013-mudman-off-road-duathlon/MUM13_BEL_002755.jpg&quot; title=&quot;MUM13_BEL_002755&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[6423]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-12-07-2013-mudman-off-road-duathlon/MUM13_BEL_002755_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;MUM13_BEL_002755&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-12-07-2013-mudman-off-road-duathlon/MUM13_BEL_002754.jpg&quot; title=&quot;MUM13_BEL_002754&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[6423]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-12-07-2013-mudman-off-road-duathlon/MUM13_BEL_002754_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;MUM13_BEL_002754&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-12-07-2013-mudman-off-road-duathlon/MUM13_PIJ_001796.jpg&quot; title=&quot;MUM13_PIJ_001796&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[6423]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-12-07-2013-mudman-off-road-duathlon/MUM13_PIJ_001796_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;MUM13_PIJ_001796&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-12-07-2013-mudman-off-road-duathlon/MUM13_PIJ_001797.jpg&quot; title=&quot;MUM13_PIJ_001797&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[6423]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-12-07-2013-mudman-off-road-duathlon/MUM13_PIJ_001797_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;MUM13_PIJ_001797&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-12-07-2013-mudman-off-road-duathlon/MUM13_PIJ_001798.jpg&quot; title=&quot;MUM13_PIJ_001798&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[6423]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-12-07-2013-mudman-off-road-duathlon/MUM13_PIJ_001798_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;MUM13_PIJ_001798&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-12-07-2013-mudman-off-road-duathlon/MUM13_PIJ_001799.jpg&quot; title=&quot;MUM13_PIJ_001799&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[6423]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-12-07-2013-mudman-off-road-duathlon/MUM13_PIJ_001799_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;MUM13_PIJ_001799&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
                <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://ww.ekynoxe.com/2013-mudman-off-road-duathlon</link>
                <author>hello@ekynoxe.com (Mathieu Davy)</author>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ww.ekynoxe.com/2013-mudman-off-road-duathlon</guid>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>2013 Wildman off-road duathlon</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;After last winter mostly spent indoors, stuck on a turbo or a treadmill, I thought it would be fun to mix things up and go play in the mud. Alongside registering to a silly event like the Grim challenge, I&amp;rsquo;ve also hit the button to enter the whole of the Human race winter off-road series. Moment of madness? Given how hard the first race was yesterday, probably!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-11-17-2013-wildman-off-road-duathlon/wildman.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Leaving T1 at the wildman 2013 (Photo Marsha El-Hage)&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[6398]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-11-17-2013-wildman-off-road-duathlon/wildman_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Leaving T1 at the wildman 2013 (Photo Marsha El-Hage)&quot; /&gt;&lt;span&gt;Leaving T1 at the wildman 2013&lt;br /&gt;&lt;small&gt;Photo Marsha El-Hage&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;!--more--&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;Setting the stage&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last time I had a bike which &amp;ldquo;resembled&amp;rdquo; a mountain bike was about 15 years ago. I never did a &amp;ldquo;proper&amp;rdquo; mountain bike ride with mud, rocks, lots of ups and downs and technical sections. I bought my current MTB exactly 1 month ago, and did only 70K on it around Richmond park and Wimbledon Common, both of which can be considered flat compared to the Wildman&amp;rsquo;s course.
Last time I did a duathlon (before last week-end&amp;rsquo;s Hillingdon road sprint), was my first multi-sport attempt at the London duathlon (also road based), all the way back in 2007. I had no idea, no training, and 2 years old shoes…
In other words, even with some good base fitness, the Wildman was going to be very hard!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Change of weather and kit choice&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As far as I know, last year&amp;rsquo;s Wildman was rainy, and extremely boggy. This year, it was cold, but there wasn&amp;rsquo;t too much mud. Just one patch on the long loop, and the usual pond on the 5K run. The forecast was right: the car was showing 2C when I arrived at the race, so I layered up a lot! I hate the cold, and with my track record of getting frozen to death and not choosing to wear enough kit, I decided to take no chances this time.
For bottoms, I had tri shorts under long leggings, plus my D3 tri shorts on top of it all for warmth, extra padding and to show the club colours. For the top: a Craft zero extreme wicking layer, a Helly Hansen crew long levee top to take the scratches, and my club tri top to keep the wind at bay. Short gloves under long running ones for the run, all topped with my assos early winter road gloves for the bike. (yes, that&amp;rsquo;s 3 pairs for the bike) Plus a neck buff and a winter cycle hat for the ride.
That&amp;rsquo;s quite some kit and I sweated a bit on the first run on the tail wind portions, but I was happy to have all that on. For me, that was a good choice: I started to feel the cold in the middle of the second run as the sun had disappeared. Some guys were wearing only shorts and tee-shirts. No idea how they do that!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;The course&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brutal! There&amp;rsquo;s no other word for it! The run, especially around the start, is up and down all the time, and it&amp;rsquo;s single track. There&amp;rsquo;s virtually no space to pass anyone, and you either seed yourself correctly at the start (Yeah… Like I had any idea!!), or you have to be patient in the line of runners. It opens only after a few Km, and you can then chose a bit more your line, but you&amp;rsquo;ve got to be very careful where you step. I think I may have twisted again my left ankle :-/
Also, there were essentially 4 races in one: a 10 K race, a 15K race with and without dogs, and a duathlon. The duathlon starting 20min after the first 10K race, you keep passing people on the run, some of them with their dogs, which is quite funny to watch (dogs goes right, owner goes left, both end up in the mud…), and also very nice to have as an organised event. A far cry from most of the WTC events I&amp;rsquo;ve raced this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When switching onto the bike, you do 2 laps of the long loop you&amp;rsquo;ve just ran. The same problems arise: narrow in many places, very steep in others, and impossible to pass at some points. There was one steep ascent I don&amp;rsquo;t think I saw anyone climb on their bike. I was glad I had studs under my shoes to push the bike uphill! The super cheap Wiggle DHB M-1 worked a treat!
On the second bike lap, I took a tumble on the very steep, gravely, descent. There was a photographer at the bottom and I really hope he&amp;rsquo;s got good shots of it! Not sure I want to do it again, but it must have been funny as it was quite a slo-mo one. No scrapes on me, just a bit of mud. Moving on!
Interestingly, coming from the road, I had good power on the flat-ish sections and passed a few people, but I was wayyyy too slow on the technical bits. Lack of MTB riding of course, but some of the guys there had either no brain, or the most amazing reactions and handling skills. Some were literally flying pass me on the descents, no brakes, just flat out… On the road I&amp;rsquo;m a good rider on descents. On a MTB, it looks like I&amp;rsquo;m pretty much useless!
Other than this, it was hard going, and it&amp;rsquo;s on another level compared to riding a long distance triathlon. You just cannot, at any time, settle into a rhythm. It&amp;rsquo;s all up/down, stop/go. That&amp;rsquo;s a killer! But that was the point…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second run was simply evil. The first one in comparison, even with its length, was almost easy. Ups are steep, downs are steep. I was tired, tight and I started to cramp severely after going through the freezing pond around the second km. Eventually both my adductors locked up trying to go up a bank that was so steep you needed your hands to go up it. With cramped legs, I was literally stranded there, unable to move for about a minute. Not. Nice!
I also realised 2Km from the end that the &amp;ldquo;roadwork ribbon&amp;rdquo; (the bits of red/white plastic ribbon) was indicating the route… Would have helped to realise that earlier as I took the wrong turn at some point! Dooh!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Nutrition&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ouch… You think it&amp;rsquo;s hard on a road triathlon? Try off-road! I knew it wasn&amp;rsquo;t going to be easy, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t expect it to be that hard. On the first run, maybe there&amp;rsquo;s no real place/time to take anything on except on the flatter parts on the other sir of the circuit, but on the bike, it&amp;rsquo;s just impossible unless you have everything in a camelback or stop on the side of the track to grab your bottle. My hands were so tight and painful from holding the bars that I had to stop a couple of times to extract my bottle from its cage!
On the second run (especially on that course), there was no respite from the terrain, and no aid station. So take your own, and maybe pause here and there to get something in? Mind you, on the last 5K, it&amp;rsquo;s probably too late anyway.
I also had a very strange thing happen to my drink bottle in that the powder didn&amp;rsquo;t dilute well. I used hot water in the hope to get a not-frozen bottle, but it may have triggered some sort of reaction as it went all lumpy and even blocked the nozzle. I didn&amp;rsquo;t notice until I reached that bit of the bottle mid ride, and therefore couldn&amp;rsquo;t drink anything from roughly half way in the bike leg, which didn&amp;rsquo;t help the second run and the massive cramping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Lessons learned&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Layering up worked this time! Keep it like that!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t over-do the first run, the rest of the route is just as hard and you&amp;rsquo;ll need energy!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ride more technical terrain! Lack of skills on descents compared to many others was clearly visible!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More hill work needed, both on bike and on foot. Cramping on the second run was probably due to a combination of many things. Too fast first run, lack of MTB riding and subsequent energy expenditure, nutrition not going in due to… err… terrain being to hard, etc. But more hill practice can only help.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Follow red/white plastic ribbon on the run trails so you don&amp;rsquo;t get lost! They&amp;rsquo;re not bits of litter, they&amp;rsquo;re showing you the route!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t use hot water with powdered drinks, or at least try it before a race. Not sure if it&amp;rsquo;s only the brand I use, but that&amp;rsquo;s something I&amp;rsquo;m not going to try again!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;Bring it on!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was hard. Very, very hard. Off road is relentless! There&amp;rsquo;s no time to admire the view or get lost in your own thoughts. You can&amp;rsquo;t end-up being bored on the bike, and the level is… astounding. But it was also a lot of fun! Brutal fun, but something new that I liked. Ah, and I&amp;rsquo;m not great at it, which is fantastic. So much to learn too!
This was only the first race in the series of 4. The next one is on December 7th, where a few other D3 will apparently also take part! So I&amp;rsquo;ll see you there!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;table_container&quot;&gt;
    &lt;table&gt;
        &lt;thead&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
                &lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
                &lt;th&gt;time&lt;/th&gt;
                &lt;th&gt;GPS data&lt;/th&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;/thead&gt;
        &lt;tbody&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;Run1 (10K)&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;49'11&quot;&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;run1 data&quot; href=&quot;http://connect.garmin.com/activity/404859691&quot;&gt;data&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;T1&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;1'23&quot;&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;Bike (18K)&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;1h06'50&quot;&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;bike data&quot; href=&quot;http://connect.garmin.com/activity/404859710&quot;&gt;data&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;T2&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;1'11&quot;&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;Run2 (5K)&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;28'25&quot;&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;run2 data&quot; href=&quot;http://connect.garmin.com/activity/404859733&quot;&gt;data&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;/tbody&gt;
    &lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Total: 2h27'03&quot; (50th overall, 48th male and 12th in M30-34)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class='gallery'&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-11-17-2013-wildman-off-road-duathlon/WIM213_ROK_000620.jpg&quot; title=&quot;WIM213_ROK_000620&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[6398]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-11-17-2013-wildman-off-road-duathlon/WIM213_ROK_000620_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;WIM213_ROK_000620&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-11-17-2013-wildman-off-road-duathlon/WIM213_PIJ_000172.jpg&quot; title=&quot;WIM213_PIJ_000172&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[6398]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-11-17-2013-wildman-off-road-duathlon/WIM213_PIJ_000172_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;WIM213_PIJ_000172&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-11-17-2013-wildman-off-road-duathlon/WIM213_PIJ_000173.jpg&quot; title=&quot;WIM213_PIJ_000173&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[6398]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-11-17-2013-wildman-off-road-duathlon/WIM213_PIJ_000173_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;WIM213_PIJ_000173&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-11-17-2013-wildman-off-road-duathlon/WIM213_ROK_001738.jpg&quot; title=&quot;WIM213_ROK_001738&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[6398]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-11-17-2013-wildman-off-road-duathlon/WIM213_ROK_001738_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;WIM213_ROK_001738&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-11-17-2013-wildman-off-road-duathlon/WIM213_ROK_002577.jpg&quot; title=&quot;WIM213_ROK_002577&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[6398]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-11-17-2013-wildman-off-road-duathlon/WIM213_ROK_002577_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;WIM213_ROK_002577&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-11-17-2013-wildman-off-road-duathlon/WIM213_ROK_002578.jpg&quot; title=&quot;WIM213_ROK_002578&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[6398]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-11-17-2013-wildman-off-road-duathlon/WIM213_ROK_002578_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;WIM213_ROK_002578&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-11-17-2013-wildman-off-road-duathlon/WIM213_ROK_002576.jpg&quot; title=&quot;WIM213_ROK_002576&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[6398]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-11-17-2013-wildman-off-road-duathlon/WIM213_ROK_002576_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;WIM213_ROK_002576&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-11-17-2013-wildman-off-road-duathlon/WIM213_ROK_001739.jpg&quot; title=&quot;WIM213_ROK_001739&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[6398]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-11-17-2013-wildman-off-road-duathlon/WIM213_ROK_001739_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;WIM213_ROK_001739&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-11-17-2013-wildman-off-road-duathlon/WIM213_ROK_001740.jpg&quot; title=&quot;WIM213_ROK_001740&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[6398]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-11-17-2013-wildman-off-road-duathlon/WIM213_ROK_001740_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;WIM213_ROK_001740&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-11-17-2013-wildman-off-road-duathlon/WIM213_ROK_001741.jpg&quot; title=&quot;WIM213_ROK_001741&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[6398]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-11-17-2013-wildman-off-road-duathlon/WIM213_ROK_001741_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;WIM213_ROK_001741&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-11-17-2013-wildman-off-road-duathlon/WIM213_ROK_000897.jpg&quot; title=&quot;WIM213_ROK_000897&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[6398]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-11-17-2013-wildman-off-road-duathlon/WIM213_ROK_000897_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;WIM213_ROK_000897&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-11-17-2013-wildman-off-road-duathlon/WIM213_ROK_000898.jpg&quot; title=&quot;WIM213_ROK_000898&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[6398]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-11-17-2013-wildman-off-road-duathlon/WIM213_ROK_000898_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;WIM213_ROK_000898&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-11-17-2013-wildman-off-road-duathlon/WIM213_ROK_000899.jpg&quot; title=&quot;WIM213_ROK_000899&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[6398]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-11-17-2013-wildman-off-road-duathlon/WIM213_ROK_000899_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;WIM213_ROK_000899&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-11-17-2013-wildman-off-road-duathlon/WIM213_ROK_000900.jpg&quot; title=&quot;WIM213_ROK_000900&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[6398]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-11-17-2013-wildman-off-road-duathlon/WIM213_ROK_000900_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;WIM213_ROK_000900&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
                <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://ww.ekynoxe.com/2013-wildman-off-road-duathlon</link>
                <author>hello@ekynoxe.com (Mathieu Davy)</author>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ww.ekynoxe.com/2013-wildman-off-road-duathlon</guid>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>2013: A first coached racing year. The coach, races and Results.</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;About 11 months ago I started my first personal coached plan with Jo Carritt through the training business she runs with her partner Steven Lord: Every Day Training. 10 months of discovery of what such a plan entails, of performance improvements, and ultimately discovery of myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-11-16-2013-a-first-coached-racing-year-the-coach-races-and-results/medals.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Some of 2013's medals haul&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[6392]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-11-16-2013-a-first-coached-racing-year-the-coach-races-and-results/medals_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Some of 2013's medals haul&quot; /&gt;&lt;span&gt;Some of 2013's medals haul&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;!--more--&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;Last year&amp;rsquo;s setup&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t race a lot in 2012, but given the relatively low amount of training I did, I didn&amp;rsquo;t do to bad. I set PBs in pretty much all the races I has entered early in the year. Half marathon, half ironman, sprint tri with a PB 5K along the way, and also got very close to my Olympic tri PB.
But after this fantastic start, I managed to pick up a nasty knee problem further compounded by a foot injury just a week before the Outlaw, where I initially had big hopes to crush my ironman distance best. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t to be, but I did smash my swim best time by 5 minutes and flew on the bike until having to jog/walk a 4h40 marathon to complete the event.
My last race of 2012 was the 70.3 Lanzarote at the beginning of November. With the knee and foot issues in the summer, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t too optimistic given the course profile and the expected wind, but I had a fantastic race and finished 15th of my age group. Even being the first edition of a race with a scary profile (so possibly a bit less competition than usual), 5h12' on the volcano island was a huge confidence boost, and one to culture dreams of getting closer to the top spots, where the 70.3 World Championship slots are awarded.
There and then I had set some goals: go to Vegas! It changed location since then, but although I&amp;rsquo;d really like to test myself against the Nevada desert, that&amp;rsquo;s being part of an event with some of the very best athletes that counts. It could take years, or even never happen, but I had decided I&amp;rsquo;d try to get to the level where I can qualify. Outright or more realistically through roll down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;A coached plan&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A coached plan was for me the next step in trying to achieve better than I ever had. To prove myself and others that there&amp;rsquo;s a lot more in that body of mine. Granted, some do it on their own and have the discipline to do so, but I&amp;rsquo;m one who sometimes needs a right ol' kick in the butt to get going!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With some encouraging words from Paul Smernicki from the BLL guys (Get plan. Do plan, remember? &lt;a title=&quot;Get Plan Do Plan Fly / BLL&quot; href=&quot;http://www.blacklinelondon.com/get-plan-do-plan-fly/&quot;&gt;http://www.blacklinelondon.com/get-plan-do-plan-fly/&lt;/a&gt; ), it&amp;rsquo;s with this in mind that I went on to search for a private coaching plan that would not cost me an arm and a leg, but would also be specific enough to me so it would not feel like another blanket plan some &amp;ldquo;coaches&amp;rdquo; use for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through Training Peaks and their coach/athlete matching program, I had a few good suggestions, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t get the &amp;ldquo;click&amp;rdquo; that I was after and it all felt a little too much &amp;ldquo;shark attack&amp;rdquo; rather than &amp;ldquo;getting to know each other&amp;rdquo;. It&amp;rsquo;s probably a very personal thing though, and I know TP is working very well for many out there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.everydaytraining.org.uk/&quot; title=&quot;Every Day Training&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-11-16-2013-a-first-coached-racing-year-the-coach-races-and-results/edt.png&quot; alt=&quot;Every Day Training&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Having talked to &lt;a title=&quot;Sarah Bowen on Twitter&quot; href=&quot;https://twitter.com/SportsMassageSB&quot;&gt;Sarah Bowen&lt;/a&gt; when I was in Lanzarote for the 70.3, she recommended &lt;a title=&quot;Every Day Training&quot; href=&quot;http://everydaytraining.org.uk/&quot;&gt;Every Day Training&lt;/a&gt;, as her own coach is Steven Lord. I contacted EDT after the race and got a response from Jo Carritt, who had room for another athlete to coach at the time. We discussed where I was at, and what where my goals and it felt right straight away. After a few nice exchanges by email, I had a few tests to do in each discipline to check what my current fitness was.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was early December 2012 and I haven&amp;rsquo;t looked back since.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Hitting it hard&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had not done that much volume before the last winter and, initially, the quantities that were on the plan looked massive in comparison. Especially the swim sets. I was genuinely scared to enter the pool feeling that the lifeguards would have to fish me out. I distinctly remember being in there one morning and thinking to myself that Jo was only looking to break me. That I wasn&amp;rsquo;t good enough anyway, and that I had reached the point where I should just admit defeat and dial it back to my pre-coached life. It was only a 2K set! But there were a lot of them! How more wrong could I be!?!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By keeping in mind the &amp;ldquo;get plan, do plan&amp;rdquo; moto, I got through it. I also have the chance (and sometimes the curse) to live with possibly the most self-driven person I know. Ellen has been going through this with me, and managed to cope with my initial tiredness and lack of attention to small things at home. I do know she kept it to herself at the time. I had also changed jobs recently when I started the plan and was commuting a lot more than before, so there was a lot to adjust to!!
But after the initial shock (the sought after kick in the backside) I settled into a rhythm with my eyes firmly set on my first big race of 2013: ironman Lanzarote.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before this, I managed to set a new half marathon PB at Wokingham (by 4min!!), and through a lot of turbo work (early 2013 was perfect for outdoor enthusiasts, right? Note sarcasm…), got to know myself more on the bike and have good power figures to target at the coming races.
As Jo did put it, I would have a love/hate relationship with the turbo sessions. I think it was alright initially, and except annoying the neighbours, I got on quite well with power and pedalling technique both getting better. This was early in 2013, and the weather getting better gradually helped translate this into some nice road sessions and solo TTs around Richmond park. Power work would get tedious later in the year though, going on the road to do long race prep intervals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Early in the year, I could already see the benefits of &amp;ldquo;proper&amp;rdquo; training. With 3 swims a week, 3 runs, 3 bike sessions including power development and a long ride at the week-end, it was  a lot more than anything I&amp;rsquo;d done previously, but all was going very well in all 3 disciplines. I&amp;rsquo;ve clocked more long rides and long runs than in almost the entirety of 2012, and I even started to actually enjoy running at some point, looking forward to get out of the door for a long one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Disaster?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was until the first week-end in March doing some off road hill reps, where an old injury came back. Twisting my left foot a week prior to the Outlaw 2012 had finally caught up, and I was forced to forget running (and initially also kicking in the pool), for the best part of a month. With only 1.5 months to what I thought would be the biggest race of my life, it couldn&amp;rsquo;t have been worse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But my lovely other half happens to be a physio &lt;a title=&quot;Ellen Physiotherapy&quot; href=&quot;http://www.physioellen.co.uk/ &quot;&gt;http://www.physioellen.co.uk/&lt;/a&gt;, and one who&amp;rsquo;s specialising in sports rehab. Not that I want to get injured at all, but I&amp;rsquo;m lucky to have had Ellen&amp;rsquo;s support for getting back to running. With Jo tweaking the plan and Ellen giving me some stability exercises, I slowly went back to walking fast, then using a run/walk strategy both in training and racing at Lanzarote.
That was the big race on my calendar, and even with the injury before, I still had a fantastic day concluded with a 3h29' run/walk marathon. I equaled my fastest iron distance time on a tough course, with my dad for witness. Training hard paid off big time. 10h37, 25th in AG and 117th overall. How about that for a training and rehab plans that work!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-11-16-2013-a-first-coached-racing-year-the-coach-races-and-results/lanza_2013_run_3.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Lanzarote 2013&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[6392]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-11-16-2013-a-first-coached-racing-year-the-coach-races-and-results/lanza_2013_run_3_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Lanzarote 2013&quot; /&gt;&lt;span&gt;Lanzarote 2013&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;Too much, too soon&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Lanzarote over, I then made the mistake to go too hard in the Swashbuckler two weeks afterwards. It was too close but I had registered for it a year before, well ahead of registering for Lanza 70.3 and full IM, and I was supposedly only going to have fun with the guys from my club. I actually had a fantastic race! But instead of holding back, I stupidly smashed it. And in doing so I smashed myself and had massively underestimated the drain Lanza had been. I was feeling fine in the interim 2 weeks with a very much reduced training load, and had fallen into the common trap of overdoing it. This had some bad effects on my return to training after that, feeling ran down, and not motivated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So one word of advice: listen to the coach! Mine&amp;rsquo;s clever, focused, dedicated and, boy, she knows what she&amp;rsquo;s talking about.
But that said, even if Jo has had some steering in my training and adapted some of the sessions due to my injuries, she&amp;rsquo;s never tried to stop me from doing the races I had entered, and did let me do my own mistakes. Intentionally or not, this has been very formative too, as I&amp;rsquo;m now more likely to pay attention to HOW I race as much as how often.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Be flexible&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a little bit of a breather after the Swashbuckler, my next race being 5 weeks away for the Outlaw, where I was initially only going to do the bike leg of a relay. Having done all the miles, a long race, and plenty of power work, I was very much looking forward to blitz my 112miles bike record. Unfortunately, the team runner got injured too and went on to do the bike instead, while I accepted to do the run. Initially a bit hesitant, it went on alright. It was a very hot day and I waited for the best part of 45min in the sun for our cyclist to come back, so conditions weren&amp;rsquo;t ideal. Adding to this a narrow course in places and shredding the upper of one shoe to bits at the half way mark, I can consider myself happy with a 3h17' in the end. We adapted the training plan with this goal in mind as soon as we knew we had to switch legs in the race, and Jo has done a great job there as well to accommodate the change!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;New records, but devil is in the details&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then came the long break. Long break from racing that is. 2 months far in the distance was 70.3 Zell Am See. A supposedly fast course set in beautiful Austria. With a second marathon under my belt in 7 weeks, it was with relief that the training plan adjusted a bit more towards cycling, while keeping focus on speed work for the run so I&amp;rsquo;d get a little closer to the 1h30 on the &amp;frac12; marathon. And it worked! No, It worked superbly well!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-11-16-2013-a-first-coached-racing-year-the-coach-races-and-results/0451_35135.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Zell Am See&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[6392]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-11-16-2013-a-first-coached-racing-year-the-coach-races-and-results/0451_35135_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Zell Am See&quot; /&gt;&lt;span&gt;Zell Am See&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Not only did I swim my fastest 1.9K race ever, I also biked my fastest 90K and ran my Fastest 70.3 half mara ever too! Previous record of 4h55 got destroyed in the pouring rainy of Austria, and even if 4h39' is something I&amp;rsquo;m likely to keep as a record for a while, it could have been a lot better. Transitions, transitions transitions! Something to add to your training routine if it&amp;rsquo;s not already there! It wasn&amp;rsquo;t part of mine, especially for such stupidly wet and cold conditions, and because I wanted to have a few layers on, I&amp;rsquo;ve wasted more than 13minutes in T1 and T2 combined… I should have worn something under my wetsuit, and that&amp;rsquo;s something I&amp;rsquo;ll try and correct this coming year! But I should have known before the race, and more importantly: practiced! Sicne that race, I made a point into racing with fast transitions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a sprint triathlon before my last 70.3 race of the year, it was the perfect time to practice being quick through T1 and T2. That was a fun, no pressure, race, and I had a blast to get a new sprint tri PB, while practicing swimming with layers under my wetsuit and very fast transitions required by this style of racing.
That set me up well for the last assault to a 70.3 top 10.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Icing on the cake&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;70.3 Lanzarote was a month earlier than last year, but it still felt far at the end of the racing calendar. I was still training hard and following the power intervals on the plan, but these were increasingly becoming tedious and un-motivating. It really was time for the season to end. I didn&amp;rsquo;t have as good a race as last year, feeling wise, but I reached the goals I had set to myself in the lead up: sub 5 hours over the renown hard profile of the volcano island, and a top 10 in my age group.
I&amp;rsquo;m not sure these fantastic results were expected by anyone, including myself, but even more surprisingly, the 4 slots available in M30-34 went all the way down to 11th place!
Year 1 of coaching, last race of the season, and achieving all the dreams I could think of already!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-11-16-2013-a-first-coached-racing-year-the-coach-races-and-results/IMG_3058.jpg&quot; title=&quot;IMG_3058&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[6392]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-11-16-2013-a-first-coached-racing-year-the-coach-races-and-results/IMG_3058_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_3058&quot; /&gt;&lt;span&gt;Qualifier!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;Thank you coach! Thank you very much!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10 months after I started with Jo and after thinking numerous time she&amp;rsquo;d kill me in the process, I&amp;rsquo;ve accomplished things I would have never thought I&amp;rsquo;d be able to do. At least not so soon! And for squeezing out some of the very best of myself this year, I can only thank her!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s do it all again!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m now at the end of my &amp;ldquo;rest period&amp;rdquo; and I&amp;rsquo;ve already kick-started my 2014 season with back to back week-ends of racing duathlons. Two weeks ago was the Hillingdon autumn road duathlon on their road circuit, where I&amp;rsquo;ve done too many laps on the bike and still didn&amp;rsquo;t do too bad. (My brain is now back on!)
This morning was the first off-road duathlon in the Human race series, the Wildman, just for fun! That was fantastic, and incredibly hard! Last time I rode a mountain bike was probably 15 years ago, I never did it &amp;ldquo;for real&amp;rdquo; on mud or rocky terrain, so it was a whole new experience for me! There&amp;rsquo;s plenty to learn in there as well, and although I&amp;rsquo;m not hoping to top the rankings or make it what I will do in the future, it&amp;rsquo;s a welcome change from the road boredom I experienced on those long solo power interval rides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the mean time, I&amp;rsquo;ve signed up for another year with Jo, and the first month of my training programme just arrived&amp;hellip; Chop chop!!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://ww.ekynoxe.com/2013-a-first-coached-racing-year-the-coach-races-and-results</link>
                <author>hello@ekynoxe.com (Mathieu Davy)</author>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ww.ekynoxe.com/2013-a-first-coached-racing-year-the-coach-races-and-results</guid>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Ironman 70.3 Lanzarote 2012 - Bike leg video...</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Finally!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a whole year waiting on my hard drive, I found the time to edit and upload this video from the 2012 race. The course has not changed for 2013, and hopefully won&amp;rsquo;t either for 2014. See you there!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;attachement iframe_wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;//player.vimeo.com/video/77336051?portrait=0&amp;amp;color=ff9933&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
                <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
                <link>http://ww.ekynoxe.com/ironman-70-3-lanzarote-2012-bike-leg-video</link>
                <author>hello@ekynoxe.com (Mathieu Davy)</author>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ww.ekynoxe.com/ironman-70-3-lanzarote-2012-bike-leg-video</guid>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>New Toy!</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I was bored last winter. Turbo trainer and treadmill didn&amp;rsquo;t cut it!
This year I decided I&amp;rsquo;d go play in the mud, and with this lovely entry level Boardman, I should be able to do just this!
I&amp;rsquo;m already registered to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://humanrace.co.uk/events/off-road&quot;&gt;HumanRace Off-road winter series&lt;/a&gt;, which will hopefully break the monotony of road triathlon training!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-10-17-new-toy/20131017-195900.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;ready to &amp;quot;test&amp;quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;span&gt;ready to &quot;test&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-10-17-new-toy/20131017-195917.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;first ride: done!&quot; /&gt;&lt;span&gt;first ride: done!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-10-17-new-toy/20131017-195923.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;already dirty!&quot; /&gt;&lt;span&gt;already dirty!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



</description>
                <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
                <link>http://ww.ekynoxe.com/new-toy</link>
                <author>hello@ekynoxe.com (Mathieu Davy)</author>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ww.ekynoxe.com/new-toy</guid>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Lanzarote 70.3 2013 - Hot, Windy, Hard. Yet the perfect end.</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;After Ironman 70.3 Zell Am See 5 weeks before Lanzarote, both Ellen and I fell ill for the whole of that time: never ending cold from being soaked through on race day, then frozen on the plane journey back, then in the midst of the september bug that always catches everyone out around the offices. This Lanzarote race couldn&amp;rsquo;t have been set-up worse for us, but the weather couldn&amp;rsquo;t have been more different either&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-10-13-lanzarote-70-3-2013-hot-windy-hard-yet-the-perfect-end/0526_00743.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Finish line!&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[6345]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-10-13-lanzarote-70-3-2013-hot-windy-hard-yet-the-perfect-end/0526_00743_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Finish line!&quot; /&gt;&lt;span&gt;Finish line!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;!--more--&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Given this and some knees niggles for my other half, It&amp;rsquo;s not with the highest optimism that we flew out to the volcano island once again, but it was the end of both our racing years and was always going to be a bit of a drag to get there. Also, having both won a free entry into the race, it would have been a crime not to go for some sunshine when it&amp;rsquo;s all starting to &amp;ldquo;freeze&amp;rdquo; in the UK. The race date (1 month earlier than last year) was also a perfect fit for an end of season dash with some hopes for me to get closer to the top spots.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We arrived late on Thursday evening on the island. So late in fact that we barely had time to buy something for breakfast the next day before rushing to our apartments place… That had shut almost a full hour before, right at the time we landed. The strong winds in this part of the world had already started to play tricks on us by slowing right down our plane!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a very restless night in the heat, we had little time to wander around! We went to do registration in the morning (Ellen on her bike… 65K hilly return trip in the 30kph wind to get used to the island… Yep!) to get transition kit bags and the massive bag of advertising that pretty much all went to the bin straight away. Then went back to the cheep and cheerful Puerto del Carmen to do a bit of bike/run race prep for me, then stuff said bags with our bike and run kit, before heading back to La Santa for the briefing and swimming the lap of the course. The water was like a bath, having been heated all day long, but quite choppy with the strong wind at that time of the day.
We also had the bike with us so we could rack them straight after. There was really not time for gaffing about, and for once I&amp;rsquo;m glad our &amp;ldquo;tri-machine&amp;rdquo; is well oiled and we know what to do! Talk about a busy pre-race day! Really not ideal to rest and relax the body.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taking a leaf out of  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.onehundredandthree.com/&quot; title=&quot;Norman Driskell&quot;&gt;Norman Driskell&amp;rsquo;s book&lt;/a&gt;, I had packed very light transition bags this time to minimise what I had to do in the changing tent. I wanted fast transitions, and that meant putting absolutely nothing unnecessary in the bags, which seemed to have worked! One doesn&amp;rsquo;t actually need much out there! Well, providing it&amp;rsquo;s sunny and warm that is…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back at our flat and after a spot of lunch, I had hoped my little tracker tool would work so friends and family could follow both Ellen and I easily, but since there were no live tracker available (even on the very morning of the race!!), I was sorry to admit defeat against yet another poorly run Ironman website. The main site all looks new and shiny now, but there&amp;rsquo;s still no substance to it… Anyway, it eventually went live towards the end of the race (!!), but it wasn&amp;rsquo;t very useful either since there were no bike splits either. No Tabayesco climb TT this time, why? It would have been nice to compare the two years! Utter rubbish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, back to the race, the morning drive to Club La Santa wasn&amp;rsquo;t as bad as anticipated. I&amp;rsquo;d have thought it would take me completely out of my &amp;ldquo;zone&amp;rdquo;, but it actually allowed me to wake up a little more. It may not work for all, but if you race the 70.3 and have a car on the island, I&amp;rsquo;d recommend to not bother paying premium prices at La Santa, and instead get some self catering accommodation in Puerto del Carmen and drive over. It&amp;rsquo;s a lot cheaper!! (And I really mean A LOT!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the swim leg, this year&amp;rsquo;s course had been changed from a two laps affair to a single loop in the shape of an inverted &amp;ldquo;L&amp;rdquo;. That was mostly a very good idea, which avoided the potential dangers of fast swimmers lapping the back of the age group field on the second lap, and easier to understand. However, the &amp;ldquo;kink&amp;rdquo; in the lagoon was still there, on the left side this time, right by the swim exit, and it caught a lot of people out on the first lap. It was actually about 400m in the swim, where the &amp;ldquo;pack&amp;rdquo; was still very much jolting and hustling for position, and many actually ended up walking on the sand banks by the swim exit. Not great for the rest of the swimmers, but our recce from the previous day prompted me to do the exact same thing than last year: Start in the middle, and stir away from the bank! Ellen later told me that there also has been some sort of panic and screams further down the field and that she had to swim around a large pack of stranded, walking athletes to get through. Improvements over last year, certainly, but more to be done. It will come I&amp;rsquo;m sure!
Starting around the middle of the pack, around 4/5 rows from the front, I managed to avoid much of the elbows and didn&amp;rsquo;t get too much swam over. I&amp;rsquo;m a fighter now, so don&amp;rsquo;t mess with me because I don&amp;rsquo;t back out of it anymore! After we all passed the &amp;ldquo;swim exit kink&amp;rdquo;, it all cleared out with more space for swimmers to fan out, but I kept my line and managed to swim straight at the first buoy. I would literally hit all buoys dead on this time! Big improvement!
The water was warm. Not as choppy as the previous day, but not all flat either, thanks to the strong established wind from early on in the day. This wind, combined with the rising sun, didn&amp;rsquo;t help sighting on the return from the far out buoys, but I managed to not go off route too much, only occasionally having to do corrections on the long stretch back towards the bottom of the course. There weren&amp;rsquo;t many swimmers around me anymore, which, combined with the few I could spot ahead, told me I was having a good swim, much like in Austria, where I believe I led a little group back towards the exit. I passed all buoys within centimetres this time, and I&amp;rsquo;m well chuffed for that! I&amp;rsquo;m usually wayyy out to keep clear of crazy arms, but not this time! And with a good feeling in the water, I believe it helped getting sub 30min for the very first time! The tracker says 30'09&quot;, but given that I started swimming a couple of seconds after the gun, and the timing mat was not right out the water, but a bit further up the bank from the water, I was just under 30min (Well, my watch says so! Ha!). Hap-py!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-10-13-lanzarote-70-3-2013-hot-windy-hard-yet-the-perfect-end/0526_05636.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Not struggling, promise!&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[6345]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-10-13-lanzarote-70-3-2013-hot-windy-hard-yet-the-perfect-end/0526_05636_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Not struggling, promise!&quot; /&gt;&lt;span&gt;Not struggling, promise!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;T1 was at last the quick dash I always wanted. If there was one thing I really needed to nail at this race, it was my transitions. I&amp;rsquo;ve had enough of being too slow and losing rankings like in Austria, and I&amp;rsquo;m well pleased with both of them. T1 in 2'32&quot; includes the long slog up the bank from the water, and T2 includes putting socks on and running around 100m of the track, so yay for my transitions this time! Granted there was nothing to put on in T1 but a helmet, and some peeps manage to run a half marathon without socks, but 4'42&quot; of cumulative transition time doesn&amp;rsquo;t even compare with nearly 13 minutes in Austria! I was quickly on the bike, where I really hoped my legs would do their usual wonders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-10-13-lanzarote-70-3-2013-hot-windy-hard-yet-the-perfect-end/0526_03888.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Not as happy as usual here...&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[6345]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-10-13-lanzarote-70-3-2013-hot-windy-hard-yet-the-perfect-end/0526_03888_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Not as happy as usual here...&quot; /&gt;&lt;span&gt;Not as happy as usual here...&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;They didn&amp;rsquo;t. The bike didn&amp;rsquo;t go as easy as I remembered it to be. Last year was a real breeze in comparison, and although I cramped a little on the way back at the time, it was all controlled and felt fantastic. Not this year. I wanted to keep on top of my target wattage, and it all worked well all the way after the Mirador de Haria descent, about 65Km in. Power was there, but legs weren&amp;rsquo;t, really. From the gun, they felt heavy and screaming, and the climb out of Famara, even with the tailwind, didn&amp;rsquo;t go like the previous two times I raced up it, including after 80K in the full distance in May. There was no need to panic at this point, but I really didn&amp;rsquo;t like it so early on.
The descent from Teguise to Tahiche was the first time I got a taste of my bigger gear ratio, and unlike last year I could pretty much pedal all the way down with my 11 teeth at the back. Yay! But as soon as we turned left towards Arieta, the same leg sluggishness came back in, this time a strong headwind, all the way up north the island! Nicely though, I found myself playing cat and mouse with the eventual 40-44 winner, Simon Gill as I was going past him up the inclines, and he was going past on the descents. I love the fact that he even apologised for passing me at some point saying that &amp;ldquo;he wasn&amp;rsquo;t taking the piss&amp;rdquo;, as we were exchanging positions regularly. Nice touch! It was good to have a carrot to chase along the way and also good to feel that my legs were back at this point.
They loosened up nicely just before the turnaround point at Arieta for the Tabayesco climb, which I enjoyed a lot yet again. There was a bit of a tailwind in the valley, it was a bit like a cauldron in some of the turns, and I was sweating a lot. Probably a lot more than expected, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t notice until later in the ride.
The descent from Mirador de Haria was as ever super speedy. Although I didn&amp;rsquo;t reach my last year&amp;rsquo;s top speed, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t too far off, but I wanted to be careful as there was more wind this time around. Under 58Kg rider with deep rims in 20knts of wind isn&amp;rsquo;t all the time easy, especially at 80kph down a mountain on tri bars!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s after this first set of switchbacks, in the little incline getting out of Los Valles that the first signs that something was not right appeared. My right adductor was starting to cramp, so much so that I couldn&amp;rsquo;t put much power through my right leg while sat, and even standing and pedalling in awkward positions didn&amp;rsquo;t change much to it. I managed to get on the road towards the descent to Teguise, but had to unclip and try to stretch that leg, not very successfully I have to admit.
Going through Teguise and its crap road got my mind of it, but in the strong headwind back to Famara I really had to lift off the power to manage the cramps that were now spreading to my left leg too. Horror of horrors! There was still 15K to go, and it all went tits-up after Famara, and I eventually had to stop. Yes! STOP. Unclip, apply brakes, stop bike, try to stretch. And that&amp;rsquo;s a horrible feeling! Guys from the race pass you, guys on a little training ride pass you, the local donkey passes you. And there&amp;rsquo;s nothing you can do to get back on the saddle because your legs are rock solid, locked in pain. I eventually managed to get going after the riders I passed on the climbs passed me back, and after taking in more water, salts and gels, went on to complete the ride. It was still 5minutes faster than last year, but what a shame it didn&amp;rsquo;t go as planned! Again, I was relieved to finish the bike leg and see what was left in the tank, but after such a disastrous last 20K on the bike, I really didn&amp;rsquo;t hope for much!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;T2 was fast too, and still promising given the very low number of bikes back in the stadium! As a non-pro you never know where you are in the field, but I thought there must have been around 50 bikes maximum back on the racks. That also meant an empty transition tent and another speedy exit, with my socks on! No fuel belt either, but two gels that I hoped I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t lose like I did in Austria.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The initial 7Km went quite fast. Good tailwind to go down to La Santa and the turnaround, taking on sponges and coke at every possible occasion, but I knew it would be a hard run from the moment I hit that dreaded little climb back up to the stadium. That&amp;rsquo;s where my legs went solid last year. Psychological negative effect: 100%! Just. Keep. Moving. I slowed down a little, taking smaller steps, and the premises of cramps went away. First lap done, first band collected. First gel in, some coke, some more sponges, and a good old look around me all the time to spot numbers in my age group.
I didn&amp;rsquo;t remember my AG number range, but I did spot a Danish runner about 50m behind me with a number around 250, so definitely in it. That gave me a good kick up the backside and I had him on my mind all the time from there on. I was never in this position before, but a quick glance at my watch and the race clock at the finish line told me I could just about get to 5h if I kept at it! The wheels buckled a little at the second time I passed the &amp;ldquo;hill&amp;rdquo;. This time cramps were back and I had to walk a bit. Not stop! No, I did not stop! I just took my time up that damn incline! The Dane passed me. Arghh!!! By the time I started running again he was about 100m up the road, but he was now my ultimate target. 7Km to go and only one &amp;ldquo;hill&amp;rdquo;, with one Dane to catch! Easy to spot in bright orange as well!
I picked the pace back up along the way. Nothing stellar, really, but I was trying to shelter behind faster runners on their first or second lap, and even hang on some super speedy ones for a few controlled and focused strides. It helped the pace, not so much the legs! But I hung on and past my &amp;ldquo;target&amp;rdquo; before the last turnaround in La Santa. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure he was in the same state of mind I was in, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t see him again after that. In my head were my goals for the day: top 10, and trying to get to the magic 5h mark on a hard course!
&lt;a title=&quot;Dan Phillips on twitter&quot; href=&quot;https://twitter.com/TheIngenieur&quot;&gt;Dan Phillips&lt;/a&gt; also gave me a good few shouts out on the run course and that was fantastic to see that he was having a great race as well. Plenty more in these young legs to come I&amp;rsquo;m sure!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-10-13-lanzarote-70-3-2013-hot-windy-hard-yet-the-perfect-end/0526_06488.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Last push for the line&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[6345]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-10-13-lanzarote-70-3-2013-hot-windy-hard-yet-the-perfect-end/0526_06488_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Last push for the line&quot; /&gt;&lt;span&gt;Last push for the line&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I pushed hard (I think) after the last slow jog up the hill, checked behind me for a potential sprint finish but there was no one there so I did not grunt or grimace this time and high-fived the few extended hands in the finish chute. 4h58'53&quot;: one box ticked. After a lot more cramps than usual and an up-and-down run, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t believe it, but there it was! Checking the time boards a little later told me I was 10th in my age group! Mission accomplished! I came to Lanzarote for a top 10 in my age group and a sub 5h and I got what I wanted! Happy times!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I knew Dan wasn&amp;rsquo;t too far behind, about 25min given where I was crossing him on the run lap, so I hung out in the finish area to give him a push too. I was also wondering where I could check for Ellen&amp;rsquo;s times on the bike. I had not seen her on the run course like last year. I was really gutted for her back then, but this time, she wasn&amp;rsquo;t around, so she must have been out on the bike course. I was sure she was somewhere out there giving the wind and the heat the two fingers she&amp;rsquo;s too polite to give to anyone doubting her, and I wanted to know where she was! And righty-oh she popped into the stadium at just before the 5h30 mark, 15min in the time limit of 5h45! Damn her she made my cry a little behind my sunnies for being so awesome and going do everything she aims for! Well done darling! So chuffed!
She then said: &amp;ldquo;I bloody hate this place, but I&amp;rsquo;ll be back to finish what I started!&quot;… I guess we&amp;rsquo;ll be back next year then!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dan&amp;rsquo;s friends all finished shortly after and we all figured on the live tracker as a happy group of finishers (although wrongly labeled as being from Italy!!!) Happy indeed! Tough day out there, but all go around what we had planned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-10-13-lanzarote-70-3-2013-hot-windy-hard-yet-the-perfect-end/7b29c6c8-0164-41f6-8b8e-0be1aee082b3.jpg&quot; title=&quot;All done an still smiling!&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[6345]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-10-13-lanzarote-70-3-2013-hot-windy-hard-yet-the-perfect-end/7b29c6c8-0164-41f6-8b8e-0be1aee082b3_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;All done an still smiling!&quot; /&gt;&lt;span&gt;All done an still smiling!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I was 10th in my age group and with that there was a slim chance to get a roll down world champs slot. So despite the usual itchiness and impatience of my other half, we stayed at Club La Santa after the race to go to the slot allocation. During that time, sitting around a nice steak and chips at the crowded grill in La Santa, we bumped into the Dane that finished right behind me in my age group! We exchanged a few things about the race and the placements, and of course the slot allocation. I&amp;rsquo;d have to be lucky to get one, but he was one more place down.
The women&amp;rsquo;s slot went all pretty much to the first of each age group without a hitch, but the same can&amp;rsquo;t be said for the men!
Some slots got re-allocated, and after a little bit of confusion over to which age group, it turned out during the allocation that one slot got transferred to my group! Heck, I hoped for a roll down, but the odds were getting better!
One unfortunate guy who finished on the podium in his category got denied a slot because he had selected &amp;lsquo;No&amp;rsquo; to the question &amp;ldquo;do you want to qualify for the WC&amp;rdquo; on his entry form. This, and the crazy and totally misplaced display of the Austrian guy next in line wasn&amp;rsquo;t exactly setting up the mood very well. I guess such is the way things go in a competitive field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When my group&amp;rsquo;s results came around, the first two guys took their slot. Two slots left, still 8 places from me. Given how all other age groups had gone, I though it was it! But the 3rd guy wasn&amp;rsquo;t there to accept his slot. Neither were the 4th, the 5th or the 6th! It was getting a little tense and I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure I was starting to look quite nervous at this point, because the guys across the table from where we were seated had a laugh at the fact I might get the very slot that was initially wrongly re-allocated to their AG. Number 7 wasn&amp;rsquo;t here either&amp;hellip; Just one more! And just as I said this to Ellen, my name was called! Number 8 must have said &amp;lsquo;No&amp;rsquo; on his entry form too, so I was taken by surprise!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes! Yes! Yes! I&amp;rsquo;m going! That might be my only chance! Yes! Yes! Here! Yes! Where do I sign?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-10-13-lanzarote-70-3-2013-hot-windy-hard-yet-the-perfect-end/IMG_3058.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Qualifier!&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[6345]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-10-13-lanzarote-70-3-2013-hot-windy-hard-yet-the-perfect-end/IMG_3058_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Qualifier!&quot; /&gt;&lt;span&gt;Qualifier!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;As there were 4 slots in my age group with the re-allocation, Thierry, our new Danish acquaintance got one slot as well! So we&amp;rsquo;ll meet again in Canada next year!
As crazy as it sounds, only in my age group did the slots rolled down to 11th place. Top spots claimed their slots in all other groups, including Dan&amp;rsquo;s 25-29, who got one place better than me with 9th. It will come for him I&amp;rsquo;m sure if he keeps at it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what a stroke of luck to finish this season. A really far from perfect race on the two legs I thought I didn&amp;rsquo;t think could go wrong, but all goals achieved and a nice little surprise at the end!
One year too late to say &amp;ldquo;Vegas baby!!&amp;rdquo;, but the feeling is the same. I&amp;rsquo;m going to the World Champs!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s now time to relax and enjoy some much deserved rest. This season has had a lot of ups and downs, a host of great results that are testament to a good coaching plan from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.joannacarritt.co.uk/&quot; title=&quot;Jo Carritt&quot;&gt;Jo Carritt&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;a href=&quot;http://everydaytraining.org.uk&quot; title=&quot;everydaytraining.org.uk&quot;&gt;Every Day Training&lt;/a&gt;, and some determination to take things slowly, but further than ever before. It&amp;rsquo;s exciting to prove oneself wrong on all levels of &amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t think I can do that&amp;rdquo;, and sure there&amp;rsquo;s plenty more in the bag.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Results and data&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Placements and times come from the official tracker, they might differ from the garmin data as I didn&amp;rsquo;t &amp;ldquo;press the button&amp;rdquo; right at the mats.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;table_container&quot;&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;
    &lt;/th&gt;

    &lt;th&gt;
    &lt;/th&gt;

    &lt;th&gt;
      data
    &lt;/th&gt;

    &lt;th&gt;
      overall rank
    &lt;/th&gt;

    &lt;th&gt;
      AG rank
    &lt;/th&gt;

    &lt;th&gt;
      gender rank
    &lt;/th&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;

  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      Swim (1.9K)
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td&gt;
      30'09&quot;
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td&gt;
      &lt;a title=&quot;swim data&quot; href=&quot;http://connect.garmin.com/activity/387462480&quot;&gt;swim data&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td&gt;
      111
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td&gt;
      17
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td&gt;
      92
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;

  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      T1
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td&gt;
      2'32&quot;
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td&gt;
      &lt;a title=&quot;T1 data&quot; href=&quot;http://connect.garmin.com/activity/387462484&quot;&gt;T1 data&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;

  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      Bike (90.1K)
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td&gt;
      2h48'28&quot;
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td&gt;
      &lt;a title=&quot;bike data&quot; href=&quot;http://connect.garmin.com/activity/387462495&quot;&gt;bike data&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td&gt;
      48
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td&gt;
      11
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td&gt;
      43
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;

  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      T2
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td&gt;
      5'38&quot;
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td&gt;
      &lt;a title=&quot;T2 data&quot; href=&quot;http://connect.garmin.com/activity/387462502&quot;&gt;T2 data&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;

  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      Run (21.1K)
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td&gt;
      1h35'34&quot;
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td&gt;
      &lt;a title=&quot;run data&quot; href=&quot;http://connect.garmin.com/activity/387462505&quot;&gt;run data&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td&gt;
      50
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td&gt;
      10
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td&gt;
      42
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;

  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      Finish
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td&gt;
      4h58'53&quot;
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finish Overall position: 50th, 42nd male and 10th in my age group.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class='gallery'&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-10-13-lanzarote-70-3-2013-hot-windy-hard-yet-the-perfect-end/IMG_3069.jpg&quot; title=&quot;IMG_3069&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[6345]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-10-13-lanzarote-70-3-2013-hot-windy-hard-yet-the-perfect-end/IMG_3069_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_3069&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-10-13-lanzarote-70-3-2013-hot-windy-hard-yet-the-perfect-end/IMG_3065.jpg&quot; title=&quot;IMG_3065&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[6345]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-10-13-lanzarote-70-3-2013-hot-windy-hard-yet-the-perfect-end/IMG_3065_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_3065&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-10-13-lanzarote-70-3-2013-hot-windy-hard-yet-the-perfect-end/IMG_3064.jpg&quot; title=&quot;IMG_3064&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[6345]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-10-13-lanzarote-70-3-2013-hot-windy-hard-yet-the-perfect-end/IMG_3064_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_3064&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-10-13-lanzarote-70-3-2013-hot-windy-hard-yet-the-perfect-end/IMG_3063.jpg&quot; title=&quot;IMG_3063&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[6345]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-10-13-lanzarote-70-3-2013-hot-windy-hard-yet-the-perfect-end/IMG_3063_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_3063&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-10-13-lanzarote-70-3-2013-hot-windy-hard-yet-the-perfect-end/IMG_3058.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Qualifier!&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[6345]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-10-13-lanzarote-70-3-2013-hot-windy-hard-yet-the-perfect-end/IMG_3058_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Qualifier!&quot; /&gt;&lt;span&gt;Qualifier!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-10-13-lanzarote-70-3-2013-hot-windy-hard-yet-the-perfect-end/IMG_3054.jpg&quot; title=&quot;IMG_3054&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[6345]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-10-13-lanzarote-70-3-2013-hot-windy-hard-yet-the-perfect-end/IMG_3054_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_3054&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-10-13-lanzarote-70-3-2013-hot-windy-hard-yet-the-perfect-end/IMG_3053.jpg&quot; title=&quot;IMG_3053&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[6345]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-10-13-lanzarote-70-3-2013-hot-windy-hard-yet-the-perfect-end/IMG_3053_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_3053&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-10-13-lanzarote-70-3-2013-hot-windy-hard-yet-the-perfect-end/0526_06488.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Last push for the line&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[6345]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-10-13-lanzarote-70-3-2013-hot-windy-hard-yet-the-perfect-end/0526_06488_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Last push for the line&quot; /&gt;&lt;span&gt;Last push for the line&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-10-13-lanzarote-70-3-2013-hot-windy-hard-yet-the-perfect-end/0526_05636.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Not struggling, promise!&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[6345]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-10-13-lanzarote-70-3-2013-hot-windy-hard-yet-the-perfect-end/0526_05636_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Not struggling, promise!&quot; /&gt;&lt;span&gt;Not struggling, promise!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-10-13-lanzarote-70-3-2013-hot-windy-hard-yet-the-perfect-end/0526_05635.jpg&quot; title=&quot;0526_05635&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[6345]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-10-13-lanzarote-70-3-2013-hot-windy-hard-yet-the-perfect-end/0526_05635_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;0526_05635&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-10-13-lanzarote-70-3-2013-hot-windy-hard-yet-the-perfect-end/0526_04503.jpg&quot; title=&quot;0526_04503&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[6345]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-10-13-lanzarote-70-3-2013-hot-windy-hard-yet-the-perfect-end/0526_04503_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;0526_04503&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-10-13-lanzarote-70-3-2013-hot-windy-hard-yet-the-perfect-end/0526_04502.jpg&quot; title=&quot;0526_04502&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[6345]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-10-13-lanzarote-70-3-2013-hot-windy-hard-yet-the-perfect-end/0526_04502_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;0526_04502&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-10-13-lanzarote-70-3-2013-hot-windy-hard-yet-the-perfect-end/0526_03888.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Not as happy as usual here...&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[6345]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-10-13-lanzarote-70-3-2013-hot-windy-hard-yet-the-perfect-end/0526_03888_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Not as happy as usual here...&quot; /&gt;&lt;span&gt;Not as happy as usual here...&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-10-13-lanzarote-70-3-2013-hot-windy-hard-yet-the-perfect-end/0526_03887.jpg&quot; title=&quot;0526_03887&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[6345]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-10-13-lanzarote-70-3-2013-hot-windy-hard-yet-the-perfect-end/0526_03887_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;0526_03887&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-10-13-lanzarote-70-3-2013-hot-windy-hard-yet-the-perfect-end/0526_03256.jpg&quot; title=&quot;0526_03256&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[6345]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-10-13-lanzarote-70-3-2013-hot-windy-hard-yet-the-perfect-end/0526_03256_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;0526_03256&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-10-13-lanzarote-70-3-2013-hot-windy-hard-yet-the-perfect-end/0526_02133.jpg&quot; title=&quot;0526_02133&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[6345]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-10-13-lanzarote-70-3-2013-hot-windy-hard-yet-the-perfect-end/0526_02133_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;0526_02133&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-10-13-lanzarote-70-3-2013-hot-windy-hard-yet-the-perfect-end/0526_01684.jpg&quot; title=&quot;0526_01684&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[6345]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-10-13-lanzarote-70-3-2013-hot-windy-hard-yet-the-perfect-end/0526_01684_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;0526_01684&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-10-13-lanzarote-70-3-2013-hot-windy-hard-yet-the-perfect-end/0526_00743.jpg&quot; title=&quot;0526_00743&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[6345]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-10-13-lanzarote-70-3-2013-hot-windy-hard-yet-the-perfect-end/0526_00743_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;0526_00743&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-10-13-lanzarote-70-3-2013-hot-windy-hard-yet-the-perfect-end/0526_00148.jpg&quot; title=&quot;0526_00148&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[6345]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-10-13-lanzarote-70-3-2013-hot-windy-hard-yet-the-perfect-end/0526_00148_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;0526_00148&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-10-13-lanzarote-70-3-2013-hot-windy-hard-yet-the-perfect-end/0526_00147.jpg&quot; title=&quot;0526_00147&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[6345]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-10-13-lanzarote-70-3-2013-hot-windy-hard-yet-the-perfect-end/0526_00147_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;0526_00147&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-10-13-lanzarote-70-3-2013-hot-windy-hard-yet-the-perfect-end/7b29c6c8-0164-41f6-8b8e-0be1aee082b3.jpg&quot; title=&quot;All done an still smiling!&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[6345]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2013-10-13-lanzarote-70-3-2013-hot-windy-hard-yet-the-perfect-end/7b29c6c8-0164-41f6-8b8e-0be1aee082b3_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;All done an still smiling!&quot; /&gt;&lt;span&gt;All done an still smiling!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;



</description>
                <pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
                <link>http://ww.ekynoxe.com/lanzarote-70-3-2013-hot-windy-hard-yet-the-perfect-end</link>
                <author>hello@ekynoxe.com (Mathieu Davy)</author>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ww.ekynoxe.com/lanzarote-70-3-2013-hot-windy-hard-yet-the-perfect-end</guid>
            </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>