<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Ekynoxe - Web development in London</title>
        <description>Mathieu Davy's one man web studio</description>
        <link>http://ww.ekynoxe.com</link>
        <atom:link href="http://ww.ekynoxe.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2014 21:15:54 +0000</pubDate>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2014 21:15:54 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        
            <item>
                <title>Every Day Training Camp - Day 6 - Windy, uphill, or both?</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Last day on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.everydaytraining.org.uk/&quot; title=&quot;EDT Camp day six&quot;&gt;EDT&lt;/a&gt; Camp. A bit sad as this has been a fantastic week but today was a big day on another level: riding the full ironman course in conditions that weren&amp;rsquo;t the best!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-14-every-day-training-camp-day-6-windy-uphill-or-both/Mirador_del_Rio_as_ever_impressive.png&quot; title=&quot;Mirador del Rio: as ever impressive&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[014-03-14]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-14-every-day-training-camp-day-6-windy-uphill-or-both/Mirador_del_Rio_as_ever_impressive_r500.png&quot; alt=&quot;Mirador del Rio: as ever impressive&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Three groups were formed, one of them going for an extended loop through Femès and Playa Blanca, while the two others would stick to the ironman route all the way around. By 9am when we had all set-off, the wind had already picked up, and we knew it wasn&amp;rsquo;t going to be an easy day.
Add to this the general fatigue from the 5 previous days of early rising, hard racing and pushing our boundaries, and you get a great cocktail of &amp;ldquo;I may not be able to do this&amp;rdquo;! But that&amp;rsquo;s the spirit of the camp: you will still find more in yourself and with the help of others, you&amp;rsquo;ll get through the last event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The day&amp;rsquo;s ride could have ended prematurely for some, as 10Km in the ride for the fast group, Matthew unfortunately rode over a glass bottle on the side of the road, which exploded and completely shredded his tire. That group had to go back to the hotel for a pit-stop, and resume their ride a little later. They still did their planned long route though, but had to drop the hammer from Orzola, since they passed there only after 5pm! They must have been absolutely flying on the way back to get back on time to get ready for dinner!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was in the &amp;ldquo;medium&amp;rdquo; group and we worked pretty well together all the way around, only splitting for the fast descents to be a bit safer, and for some of the ascents to ride at our own rhythm, before regrouping at the top.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But today was honestly a long struggle. The wind was quite strong, making the ascents north-eastwards harder, and any descent very twitchy and dangerous. I certainly had a few moments on my deep rims which I&amp;rsquo;m happy I handled well, but which were definitely borderline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The initial idea was to get around the course in about 6h30, but it took us 7h15. Still, we were pretty pleased with that given the conditions!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2 months time, I hope to get around in 5h30 max if I want to get close to the 10h mark overall&amp;hellip; This little reminder will always be on my mind:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-14-every-day-training-camp-day-6-windy-uphill-or-both/run_boy_run.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Run boy Run&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2014-03-14]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-14-every-day-training-camp-day-6-windy-uphill-or-both/run_boy_run_r500.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Run boy Run&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone from all groups made it through the course, and it&amp;rsquo;s a pleasure to see that although it&amp;rsquo;s been a long, hard ride at the end of a very busy training week, it&amp;rsquo;s been enjoyable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With each one of us having done more than 30 hours of training this week, EDT Camp has now been completed! We were all very much looking forward to a nice meal out altogether, and proper grilled meat was on most plates tonight!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the performances of the week, and finishing the ride today, it meant that on points I did win the camp. And Jo presented me with my very own winner tee-shirt. A unique one! Fantastic memory for a massive week of training.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-14-every-day-training-camp-day-6-windy-uphill-or-both/camp_winner.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Camp winner!&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2014-03-14]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-14-every-day-training-camp-day-6-windy-uphill-or-both/camp_winner_r500.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Camp winner!&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tired? Yes! Happy? Ecstatic! That was a fantastic week and I&amp;rsquo;m sure I&amp;rsquo;ll be back for more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you want to do a week of great training with like-minded crazy athletes? Contact &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:coaches@everydaytraining.org.uk&quot; title=&quot;Contact Every Day Training&quot;&gt;Steven and Jo&lt;/a&gt; to get the low down on the camps and register your interest for next year&amp;rsquo;s edition! Entries may not be open yet, but enquire before and secure a place when they do. You won&amp;rsquo;t regret it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks a lot to &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/lord_lordy&quot;&gt;Steven&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jo_carritt&quot;&gt;Jo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/waterrat77&quot;&gt;Emma&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/SportsMassageSB&quot;&gt;Sarah&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/millsphysio&quot;&gt;Ali&lt;/a&gt; and to all the campers for making this week an amazing one. It&amp;rsquo;s not been easy sailing for any of us, but the atmosphere and support has carried us all around the activities, races and ice-cream contests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See you next year, I&amp;rsquo;m off for a rest now!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Today&amp;rsquo;s stats for me&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://connect.garmin.com/activity/461866307&quot;&gt;Bike: 182Km, ~2600m ascent&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;My camp stats&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Swim: 6.8Km&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bike: 711Km with about 10.000m ascent&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run: 51.2Km&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Total hours: 34.8h&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;gallery&quot;&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-14-every-day-training-camp-day-6-windy-uphill-or-both/Happy_climbing.png&quot; title=&quot;Happy climbing&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2014-03-14]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-14-every-day-training-camp-day-6-windy-uphill-or-both/Happy_climbing_r300.png&quot; alt=&quot;Happy climbing&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-14-every-day-training-camp-day-6-windy-uphill-or-both/Jo_smiles_despite_hard_work.png&quot; title=&quot;Jo smiles despite hard work&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2014-03-14]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-14-every-day-training-camp-day-6-windy-uphill-or-both/Jo_smiles_despite_hard_work_r300.png&quot; alt=&quot;Jo smiles despite hard work&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-14-every-day-training-camp-day-6-windy-uphill-or-both/Mirador_del_Rio_as_ever_impressive.png&quot; title=&quot;Mirador del Rio: as ever impressive&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2014-03-14]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-14-every-day-training-camp-day-6-windy-uphill-or-both/Mirador_del_Rio_as_ever_impressive_r300.png&quot; alt=&quot;Mirador del Rio: as ever impressive&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-14-every-day-training-camp-day-6-windy-uphill-or-both/run_boy_run.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Run boy Run&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2014-03-14]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-14-every-day-training-camp-day-6-windy-uphill-or-both/run_boy_run_r500.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Run boy Run&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-14-every-day-training-camp-day-6-windy-uphill-or-both/camp_winner.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Camp winner!&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2014-03-14]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-14-every-day-training-camp-day-6-windy-uphill-or-both/camp_winner_r500.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Camp winner!&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2014 19:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://ww.ekynoxe.com/every-day-training-camp-day-6-windy-uphill-or-both</link>
                <author>hello@ekynoxe.com (Mathieu Davy)</author>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ww.ekynoxe.com/every-day-training-camp-day-6-windy-uphill-or-both</guid>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Every Day Training Camp - Day 5 - A tale of two races</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Today everyone is pretty much cream-crackered after yesterday&amp;rsquo;s hard work up Tabayesco. Nonetheless, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.everydaytraining.org.uk/&quot; title=&quot;EDT Camp day five&quot;&gt;EDT&lt;/a&gt; Camp has no respite, and this is the business end of the week, with not one, but two handicapped races to get done: a swim in the morning, and a 10K run after the day&amp;rsquo;s ride.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;




&lt;h3&gt;Swim&lt;/h3&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The swim race was a two lap event, around the channel where the ironman starts. But unlike yesterday&amp;rsquo;s bike TT where campers were set off at regular 30s intervals, the starts were done on handicaps calculated down to seconds. Given that Simon swam almost twice the distance than anyone else in the aquathlon, following the wrong course, he had a huge lead on everyone, Mel even starting her race only after Simon had started his second lap! The handicap system was probably not really made for this kind of situations so results at either end were probably not most representative. With this handicap, Simon actually won the race, but as a gent he declined the prize on the basis that the handicap wasn&amp;rsquo;t really fair.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I&amp;rsquo;m not a particularly great swimmer, I finished mid-pack in the aquathlon swim, and therefore started mid-pack in the swim race. And being in this position allowed for quite a bit of action around the 2 laps course. I was 2 seconds behind Linda and maybe 5 behind Rob at the start, which I quickly made up, but as I found out, it was a bit too much for me to handle and I tired quickly towards the end of the first lap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Follow that with a little run on the beach between the two laps to get your hear rate through the roof, and I was caught by Rob and James before the first buoy on the second lap. In true racing spirit James tried to push me straight onto the buoy but a good old shove from me managed to get the inside line&amp;hellip; before being dunked in heavily on the turn itself. Rob, in the mean time, kept clear of all the action and passed both of us. I had nothing left in the tank for the final sprint, but that was great, great fun!
I absolutely loved it, and given the number of huffing and puffing rubber-clad bodies lying in the sand after the swim, it looks like everyone had given it their all!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although I felt like I blew up, I certainly had a great swim as I managed 1'29&quot; / 100m on average, which is the fastest pace I&amp;rsquo;ve ever swam either in a wetsuit in any race or in any training session doing reps. Good times!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Bike&lt;/h3&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The day&amp;rsquo;s ride was going to be fairly short, but still include some hard work: the climb from Playa Blanca to Femès, all in a headwind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-13-every-day-training-camp-day-5-a-tale-of-two-races/femes_the_not_so_steep_bit.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Femes: The not so steep bit&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2014-03-13]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-13-every-day-training-camp-day-5-a-tale-of-two-races/femes_the_not_so_steep_bit_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Femes: The not so steep bit&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;And to make up for an early navigation blunder that saw us take a short route, most of the group did some reps of the last bit of the climb: 1km of gut busting gradients with an average of 13% and passages at more than 22%! I had to push above 300W for more than 4'30&quot; and move at only 10.5 kph! Those figures for me a way above what I can sustain for a long period of time, so that climb really earns its fierce reputation!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was such a challenge that Matthew had a 20&amp;euro; bet with both James and Mel that he&amp;rsquo;d climb the whole thing from Playa Blanca in the big ring&amp;hellip; And he did! His quads were still twitching at the cafe afterwards, but he really earned that!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-13-every-day-training-camp-day-5-a-tale-of-two-races/a_20_euro_bet.jpg&quot; title=&quot;A 20 EURO bet&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2014-03-13]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-13-every-day-training-camp-day-5-a-tale-of-two-races/a_20_euro_bet_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A 20 EURO bet&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;We managed to trick David into doing 4 reps of the steep part, telling him that Jo went for a 4th while she was hiding around the back of the cafe, which earned him the camp record. And on a TT bike with deep rims, that&amp;rsquo;s quite a feat too!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Run&lt;/h3&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The run was a &amp;ldquo;no watches&amp;rdquo; 10K race. Given how I hurt last time I did one, fresh, round the corner from home, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t too optimistic about the result on the 5th day of an overloaded week of training and without any idea of pace. The basic race was designed to be like the swim this morning: the slowest time from the aquathlon would start first, then every athlete would set off at intervals calculated from their run times in the aquathlon. Mix it all with a secret formula Steven&amp;rsquo;s been brewing for the last few camps, and it&amp;rsquo;s supposed to be a close finish with everyone.
Having ran the fastest time in the aquathlon, I therefore started last, which gave me targets to pick, much like during the TT on Tabayesco.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But to add a little more fun to the race, Jo and Steven asked each one of us to predict their times. The goal being to see how confident people feel they can run fast on the back of such a training week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not really optimistic by nature (see &lt;a href=&quot;/every-day-training-camp-pre-camp/&quot;&gt;my post before the camp&amp;hellip;&lt;/a&gt;), so I predicted something in the region of 3min slower than my all time PB of 38'15&quot;. Also, the lack of pacing could be problematic (or not).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I saw everyone set off one after the other, and as Jo and Steven predicted: it was quite hard not to get disheartened at the seemingly huge lead they were getting, but when my turn finally came, I just went for it. My first target was already 37s ahead of me, and barely visible, but I wanted to catch as many people as I could, the cherry on the cake would have been to catch Jo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started to reel people in and I knew I was pushing hard, but that was the exercise: keep pushing without pace indication. I apologies for the amount of swearing I did around the course when I was passing people: I could barely see Jo in the distance, and only got an idea of how far I was at the turnaround points. I did get closer, but she must have found an extra gear because I certainly didn&amp;rsquo;t feel that I was slowing down at the time. Checking the data from my taped watch after the race, I actually went faster in the last 2K, so Jo had the afterburners turned well on at the right time and despite catching everyone else, I never caught her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taping my watch was probably the best thing to have been asked to do. And I was shocked to see that I had ran close to a PB in 38'34&quot;, getting the fastest time of the day and a camp record! What a result!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What was a lot less impressive however was my prediction of my finish time&amp;hellip; At 2'36&quot; slower than what I actually ran, I had one of the most pessimistic guesses, and that really shows that I need to work on my belief in myself for the next races. That should come handy in 2 months when I race the ironman here!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That race was concluding the day for most, but as I had not done the extended swim in the morning, and to avoid having to swim right before the ironman bike ride tomorrow, I decided to swim the way back. I never thought I&amp;rsquo;d say &amp;ldquo;I swam back home from a 10K race&amp;rdquo;, but I did! Nice and easy, warm in the shallows, taking my time and enjoying the relaxation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Today's stats for me&lt;/h3&gt;


&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Swim: 2.32Km&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://connect.garmin.com/activity/461239665&quot;&gt;Bike: 63Km, 1110m ascent&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run: 16.84Km (including a 38'34&quot; 10K)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
                <pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2014 21:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://ww.ekynoxe.com/every-day-training-camp-day-5-a-tale-of-two-races</link>
                <author>hello@ekynoxe.com (Mathieu Davy)</author>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ww.ekynoxe.com/every-day-training-camp-day-5-a-tale-of-two-races</guid>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Every Day Training Camp - Day 4 - High flying</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Today&amp;rsquo;s feature on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.everydaytraining.org.uk/&quot; title=&quot;EDT Camp day four&quot;&gt;EDT&lt;/a&gt; Camp was the Tabayesco time trial. With about 500m of ascent over 10Km, that was the first of the three handicapped races, where riders were set off in an order determined from the previous timed events.
After winning the TT on the first day, needless to say that expectations were high, and not just from myself! Thanks to everyone in the group for that! I had a target to beat!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-12-every-day-training-camp-day-4-high-flying/time_keeping_and_cheering.png&quot; title=&quot;Time keeping and cheering&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2014-03-12]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-12-every-day-training-camp-day-4-high-flying/time_keeping_and_cheering_r500.png&quot; alt=&quot;Time keeping and cheering&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;!--more--&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Prior to this, the morning swim saw us do a nice bay-to-beach-and-back swim. That was a welcome change from the standard loops, with a few more things to see underwater as well! I had the camera with me, so that should make it through the camp film later on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;gallery&quot;&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-12-every-day-training-camp-day-4-high-flying/after_swim.jpg&quot; title=&quot;After the swim&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2014-03-12]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-12-every-day-training-camp-day-4-high-flying/after_swim_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;After the swim&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-12-every-day-training-camp-day-4-high-flying/rubber_legs.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Rubber legs&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2014-03-12]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-12-every-day-training-camp-day-4-high-flying/rubber_legs_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Rubber legs&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-12-every-day-training-camp-day-4-high-flying/underwater.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Steven under water&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2014-03-12]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-12-every-day-training-camp-day-4-high-flying/underwater_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Steven under water&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;After raiding the buffet breakfast once more, we rode 40 km in a strong headwind to get to the bottom of the climb, where riders were then set-off at 30s or 1min intervals. From two synchronised watches, the times were expertly taken at the top by &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/SportsMassageSB&quot;&gt;Sarah&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/millsphysio&quot;&gt;Ali&lt;/a&gt;, handicapped results being worked-out later-on by Steven at the Mirador de Haria cafe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I did a good time on the El Golfo TT on Sunday, I was the last one to start before Steven, and the expectation put on me by pretty much everyone was that I&amp;rsquo;d catch most of them&amp;hellip; Easier said than done!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the wind blowing down the valley, and having lead legs from having started last, it was tough at first. But the heavy legs soon went away and I could just put my head down and concentrate on keeping the power up with a good leg turnover.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted to try and not get caught by Steven, who was the course record holder, so I really pushed hard at the start, averaging close to 290-300W for several minutes, then had to slow down a bit to not completely explode. With my best ever turbo 20min effort being 289W, and a climb that should take around 30min to get over at speed, it was the right thing to do!
I stayed on the tri bars most of the way as this is how I train on the turbo, but had to sit-up in a few passages where I couldn&amp;rsquo;t push the pedals hard enough in that position.
I reached the left turn, before the switchbacks, in around 18:30, so it was game-on to get under 30min at the top if I could maintain the effort. Having the others of the group ahead of me was a fantastic help though, as I had targets to chase all the time. It must be a lot harder to start at the front and keep motivated all the way.
With two corners to go after the windy switchbacks, I threw everything I had left and I couldn&amp;rsquo;t believe that my watch was showing 28'59&quot; when I crossed the line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was properly gut busting and everyone was feeling it well at the top, but there wasn&amp;rsquo;t really any time to rest, as half of the group went for a hilly trail run around the observatory. I had never seen that side, and it&amp;rsquo;s simply gorgeous!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-12-every-day-training-camp-day-4-high-flying/top_of_haria.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Running at the top of Mirador de Haria&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2014-03-12]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-12-every-day-training-camp-day-4-high-flying/top_of_haria_r500.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Running at the top of Mirador de Haria&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Results of TT where announced when everyone was back at the cafe and eaten their bodyweight in cake, ice cream and cheese. I had won it on pure time, setting a new course record, but Ellen had also done just above 41min!! The initial goal for here being around 50min, that was a fantastic time! Get in missy! What a way to get up the &amp;ldquo;hill&amp;rdquo;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;attachement iframe_wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;//player.vimeo.com/video/89182544?portrait=0&amp;amp;color=ff9933&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Combined with her initial El-Golfo TT, it also meant she pipped everyone to the handicapped win by a mile! Unfortunately the conditions of the camp competitions are such that she couldn&amp;rsquo;t claim the prize, but well done for winning it! That must boost your confidence big time!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the prize of a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.freespeed.co.uk/&quot;&gt;Freespeed bike fit&lt;/a&gt; stayed &amp;ldquo;in the family&amp;rdquo; as Steven put it, as I was the second camper behind Ellen on handicap, which was pretty handy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There have been a few surprises on this climb, but I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure everyone enjoyed it, even if it is secretly. We&amp;rsquo;re nutters enough to do 6 days of overload in one of the most unfriendly bike environments, so I&amp;rsquo;m sure we&amp;rsquo;re all enjoying those little races!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you wonder how to run races for small groups and make them fun while giving everyone a chance: use handicaps! That&amp;rsquo;s a fantastic way to keep everyone involved and guessing for results, as the fastest doesn&amp;rsquo;t always win! There are numerous ways to do it and I need to grill Steven about his methods, but it&amp;rsquo;s always entertaining.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After this, I took the long way back to the hotel with a few others, riding through Fire Mountain the other way: downhill! Views are again exceptional over there, and since we had already gone up the other side 3 times this week, it was only fair to get to do it this way at least once.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the runs to and from swimming, the run at the top of the climb validated my run quota for today, so I could put my feet up a little tonight, which was most welcome!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Today's stats for me&lt;/h3&gt;


&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Swim: 1.34Km&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bike: 117.63Km, 1544m ascent &lt;a href=&quot;http://connect.garmin.com/activity/461239822&quot;&gt;part1&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://connect.garmin.com/activity/461239760&quot;&gt;part2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run: 4.76Km&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;gallery&quot;&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-12-every-day-training-camp-day-4-high-flying/Brian.png&quot; title=&quot;Brian&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2014-03-12]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-12-every-day-training-camp-day-4-high-flying/Brian_r300.png&quot; alt=&quot;Brian&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-12-every-day-training-camp-day-4-high-flying/David.png&quot; title=&quot;David&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2014-03-12]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-12-every-day-training-camp-day-4-high-flying/David_r300.png&quot; alt=&quot;David&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-12-every-day-training-camp-day-4-high-flying/Heather.png&quot; title=&quot;Heather&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2014-03-12]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-12-every-day-training-camp-day-4-high-flying/Heather_r300.png&quot; alt=&quot;Heather&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-12-every-day-training-camp-day-4-high-flying/James.png&quot; title=&quot;James&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2014-03-12]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-12-every-day-training-camp-day-4-high-flying/James_r300.png&quot; alt=&quot;James&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-12-every-day-training-camp-day-4-high-flying/Matthew.png&quot; title=&quot;Matthew&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2014-03-12]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-12-every-day-training-camp-day-4-high-flying/Matthew_r300.png&quot; alt=&quot;Matthew&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-12-every-day-training-camp-day-4-high-flying/Mel.png&quot; title=&quot;Mel&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2014-03-12]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-12-every-day-training-camp-day-4-high-flying/Mel_r300.png&quot; alt=&quot;Mel&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-12-every-day-training-camp-day-4-high-flying/Rob.png&quot; title=&quot;Rob&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2014-03-12]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-12-every-day-training-camp-day-4-high-flying/Rob_r300.png&quot; alt=&quot;Rob&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-12-every-day-training-camp-day-4-high-flying/roz_waved.png&quot; title=&quot;As promised, Roz did wave!&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2014-03-12]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-12-every-day-training-camp-day-4-high-flying/roz_waved_r300.png&quot; alt=&quot;As promised, Roz did wave!&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-12-every-day-training-camp-day-4-high-flying/Sarah_chief_time_keeper.png&quot; title=&quot;Sarah was chief time keeper at the top&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2014-03-12]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-12-every-day-training-camp-day-4-high-flying/Sarah_chief_time_keeper_r300.png&quot; alt=&quot;Sarah was chief time keeper at the top&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-12-every-day-training-camp-day-4-high-flying/Simon.png&quot; title=&quot;Simon&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2014-03-12]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-12-every-day-training-camp-day-4-high-flying/Simon_r300.png&quot; alt=&quot;Simon&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-12-every-day-training-camp-day-4-high-flying/Steve.png&quot; title=&quot;Steve&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2014-03-12]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-12-every-day-training-camp-day-4-high-flying/Steve_r300.png&quot; alt=&quot;Steve&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-12-every-day-training-camp-day-4-high-flying/Steven.png&quot; title=&quot;Steven&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2014-03-12]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-12-every-day-training-camp-day-4-high-flying/Steven_r300.png&quot; alt=&quot;Steven&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-12-every-day-training-camp-day-4-high-flying/time_keeping_and_cheering.png&quot; title=&quot;Time keeping and cheering&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2014-03-12]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-12-every-day-training-camp-day-4-high-flying/time_keeping_and_cheering_r300.png&quot; alt=&quot;Time keeping and cheering&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
                <pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2014 16:57:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://ww.ekynoxe.com/every-day-training-camp-day-4-high-flying</link>
                <author>hello@ekynoxe.com (Mathieu Davy)</author>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ww.ekynoxe.com/every-day-training-camp-day-4-high-flying</guid>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Every Day Training Camp - Day 3 - Wind, rain and an early race</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Today on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.everydaytraining.org.uk/&quot; title=&quot;EDT Camp day three&quot;&gt;EDT&lt;/a&gt; camp, it was all about the early morning race: an aquathlon on the sea front of Puerto del Carmen. Then a simple ride just above 100K to make things right!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-11-every-day-training-camp-day-3-wind-rain-and-an-early-race/Aquathlon_transition.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Aquathlon transition&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[20140311]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-11-every-day-training-camp-day-3-wind-rain-and-an-early-race/Aquathlon_transition_r500.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Aquathlon transition&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;!--more--&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The aquathlon was held on the seafront of Puerto del Carmen, very close to the ironman finish line. The swim was 2 out-and-back loops from the beach to the line of permanent yellow buoys, and the run was on the undulating seafront. With a &amp;ldquo;mass&amp;rdquo; start, it was a great format: whoever is ahead&amp;hellip; is ahead!
The transition area was up at road level, on a children&amp;rsquo;s playground.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unlike yesterday, the mass start wasn&amp;rsquo;t feisty, mostly because the target for the turnaround wasn&amp;rsquo;t a single, small buoy, but a line of buoys out at sea. This meant everyone fanned out quickly, with a few working together. I found myself pretty isolated to the right of it all, and got tangled in the ropes of a buoy &amp;frac34; of the way to the turnaround. That, and getting it again on the way back, didn&amp;rsquo;t help, but I had a normal swim, despite really feeling my ribs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got caught big time by swimmers who didn&amp;rsquo;t start too fast and didn&amp;rsquo;t half blow-up in the middle of their swim, but I managed to exit transition in about 7th or 8th place, being speedy through the zone, even with putting socks on. That&amp;rsquo;s a welcome change for me!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also had an interesting target to try and catch in Jo, my coach, who shot out of transition slightly ahead of me. I passed her right at the end of the first lap, but she&amp;rsquo;s a racer, and I didn&amp;rsquo;t want her to be able to stick around, so had to dig deeper to not be caught. That worked well since I finished 5th, with the fastest run split of the day. I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure Jo&amp;rsquo;s having fun though. Aren&amp;rsquo;t you, coach? :-)
Gut-busting action for everyone, and well done to Greg for winning it, cracking run there! He managed to catch Mel who was out on the run first, almost 5 minutes ahead of me! I&amp;rsquo;m definitely not a front-pack swimmer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Running back to the hotel validated our &amp;ldquo;wildcard&amp;rdquo; to not have to do an extra run in the afternoon after the ride, which was welcome since tomorrow, there is another bike TT, uphill this time, on Tabayesco. Discussions have been going on fiercely about me winning it, but I&amp;rsquo;m yet to be convinced some are going full blast. Tomorrow will be fun regardless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today&amp;rsquo;s ride was a long loop through Playa Blanca, Fire Mountain and Famara, and it was pretty windy. Great test of the legs doing some work at the front (but not all of it, there&amp;rsquo;s a TT tomorrow after all ;-) ), and of bike handling in cross winds around the island. Wheels are fine, legs seem to work al-right, so all is good on this front.
Some of the group on the long ride today decided to ride up to Teguise, and I&amp;rsquo;m yet to hear the stories, but apparently they&amp;rsquo;ve got offered a full cake (as in the WHOLE thing!) and, well, gobbled it up. After the few ice creams of those last few days, I&amp;rsquo;m not sure how this is going to end!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It also rained today. Clouds come just like this and disappear after 1h after having drenched everything. On the way back with Frankie, we managed to miss them. Lucky this time!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not many photos today: I didn&amp;rsquo;t take my camera with me, and the wind was so strong it would have been a bad idea to try and take the phone out of my pocket. I&amp;rsquo;m sure the official blog will have more later on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Today's stats for me&lt;/h3&gt;


&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Swim: 1.4K as part of the aquathlon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://connect.garmin.com/activity/459285098&quot;&gt;Bike: 107Km, 2000m ascent&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run: 4.3K as part of the aquathlon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
                <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2014 21:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://ww.ekynoxe.com/every-day-training-camp-day-3-wind-rain-and-an-early-race</link>
                <author>hello@ekynoxe.com (Mathieu Davy)</author>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ww.ekynoxe.com/every-day-training-camp-day-3-wind-rain-and-an-early-race</guid>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Every Day Training Camp - Day 2 - Ice creams and mountain goats</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.everydaytraining.org.uk/&quot; title=&quot;EDT Camp day two&quot;&gt;Every Day Training&lt;/a&gt; camp, day two:
A swim session with entering/leaving the water drills (and a race!), a long day in the saddle with a lot of climbing, and a nice steady run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-10-every-day-training-camp-day-2-ice-creams-and-mountain-goats/mirador_del_rio.jpg&quot; title=&quot;At the top of Mirador del Rio&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[20140310]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-10-every-day-training-camp-day-2-ice-creams-and-mountain-goats/mirador_del_rio_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;At the top of Mirador del Rio&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;!--more--&gt;


&lt;p&gt;We all started by a fun little session from the beach. The idea was to do a 25m out and back around a buoy by teams of two, paired after an initial flat out test from a mass start on the beach. It was close to reproduce and ironman start! Lots of pushing and shoving! Not on the same scale of course, but a nice washing machine around the buoy.
Although some didn&amp;rsquo;t get the rules fully, and therefore had to do an extra lap, everyone had a ball, much to the bemusement of passers by, who had no idea what our group of rubber clad athletes was doing. Sweet and short, but quite funny. The run back up to the hotel didn&amp;rsquo;t feel as hard today, which was nice. There should be some good footage of this race later on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.everydaytraining.org.uk/&quot;&gt;Every Day Training blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As mentioned in the briefing this evening, the ride today was the second hardest after the ful IM course we&amp;rsquo;ll do on Thursday. And we all felt it! 2000m of ascent in 140Km, The donkey track out of Puerto del Carmen, the climb to Teguise, the meaty bit: Orzola to Mirador del Rio, Haria to its mirador through the switchbacks, and then the return from La Santa. Some stiff legs on the way back, and a fair bit of wind as well. Perfect Lanzarote. Some did feel it more than others today, but they&amp;rsquo;ll be back for more tomorrow I&amp;rsquo;m sure. That&amp;rsquo;s what camp is about: getting to and over your limits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had my go pro with me all day and filmed a few things along the way. I think I must have looked like a right goof with the camera on my head and my helmet completely sideways but hey, we&amp;rsquo;re here for some fun too!
The hotel wifi is so rubbish that I&amp;rsquo;ll have to upload them when I&amp;rsquo;m back, which should give me a it of time to edit them as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &amp;ldquo;fast&amp;rdquo; group today didn&amp;rsquo;t manage to catch the supposedly &amp;ldquo;slower&amp;rdquo; one before the top og Haria, which meant there was also a lot of good riding done up front!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have to admit, the brick-sized sugar cake and coffee at the top of Haria was very welcome. Buzzing like crazy after that, but lovely stop. I also kept half my sandwich to eat at La Santa while some of the others had their bikes repaired, some quite extensively!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The return after La Santa was a little bit less enjoyeable as it was basically a long climb all the way back to and then a relatively short climb through Conil and the donkey track.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Top all that action packed day with 1h run along the seafront (and the dreaded climb back up afterwards), and you&amp;rsquo;ve got all the ingredients for a tired VERY hungry athletes who hapily raided the hotel restaurant :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks Sarah for massage and the nudge about &amp;ldquo;getting acquaitned with my foam roller&amp;rdquo;. I&amp;rsquo;ll try to get on it more often. I don&amp;rsquo;t like knots either!!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tired now, I need some sleep: tomorrow, there&amp;rsquo;s an aqauthlon and that one will hurt!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Today's stats for me&lt;/h3&gt;


&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Swim: 800m (only, but crazy sprinting)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://connect.garmin.com/activity/458826817&quot;&gt;Bike: 140Km, 2000m ascent&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run: 1h, 12.3Km.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;gallery&quot;&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-10-every-day-training-camp-day-2-ice-creams-and-mountain-goats/to_arieta.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Going towards Arieta&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[20140310]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-10-every-day-training-camp-day-2-ice-creams-and-mountain-goats/to_arieta_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Going towards Arieta&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-10-every-day-training-camp-day-2-ice-creams-and-mountain-goats/mirador_del_rio.jpg&quot; title=&quot;At the top of Mirador del Rio&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[20140310]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-10-every-day-training-camp-day-2-ice-creams-and-mountain-goats/mirador_del_rio_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;At the top of Mirador del Rio&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-10-every-day-training-camp-day-2-ice-creams-and-mountain-goats/coffee_stop_haria.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Coffee stop at Mirador de Haria&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[20140310]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-10-every-day-training-camp-day-2-ice-creams-and-mountain-goats/coffee_stop_haria_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Coffee stop at Mirador de Haria&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-10-every-day-training-camp-day-2-ice-creams-and-mountain-goats/ice_creams_while_u_wait.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Ice creams while u wait&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[20140310]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-10-every-day-training-camp-day-2-ice-creams-and-mountain-goats/ice_creams_while_u_wait_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ice creams while u wait&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
                <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2014 22:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://ww.ekynoxe.com/every-day-training-camp-day-2-ice-creams-and-mountain-goats</link>
                <author>hello@ekynoxe.com (Mathieu Davy)</author>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ww.ekynoxe.com/every-day-training-camp-day-2-ice-creams-and-mountain-goats</guid>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Every Day Training Camp - Day 1</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;After a nice introductory briefing by the pool yesterday night where we got to know each other, the general plan for the camp was outlined, and we go our first taste of the little competition running: today, first day of the camp, would include a 10 miles TT around the El Golfo loop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-09-every-day-training-camp-day-1/edt.png&quot; alt=&quot;70.3 California medal&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;!--more--&gt;


&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve been spoilt by the camp sponsors: PowerBar — well, if you like gels (I do) — but we also got a nice pair of goggles from Blue Seventy, an offer for some weird recovery device from Firefly, and some Nuun tabs which should come in handy this week ask I&amp;rsquo;ll sweat a lot! We also have some amazing sport massage from The Tri Touch that will for sure become very handy!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-09-every-day-training-camp-day-1/goodies.jpg&quot; title=&quot;goodies_r300.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[20140309]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-09-every-day-training-camp-day-1/goodies_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;goodies_r300.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;But before the bike action, it was &amp;ldquo;up and at &amp;lsquo;em&amp;rdquo; early, to get a swim at 6:30 and be for the opening of the breakfast doors at the hotel by 8:30. A bit frantic, but that sure gets you going!
The water wasn&amp;rsquo;t as warm as I expected but after a couple of minutes it all warmed up nicely. I had to stop on the way out to get a grasp of the sunshine! I haven&amp;rsquo;t seen much of it in the UK for some time, and with my first open water swim of the season, that was picture perfect.
Pretty much everyone was ahead in the sun, but the 20-strong group all gathered for a short rest towards at the end of line of buoys before heading back&amp;hellip; In the current. No wonder the way out felt easy!
I still felt my arm and right ribs from the crash last Friday, but it wasn&amp;rsquo;t getting worse in the swim, so all was more or less OK. I think the end of the swim transformed itself in a bit of a race, with everyone surging around, but some of us got tangled in the ropes of the channel going out from the beach. Great fun though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Running back up to the hotel (and I really mean &amp;ldquo;up&amp;rdquo;!!), felt OK as well, so the day started quite good for everyone, as I learnt afterwards that no-one took the minibus back to the hotel. Still lots of energy in everyone at this point!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Breakfast was quickly gobbled-up before we all set off on the day&amp;rsquo;s ride: a long loop around the south west, up through the donkey track, then through the back roads to Yaiza. (I&amp;rsquo;ve never been that way so it was a welcome change, albeit all in a headwind which is unusual here.) Then we&amp;rsquo;ve done two laps of the El Golfo loop from the Yaiza roundabout, the second one being a 10mi time trial with everyone being set-off at at 30s intervals, and return through Fire Mountain and that infamous long, uphill, stretch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 10mi TT was a flyer. I&amp;rsquo;ve never done a pure TT before, so even in the middle of a ride, that was a first. The route was the loop from the ironman course, so I knew it well, except that I didn&amp;rsquo;t know where the end was. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t back where we started, but about 500m before, so I went straight past Jo through what was the finish line, and carried on until the starting point (Know the course, muppet!).
But even with that, I picked up quite a few people, and finished in under 25min, which interestingly gave me the fastest time of the day and the course record (gasp!). The cafe stop afterwards was welcome for everyone to chill out a bit before the rolling way back through the lunar landscape of Timanfaya National Park and fire mountain. Interesting refuelling strategies from some as well with ice-cream on one end of the spectrum, and avocados on the other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything was a little bit rushed after that since I forgot to bring a pump and I tried to find a shop opened in town but I got lost getting there (duuhh), and as it was Sunday, they were all closed.
Follow that with a 35min run down to the sea-front, along the shore and back, and in no time I was in the hands of Sarah for a much overdue massage that left me pretty stiff&amp;hellip; It&amp;rsquo;s all for my own good, I know!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that camp started with a bang, and hopefully I&amp;rsquo;ll have some energy in the next few days to keep going! Well done everyone today, and especially to my other half who&amp;rsquo;s done brilliantly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Find also the official &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.everydaytraining.org.uk/&quot;&gt;Every Day Training blog&lt;/a&gt; online where the coaches Steven and Jo will be blogging every day as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully I&amp;rsquo;ll take more photos for tomorrow&amp;rsquo;s post. Today was a bit of a blur.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lanzarote - Over and out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Today's stats for me&lt;/h3&gt;


&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Swim: 2.1Km (one lap of the IM course + extra at start)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://connect.garmin.com/activity/458041343&quot;&gt;Bike: 103Km, 1500m ascent&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run: 35min, 7.3Km&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
                <pubDate>Sun, 09 Mar 2014 21:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://ww.ekynoxe.com/every-day-training-camp-day-1</link>
                <author>hello@ekynoxe.com (Mathieu Davy)</author>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ww.ekynoxe.com/every-day-training-camp-day-1</guid>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Every Day Training Camp - Pre-camp</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re on the eve of going away with Ellen to what should be an awesome week of riding, running and swimming in the sunshine of Lanzarote.
However, there&amp;rsquo;s been a few little hicups in the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-07-every-day-training-camp-pre-camp/travelling.jpg&quot; title=&quot;travelling&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[20140307]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-07-every-day-training-camp-pre-camp/travelling_r500.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;travelling&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;A month ago, I managed to get tonsillitis, which lingered on and on and on until I finally managed to get some antibiotics from my GP&amp;hellip; Last Wednesday. Training has therefore been ridiculously minimal for the last 3 weeks&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week, Ellen found out that she&amp;rsquo;s got a stress fracture in her right foot, and is now walking around in an air cast. Not that this will discourage her from riding the hills on the volcano island!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this morning I managed to crash heavily, all on my own, going to work, and my right ribs are now painful&amp;hellip; Nothing is broken, I can still move, lift and do most things, but we&amp;rsquo;ll see tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So instead of two healthy and strong athletes going for a week of proper training camp, we&amp;rsquo;re now two cripples going for rehab!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully we&amp;rsquo;ll manage to do a few of the activities planned. It seems that there&amp;rsquo;s some sunshine at least!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2014 21:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://ww.ekynoxe.com/every-day-training-camp-pre-camp</link>
                <author>hello@ekynoxe.com (Mathieu Davy)</author>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ww.ekynoxe.com/every-day-training-camp-pre-camp</guid>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>It's YOUR race</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The triathlon race season will start again soon here in the UK, and with the plethora of winter running races and other duathlons available — not to mention overseas racing — I can see a lot of my friends and twitter buddies getting in some fast action over the week-ends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, I noticed a trend lately: this also comes with plenty of them doubting themselves for the goals they have set a long way back. For most, they&amp;rsquo;ve been reasonable in setting those up, so it&amp;rsquo;s all about confidence and re-adjustment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;


&lt;p&gt;In one of his &lt;a href=&quot;http://triathlete-europe.competitor.com/tag/steven-lord&quot;&gt;latest columns in Triathlete Europe&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://triathlete-europe.competitor.com/2014/02/19/steven-lord-blog-challenges&quot;&gt;Steven Lord described the &amp;ldquo;challenges&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; that plenty of us hop-on during our athletic life, and ultimately, draws on the conclusion that those challenges are useful only if they bring a purpose to a training / racing season, and more importantly, not injure ourselves in the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe it should be the same for setting up — and reviewing — your next goals:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set them up as well as you can, based on known ability and a reasonable outcome from your training programme. You must set them high enough so that there is a chance you could not quite make them, but low enough so that the chance of failure is only that: a chance. If you can put in the correct work, you WILL achieve them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You don&amp;rsquo;t have to kill yourself to finish an event (or a training session for that matter!). Chances are that if you&amp;rsquo;re not an elite or a pro, you are in the racing to have a target to aim for and enjoy the journey. Not prize money. If your aim is to qualify for some world championship events or similar, then that qualification should carry a tag reading &amp;ldquo;possibility of not achieving&amp;rdquo;, and you should be fine with that.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t compare yourself to other, much faster athletes. Unless you compare yourself with your training buddies who you know are quite evenly matched to you. There&amp;rsquo;s no point dwelling on the fact that you&amp;rsquo;ll never be a sub 9h ironman, or a 3h marathon runner etc etc&amp;hellip; Know where you stand, and be happy with what you can achieve. Whether it&amp;rsquo;s running a 5K or finishing an ironman, you&amp;rsquo;ll be an achiever, and identical on this point.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t be afraid of changing those goals. Ever. Again: not an elite? Then complete before compete. If life or injury comes in the mix of your training, you can adjust your results prospects to something more manageable and / or more achievable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be definitely prepared for not achieving those goals. But please don&amp;rsquo;t see that as a failure. You don&amp;rsquo;t fail when you train your butt off as close to the plan as possible. You don&amp;rsquo;t fail when you miss a training session. You don&amp;rsquo;t fail when you don&amp;rsquo;t quite get under the fictitious time bar you set yourself either. You may be disappointed a little bit, but you should never be disheartened, or dejected at the sport. If you are, then it&amp;rsquo;s a sign that you&amp;rsquo;re not enjoying it any-more and you need to re-focus and dial it down. Think about the journey and what that brings you. The end goal is a mere pretext to be on the journey.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m frequently told that what I do is fast and furious, top level stuff. No. It&amp;rsquo;s not. My personal goals may not be the same than yours or other people out there, but I&amp;rsquo;m still sticking to the above points. I am a bit disappointed with myself when I can&amp;rsquo;t do a training session, but all in all I reflect on past experiences and shrug it out: because it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter! I have not reached some goals in the past, and will definitely not reach many more in the future. It&amp;rsquo;s part of the training / racing process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not convinced? Here are some personal examples:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learn lessons:&lt;/strong&gt; In July 2011, I &lt;a href=&quot;http://tri.ekynoxe.com/hillingdon-sprint-or-my-first-dnf/&quot;&gt;DNF'ed at a local race&lt;/a&gt; because my rear mech went through my rear wheel on the last lap of the bike, a mile from the finish line (Hillingdon sprint is ran in a strange swim-run-bike format). I didn&amp;rsquo;t fall, I only skidded with a locked back wheel and stopped. I obviously couldn&amp;rsquo;t ride the bike any-more, but instead of walking that remaining mile to the finish, I made the mistake to take a lift from one of the marshals. That&amp;rsquo;s my biggest mistake to date and it won&amp;rsquo;t happen again.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Revise goals:&lt;/strong&gt; In 2012 &lt;a href=&quot;/the-outlaw-triathlon-2012-the-long-walk/&quot;&gt;I raced the Outlaw&lt;/a&gt;. I had a knee injury entering the race and I knew it full well. My very initial goal before injury was to go sub 10h overall. This couldn&amp;rsquo;t happen any-more. I thought I&amp;rsquo;d then try smash the bike in a proper long time trial before checking what would be left in the tank on the &amp;ldquo;run&amp;rdquo;. The conditions on the day, and my knee, didn&amp;rsquo;t let it happen either. Then I shuffled / walked the whole marathon. Some medics and volunteers at aid stations on the run course were drawing me to ambulances as I had been walking for ages, telling me the end of the lap wasn&amp;rsquo;t far if I needed to pull out. I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to, and I didn&amp;rsquo;t. My end time wasn&amp;rsquo;t too bad, although almost 2h slower than initially planned, but that didn&amp;rsquo;t matter. I had revised my goals, and I finished!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have a plan:&lt;/strong&gt; In 2013, &lt;a href=&quot;/ironman-lanzarote-2013-race-report/&quot;&gt;I did Ironman Lanzarote&lt;/a&gt;. I didn&amp;rsquo;t have other goals than to complete in the first place, but still, I injured my left ankle in training, and I simply couldn&amp;rsquo;t run, at all, for about 7 weeks. I only resumed some running with just about month before the race. The strategy therefore had to change, and after a great bike ride, I ran / walked the marathon. Definitely not what I wanted to do, and definitely not doing well for me not wanting to look like &amp;ldquo;another one who smashed the bike and blew up on the run&amp;rdquo;. But it was the plan! The hardest bit was to explain to people on course that I was absolutely fine and walking was intentional to relieve my ankle. I ran / walked and I still finished strong.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;At the end of the day, you are probably your hardest judge and critic. I live with someone who&amp;rsquo;s the harshest on herself I have ever seen anyone be, and I know very well that it&amp;rsquo;s hard not to be like this when you&amp;rsquo;re as determined as we all are in the sport. Talk to your fellow athletes friends and club-mates, let it all out there and listen to the feedback and advice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you can compete, that&amp;rsquo;s great, but before all, make sure you complete YOUR race with what you have at the time. And be happy with the result whatever it is, because you will know you have planned to do just that.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2014 18:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://ww.ekynoxe.com/its-your-race</link>
                <author>hello@ekynoxe.com (Mathieu Davy)</author>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ww.ekynoxe.com/its-your-race</guid>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>SO46 replacement mech hanger</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week I stupidly fell with my in the corridor at home. The new floor is some kind of plastic tilling that makes walking with cleats extremely slipper. Long story short: I fell ON my bike, with a backpack, and in the process bent and cracked the mech hanger on my Old Focus Variado 2007.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is an old bike, and like with many old things, finding parts is close to impossible. The hanger reference I needed is SO46, but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find it anywhere on-line, and even the manufacturer in US sent me back to &lt;a href=&quot;http://wheelsmfg.com/derailleur-hanger-42.html&quot;&gt;Wheels Manufacturing Inc.&lt;/a&gt; to check if they could help me. Unfortunately, I had no luck anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking at several models on-line, I found a few close matches and ordered three, including one supposedly for Bianchi bikes that looked very close. Funny enough, it&amp;rsquo;s a Evans that I found what I needed, and the only one who had them in stock!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-15-so46-replacement-mech-hanger/replacement_for_SO46_choice.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Replacement choice: two WMFG and one Bianchi... for a focus Bike&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[20140215]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-15-so46-replacement-mech-hanger/replacement_for_SO46_choice_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Replacement choice: two WMFG and one Bianchi... for a focus Bike&quot; /&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;small&gt;Replacement choice&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;None of the three were a perfect fit straight away. Both the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.evanscycles.com/products/bianchi/hanger-01-02-ec009107&quot;&gt;Bianchi&lt;/a&gt; or the &lt;a href=&quot;http://wheelsmfg.com/derailleur-hanger-41.html&quot;&gt;WMFG 41&lt;/a&gt; needed their top to be milled to properly align the bolt hole with the frame, while the &lt;a href=&quot;http://wheelsmfg.com/derailleur-hanger-42.html&quot;&gt;WMFG 42&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ldquo;only&amp;rdquo; needed the ridge to be removed. While the Bianchi seemed overall a closer fit, it also seemed weaker than the other two, so I elected to take the ridge out of the WMFG42. I took about 10 minutes with a mini drill, a cutting disc and some milling heads, but it went on without much of a problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if you have a bike that needs a hanger reference SO46, you can use a &lt;a href=&quot;http://wheelsmfg.com/derailleur-hanger-42.html&quot;&gt;Wheels MFG #42&lt;/a&gt; and remove the ridge. I&amp;rsquo;m posting this here because I know that if I break it again, I&amp;rsquo;ll have a place to look back for clues as to which one to get!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-15-so46-replacement-mech-hanger/WMG42_for_SO46.jpg&quot; title=&quot;A bit of disc and milling action&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[20140215]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-15-so46-replacement-mech-hanger/WMG42_for_SO46_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A bit of disc and milling action&quot; /&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;small&gt;A bit of disc and milling action&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-15-so46-replacement-mech-hanger/WMG42_for_SO46_mounted.jpg&quot; title=&quot;As new! Well, almost.&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[20140215]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-15-so46-replacement-mech-hanger/WMG42_for_SO46_mounted_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;As new! Well, almost.&quot; /&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;small&gt;As new! Well, almost.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



</description>
                <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2014 20:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://ww.ekynoxe.com/so46-replacement-mech-hanger</link>
                <author>hello@ekynoxe.com (Mathieu Davy)</author>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ww.ekynoxe.com/so46-replacement-mech-hanger</guid>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>2014 Iceman off-road duathlon</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Race 3 of the Human race off road series was the Iceman. Held on January 25th 2014, I was expecting a lot colder conditions than at the previous races, but it was in fact quite mild, and instead of ice&amp;hellip; we had mud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-07-2014-iceman-off-road-duathlon/iceman_mud.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Iceman: Done! (photo Marsha El-Hage)&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[20131117]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-07-2014-iceman-off-road-duathlon/iceman_mud_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Iceman: Done! (photo Marsha El-Hage)&quot; /&gt;&lt;span&gt;Iceman: Done!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;small&gt;(photo Marsha El-Hage)&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;!--more--&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I was slightly disappointed that the Mudman was in fact the &amp;ldquo;Hillman&amp;rdquo;, and there was barely any mud to contend with. Not that my MTB skills at the time could have coped, but I wanted to get dirty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has now been done! Coming out of the iceman, I was properly covered in sticky black stuff, and grinning from ear to ear from having tamed a proper slippery course. 4th proper mountain bike ride at speed, and finally some deep mud!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the weather was so horrendous for the few weeks before the race with flooding everywhere, I elected to steal Ellen&amp;rsquo;s wheels, since they had Contis Mountain King on them, which, even if not proper mud tyres, would work better than my shallower studded ones.
I had a chuckle looking at them with their reflectors and chain guard, but that would prove the point that the machine doesn&amp;rsquo;t play a massive role in having a great race.
At more than 13Kg, I have a heavy entry level bike complete with reflectors and bell. It&amp;rsquo;s obviously no match for full carbon bikes like &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/JohnBrame&quot; title=&quot;John Brame on Twitter&quot;&gt;John&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; Rose Psycho Path that weighs the best part of 6Kg less (!), but I&amp;rsquo;m having fun :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the morning of the race, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t feeling that well rested after a week of hard training, but the weather helped a lot in feeling better. This time, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t windy or too cold, and the sun was making an appearance, so there would only be a lot of mud to contend with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After waving the RGActive peeps good luck for their trail run, I started the first run conservatively and not too close from the front of the pack. That was intentional so I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t get too carried away on the first lap. I felt tired on that first leg, and I my left ankle was getting a little twitchy again, so I wanted to be in control of my run. It was pretty hard to start with, with a lot of people around making it difficult to look where to land my feet. But after the first lap I settled into a nice rhythm, including the hills which I mostly walked to make sure I didn&amp;rsquo;t cramp later on in the race. There was a lot of mud and deep puddles that I initially mostly managed to avoid before being inevitably being covered in mud and not caring any-more.
Compared to the Mudman, the course this time had a nicer mix of short very steep hills and long flat-ish portions on which it was possible to recuperate a little bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took my time in T1 as usual. I&amp;rsquo;m in those races for the fun of it, and I was feeling al-right after the run &amp;ldquo;warm-up&amp;rdquo;. Strangely however the bike started with my legs screaming. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure why, maybe the lack of brick practice or the week of training, but it took me a little time to settle in any kind of pace. The going went easier and easier each lap and it was fantastic to be greeted every time by the ever cheerful &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/RGActive&quot; title=&quot;RGActive on Twitter&quot;&gt;RGActive crew&lt;/a&gt;. No D3 friends this time, but those guys more than make up for it!
There were some deep mud and water sections on/in which I had never ridden before, so I had a few hairy moments where my front or back wheel would slide away from under the bike, but I clung on and didn&amp;rsquo;t fall off this time. It was, on the whole, more technical than the previous races, but like the run, had short steep climbs and longer rolling sections.
Being less relentless than the Mudman, but having great terrain variety and still keeping a nice forest feel throughout the course, that is so far ma favourite ride of the series.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I only had to un-clip once on one of the steep hills as I was in the wrong gear when someone stopped dead in front of me. But that was almost at the top of the climb so that didn&amp;rsquo;t hinder my progress too much.
With the winter turbo training, I have now a lot more power in my legs than when the series started, and I can really feel it since I can power up hills rather than having to push the bike.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only issue I had (again) on the ride was that I was almost unable to take my bottle out of it&amp;rsquo;s cage. I really need to change that one for racing, but I don&amp;rsquo;t want to lose a bottle. Any suggestions?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the 3rd lap, although sometimes caught up in the midst of people one lap down, I kept picking up places regularly, and was feeling better and better.
T2 was a welcome short break before heading out on the final run lap, but I was quite surprised at the low number of bikes in there. There were about 25 bikes in the whole transition area when I arrived, so I wasn&amp;rsquo;t far off the front!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I felt tired on first run and couldn&amp;rsquo;t settle initially because of the amount of people around, it was a stark contrast on the last leg, and I was happy to be almost alone for the whole of the second one. Legs were now feeling fine (well, aside the normal race tightness at this stage), and I powered through that last leg, picking up everyone I had in sight. In fact, I picked up 7 places between T2 and the finish, feeling good in the process, so it proves that the strategy to start easy is paying off well!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m glad it&amp;rsquo;s over, but I enjoyed this one a lot more than the Mudman which was a little too hard for comfort at the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s now only one race left in the series, and after increasing my ranking every time through the first three races, I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to see how far up the series leader boards I can go! I&amp;rsquo;m now 17th overall, 5th in my age group, so it&amp;rsquo;s not too bad for a first dab into off-road racing so far!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;table_container&quot;&gt;
    &lt;table&gt;
        &lt;thead&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
                &lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
                &lt;th&gt;time&lt;/th&gt;
                &lt;th&gt;GPS data&lt;/th&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;/thead&gt;
        &lt;tbody&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;Run1 (10K)&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;48'33&quot;&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;run1 data&quot; href=&quot;http://connect.garmin.com/activity/435341543&quot;&gt;data&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;T1&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;1'48&quot;&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;Bike (18K)&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;1h04'37&quot;&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;bike data&quot; href=&quot;http://connect.garmin.com/activity/435341553&quot;&gt;data&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;T2&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;1'02&quot;&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;Run2 (5K)&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;23'12&quot;&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;run2 data&quot; href=&quot;http://connect.garmin.com/activity/435341565&quot;&gt;data&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;/tbody&gt;
    &lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Total: 2h19'14&quot; (20th overall, 18th male and 6th in M30-34)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;gallery&quot;&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-07-2014-iceman-off-road-duathlon/iceman_mud.jpg&quot; title=&quot;iceman_mud_r300.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[20131117]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-07-2014-iceman-off-road-duathlon/iceman_mud_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;iceman_mud_r300.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-07-2014-iceman-off-road-duathlon/MIM14_GAG_002455.jpg&quot; title=&quot;MIM14_GAG_002455_r300.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[20131117]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-07-2014-iceman-off-road-duathlon/MIM14_GAG_002455_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;MIM14_GAG_002455_r300.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-07-2014-iceman-off-road-duathlon/MIM14_GAG_002457.jpg&quot; title=&quot;MIM14_GAG_002457_r300.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[20131117]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-07-2014-iceman-off-road-duathlon/MIM14_GAG_002457_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;MIM14_GAG_002457_r300.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-07-2014-iceman-off-road-duathlon/MIM14_GAG_002458.jpg&quot; title=&quot;MIM14_GAG_002458_r300.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[20131117]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-07-2014-iceman-off-road-duathlon/MIM14_GAG_002458_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;MIM14_GAG_002458_r300.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-07-2014-iceman-off-road-duathlon/MIM14_GAG_002853.jpg&quot; title=&quot;MIM14_GAG_002853_r300.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[20131117]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-07-2014-iceman-off-road-duathlon/MIM14_GAG_002853_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;MIM14_GAG_002853_r300.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-07-2014-iceman-off-road-duathlon/MIM14_GAG_002854.jpg&quot; title=&quot;MIM14_GAG_002854_r300.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[20131117]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-07-2014-iceman-off-road-duathlon/MIM14_GAG_002854_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;MIM14_GAG_002854_r300.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-07-2014-iceman-off-road-duathlon/MIM14_GAG_002855.jpg&quot; title=&quot;MIM14_GAG_002855_r300.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[20131117]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-07-2014-iceman-off-road-duathlon/MIM14_GAG_002855_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;MIM14_GAG_002855_r300.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-07-2014-iceman-off-road-duathlon/MIM14_ROK_000192.jpg&quot; title=&quot;MIM14_ROK_000192_r300.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[20131117]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-07-2014-iceman-off-road-duathlon/MIM14_ROK_000192_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;MIM14_ROK_000192_r300.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-07-2014-iceman-off-road-duathlon/MIM14_ROK_000193.jpg&quot; title=&quot;MIM14_ROK_000193_r300.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[20131117]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-07-2014-iceman-off-road-duathlon/MIM14_ROK_000193_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;MIM14_ROK_000193_r300.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-07-2014-iceman-off-road-duathlon/MIM14_ROK_000194.jpg&quot; title=&quot;MIM14_ROK_000194_r300.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[20131117]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-07-2014-iceman-off-road-duathlon/MIM14_ROK_000194_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;MIM14_ROK_000194_r300.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-07-2014-iceman-off-road-duathlon/MIM14_ROK_001637.jpg&quot; title=&quot;MIM14_ROK_001637_r300.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[20131117]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-07-2014-iceman-off-road-duathlon/MIM14_ROK_001637_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;MIM14_ROK_001637_r300.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-07-2014-iceman-off-road-duathlon/MIM14_ROK_001638.jpg&quot; title=&quot;MIM14_ROK_001638_r300.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[20131117]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-07-2014-iceman-off-road-duathlon/MIM14_ROK_001638_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;MIM14_ROK_001638_r300.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-07-2014-iceman-off-road-duathlon/MIM14_ROK_001639.jpg&quot; title=&quot;MIM14_ROK_001639_r300.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[20131117]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-07-2014-iceman-off-road-duathlon/MIM14_ROK_001639_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;MIM14_ROK_001639_r300.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-07-2014-iceman-off-road-duathlon/MIM14_TOM_003466.jpg&quot; title=&quot;MIM14_TOM_003466_r300.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[20131117]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-07-2014-iceman-off-road-duathlon/MIM14_TOM_003466_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;MIM14_TOM_003466_r300.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-07-2014-iceman-off-road-duathlon/MIM14_TOM_003467.jpg&quot; title=&quot;MIM14_TOM_003467_r300.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[20131117]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-07-2014-iceman-off-road-duathlon/MIM14_TOM_003467_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;MIM14_TOM_003467_r300.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-07-2014-iceman-off-road-duathlon/MIM14_TOM_003468.jpg&quot; title=&quot;MIM14_TOM_003468_r300.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[20131117]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-07-2014-iceman-off-road-duathlon/MIM14_TOM_003468_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;MIM14_TOM_003468_r300.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-07-2014-iceman-off-road-duathlon/MIM14_TOM_003469.jpg&quot; title=&quot;MIM14_TOM_003469_r300.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[20131117]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-07-2014-iceman-off-road-duathlon/MIM14_TOM_003469_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;MIM14_TOM_003469_r300.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-07-2014-iceman-off-road-duathlon/MIM14_TOM_003977.jpg&quot; title=&quot;MIM14_TOM_003977_r300.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[20131117]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-07-2014-iceman-off-road-duathlon/MIM14_TOM_003977_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;MIM14_TOM_003977_r300.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-07-2014-iceman-off-road-duathlon/MIM14_TOM_003978.jpg&quot; title=&quot;MIM14_TOM_003978_r300.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[20131117]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-07-2014-iceman-off-road-duathlon/MIM14_TOM_003978_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;MIM14_TOM_003978_r300.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-07-2014-iceman-off-road-duathlon/MIM14_TOM_003979.jpg&quot; title=&quot;MIM14_TOM_003979_r300.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[20131117]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-07-2014-iceman-off-road-duathlon/MIM14_TOM_003979_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;MIM14_TOM_003979_r300.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-07-2014-iceman-off-road-duathlon/MIM14_TOM_004315.jpg&quot; title=&quot;MIM14_TOM_004315_r300.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[20131117]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-07-2014-iceman-off-road-duathlon/MIM14_TOM_004315_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;MIM14_TOM_004315_r300.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-07-2014-iceman-off-road-duathlon/MIM14_TOM_004316.jpg&quot; title=&quot;MIM14_TOM_004316_r300.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[20131117]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-02-07-2014-iceman-off-road-duathlon/MIM14_TOM_004316_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;MIM14_TOM_004316_r300.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;



</description>
                <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2014 23:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://ww.ekynoxe.com/2014-iceman-off-road-duathlon</link>
                <author>hello@ekynoxe.com (Mathieu Davy)</author>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ww.ekynoxe.com/2014-iceman-off-road-duathlon</guid>
            </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>