<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Ekynoxe - Mathieu Davy's triathlon ramblings</title>
        <description>Mathieu Davy's triathlon ramblings</description>
        <link>http://tri.ekynoxe.com</link>
        <atom:link href="http://tri.ekynoxe.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <pubDate>Sat, 27 Sep 2014 14:58:05 +0100</pubDate>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Sep 2014 14:58:05 +0100</lastBuildDate>
        
            <item>
                <title>How British bicycles were made in 1945</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Although now what many would consider a proper geek, I&amp;rsquo;ve always been an engineer at heart, and I haven&amp;rsquo;t forgotten my times in mechanical engineering. Watching this video is for me a fantastic highlight about manufacturing processes, all applied to one of the greatest inventions ever: the bicycle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was filmed in 1945 apparently, 60 odd years ago. Judging by the amount of workers and machinery in this British factory, the bike was then clearly the most convenient way to get around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;The bicycle is a comfortable and cheap way of getting about. A great boon to man, ideal for shopping, easy to park. And if at work, a faithful friend, ever ready to take tired workers back home, and after work, to bring relaxation, health and happiness.&lt;/blockquote&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/cyclr&quot;&gt;@cyclr&lt;/a&gt; for sharing this one!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;attachement iframe_wrapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&quot;//player.vimeo.com/video/39401575&quot; webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
                <pubDate>Sat, 23 Aug 2014 09:28:00 +0100</pubDate>
                <link>http://tri.ekynoxe.com/how-british-bicycles-were-made-in-1945</link>
                <author>hello@ekynoxe.com (Mathieu Davy)</author>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://tri.ekynoxe.com/how-british-bicycles-were-made-in-1945</guid>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Ironman Lanzarote 2014</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Last year&amp;rsquo;s ironman Lanzarote was fun. Yes, I dare say it! I had a ball and a fantastic result. With a full year of proper training and all indicators telling me I had made massive progress across the board, this year should have been an absolute blast. I had good hopes of smashing it even more, and was even eyeing a top ten finish, close to the magical 10h mark.
It didn&amp;rsquo;t quite go that way, but I still had a good race.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-06-13-ironman-lanzarote-2014/DSC_1108_r1024.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Back towards Teguise&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2014-06-11]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-06-13-ironman-lanzarote-2014/DSC_1108_r500.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Back towards Teguise&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;!--more--&gt;


&lt;p&gt;With my improved abilities this year, 10h seemed doable at first sight: 1h05 swim, 5h25 bike, 3h20 run. Plus 10min for my snail transitions with a coffee, cake, hair do and whatever else I feel like on the day :-D The 5h25 bike was still a tall order, but if conditions were OK, I was confident I could get pretty close to that. But this was all on paper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reality on the island can be brutal, and even though last year&amp;rsquo;s race was windy by all accounts, this year was even windier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been very windy on the island the previous week, and during the days prior to the race the wind was mostly blowing from the south-west. If it was fun to climb Fire Mountain flat out with a tail wind in training, the thought of race day going back towards town on the the LZ-1 motorway in a headwind wasn&amp;rsquo;t particularly something I fancied.
The wind direction went back to normal for race day, but it unfortunately picked-up more and was already well established before we had even started&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&amp;ldquo;In a washing-machine with Greco-Roman wrestlers on spin cycle&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like last year, I started my swim on the right hand side, but this time, I was almost at the front, closer to the 60min marker. Training told me I should be able to be close to the hour and a few minutes, and with plenty of fast feet to follow on the first lap, I should get a decent tow and I was hoping to break 1h05.
Neither happened, and I had a bad swim. No, I had a properly shit swim! I&amp;rsquo;ve since been told that I should not say this since I&amp;rsquo;m still faster than many aspiring triathletes and &amp;ldquo;completers&amp;rdquo;, but I&amp;rsquo;m only being honest with myself here: it&amp;rsquo;s crap for my goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As expected, it was rough. But I didn&amp;rsquo;t anticipate it being &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; rough. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if it was due to the increased number of entrants - raised from 1800 to almost 2300 - or the slightly different course design, but the first lap was carnage all the way around. I didn&amp;rsquo;t even see the first buoy and barely caught a glimpse of the line of yellow floats on the outside leg. That&amp;rsquo;s how far out I was. And it was impossible (or desirable for me to be honest) to get closer to the ropes. I got pummelled, swam over, swam under, my swim hat got pulled off, my goggles knocked away and I had limbs flying into me from directions I can only imaging a contortionist swimmer would be able to do.
In the melee, I managed to grab my swim hat and tuck it in my wetsuit, readjusted my goggles and I kept on going to finish the first lap in&amp;hellip; 32min. Like last year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-06-13-ironman-lanzarote-2014/DSC_1042_r1024.jpg&quot; title=&quot;The usual melee&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2014-06-11]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-06-13-ironman-lanzarote-2014/DSC_1042_r500.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The usual melee&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I wasn&amp;rsquo;t too worried at this point, but I knew I couldn&amp;rsquo;t hang around too much if I wanted to get close to 1h05.
The second lap was calmer, and this time I managed to actually see the buoys at the turns and get pretty close! That lap &lt;em&gt;felt&lt;/em&gt; substantially faster and simple maths tell that 32' x 2 = 1h04', right? No. Not at all. That second lap had been terrible. Exiting the water, the race timer was nearing on 1h08, so I knew straight away that it was already game over for my (ambitious) goal of hitting 10h.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like last year, I faded out in the second lap. And out of all the improvements I made in training, I got nothing for my swim. It was even 1min slower this time around. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure how accurate the Garmin data is, but it told me I swam almost 4.3K!! If that&amp;rsquo;s correct, it gives me a pace closer to what I know I can swim, but still, that&amp;rsquo;s not a great result for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Speedy gear change&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the memorable &lt;a href=&quot;/ironman-70-3-zell-am-see-2013-the-wet-one/&quot; title=&quot;Ironman 70.3 Zell Am See race report&quot;&gt;70.3 Zell Am See&lt;/a&gt; and its glorious 13min of combined transitions, I tried reduce the time I spend having a coffee and a natter on the T1 benches, and I&amp;rsquo;m almost pleased with my T1 this time. No socks, no gloves, just a helmet and the cover for my shoulders and arms. Those are the ones that cost me time, but if you&amp;rsquo;ve got my complexion, you have to be careful! 9h of bike + run in the blazing sun would ensure I kill my skin in a single event. Just under 6min including the runs on the beach and outside of the bike racks isn&amp;rsquo;t too bad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;T1 was over in 5'46&quot;, and I was out of the zone about 5min later than I wanted overall, with a lot of work to do. But I had a nice target to catch as &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.joannacarritt.co.uk&quot; title=&quot;Joanna Carritt&quot;&gt;Jo, my coach&lt;/a&gt;, was up the road. Well, I hoped she was anyway, and the initial plan was to make the pass by the top of Fire Mountain, about 50Km into the ride.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Shit swim = bike overtake galore!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year, I started hard. I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to cruise the first bit and have way too much left in the tank later. Last year, I didn&amp;rsquo;t know what I could do, and I ended up riding about 20W under what I should have been doing. So this year I pushed on. The wind was already strong early in the day, and I knew it would be a tough ride, but the bike is where I usually make my time, and everyone is on the same course, so I hit it hard and started my usual overtaking frenzy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was still a bit of cloud cover after the swim, so it wasn&amp;rsquo;t searing hot just yet, and I was pleased to see that I was a lot closer to the lead pros than last year. I could only see the 2 lead guys getting out of the El Golfo loop when I was going down towards its start. Last year, there was a stream of pros already coming back up the LZ-2, so this gave me a bit of an extra boost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;El Golfo is always special to ride. It&amp;rsquo;s always almost traffic free as there is pretty much nothing around it, and is fast rolling terrain on silky smooth roads, with just enough inclines and tight turns to remind you to work a little bit.
It wasn&amp;rsquo;t the &lt;a href=&quot;/every-day-training-camp-day-1/&quot; title=&quot;Every day training camp. Day 1.&quot;&gt;24min blast&lt;/a&gt; I did on camp a couple of months ago though, and while the legs where still relatively fresh, I had to fight my head against hammering the 10mi loop. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t a day to try and &amp;ldquo;set new course records&amp;rdquo;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what the camp experience gave me was something else than my watts to focus on. And while I was thinking about the camp ride, the miles passed, the second aid station as well, and in what felt like no time at all, I was back grinding it up towards Yaiza, and ready for the left turn for Fire Mountain uphill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like that climb up Fire Mountain. But that&amp;rsquo;s because I know it now. Its massive fields of serrated lava rocks, and that single, long, straight, uphill road, in a nice and strong headwind can destroy you mentally. When you have reached the first bend you can see from the bottom, you think you&amp;rsquo;re there! No. There&amp;rsquo;s another bend. It must be the top! No. There is still a little bit of hard work in what is now a funnel for all the wind Lanzarote can howl at you. And it&amp;rsquo;s still going up. If you don&amp;rsquo;t know that, or haven&amp;rsquo;t ridden it before, you&amp;rsquo;re in for a surprise. But well, you&amp;rsquo;re in a hard place and you came for it, so suck it up!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fire Mountain over, whizzing down that left hand bend on the other side. Avoiding a line of cars who decided to stop dead in the middle of the road to get into the National park. Thinking about nutrition. And pace. And Jo&amp;hellip; Where is Jo? I know my swim wasn&amp;rsquo;t great, but it wasn&amp;rsquo;t THAT disastrous. And I&amp;rsquo;m sure she didn&amp;rsquo;t plan for me going that hard in the first climbs either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s only after Mancha Blanca and Tinajo, at the beginning of the descent towards La Santa, that I caught her. And it was all pretty hard work. Usually, the wind around there is across the road, trying to blow away the big guys with disc wheels. This time it was pretty much head on. So the downhill was now as hard as a hard flat stage, and that would need to be paid for later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, one thing that was working well this year was nutrition. Even pushing quite hard, I managed to get down some food and gels, and I didn&amp;rsquo;t regret the decision of going with only one frame bottle, ditching the massive bracket from under my saddle. Weight saving from both the bracket and a 750ml bottle that I would have carried around the course like last year&amp;hellip; It was also a lot more reassuring as I didn&amp;rsquo;t have to constantly check that my bottles were still there, which is handy around some special bits of road on the island!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ticking off the miles, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t as easy as usual, especially when I reached the climb to Mirador de Haria. This is the hardest one because of its length. After that, it&amp;rsquo;s almost job done. Ok, there are still a few kicks to get to Mirador del Rio, and a further 60K to follow, but I find Haria to be the hardest with the switchbacks and the head wind.
There, I passed a few other competitors and a couple of pro women, including Kristin Möller - last year&amp;rsquo;s winner - who was visibly not having the best of days. She would eventually storm past me on the run, but that was still encouraging.
Focusing on the climb was made a bit easier having my &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.blacklinelondon.com&quot; title=&quot;Follow the Black Line&quot;&gt;Black Line London&lt;/a&gt; bottle at the front of the bike.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-06-13-ironman-lanzarote-2014/IMG_3532_r1024.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Black Line support&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2014-06-11]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-06-13-ironman-lanzarote-2014/IMG_3532_r500.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Black Line support&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Having just been asked to join the group was a massive boost to my confidence, and a kick to the backside knowing at least a few would be following.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the time I reached the top of Mirador del Rio, I could feel my hamstrings being very tense, so it was a relief to hit the downhill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I passed a couple of guys there, including one who almost dragged me outside a bend and had me hit my brakes like I never did before. I now know that the Zipp cork pads have amazing stopping power if you squeeze them enough. The smell of burnt cork afterwards was however a warning sign for me not to do that kind of stuff too often! Still, I was now on my own and blazing down towards Arieta and the LZ-1. I would hopefully get a good tailwind and a push before the struggle back up towards Teguise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This section wasn&amp;rsquo;t as easy as I remembered it - probably because of the previous efforts this time - but I was still maintaining my target wattage, and managing my legs. The right turn for the climb towards Teguise brought the usual headwind and I put my head down to reach the &amp;ldquo;Paris-Roubaix&amp;rdquo; section as fast as I could, passing dad for a quick photo and a &amp;ldquo;thumbs up&amp;rdquo;, then hung on to the bars for 3Km, dodging potholes and the few water bottles that were already there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-06-13-ironman-lanzarote-2014/DSC_1109_r1024.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Head down towards Nazaret&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2014-06-11]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-06-13-ironman-lanzarote-2014/DSC_1109_r500.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Head down towards Nazaret&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;When I reached the other end, a sigh of relief is all I had! I was now only looking forward to my next mental checkpoint: the 100 miles mark right by the El Griffo winery. We stopped there on camp during our IM route ride on the last day as it was Simon&amp;rsquo;s first 100 miler. It was the perfect reminder that there were only 12 miles left of riding, with only a tiny little crest to go over before the massive downhill of Coníl and the &amp;ldquo;donkey track&amp;rdquo;. 80kph towards Tias and a flashback of the burnt cork in the north of the island reminded me to brake a little earlier this time, but I could also smell the restaurants along the sea front. They would tickle my nostrils for the next 3.5h or so&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Yet another natter&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dismounting for T2 was a breeze. Now with my velcro strap shoes, long gone are the problems with my boa shoes I had at Zell am See, and I could run quickly over the carpet. Legs were working ok, speedy feet, run, run, run more&amp;hellip; Damn where is everyone!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like last year, I had ridden myself in a nice position overall, and had to push my bike for an age before picking up my run bag.
Although I tried and tried again this year, I didn&amp;rsquo;t manage to really pee on the bike. So I needed a long pit stop before the changing tent. That toilet stop on its own was not short, but then time must have accelerated, or disappeared, or distorted, or done something funny&amp;hellip; I have no idea what happened, but I spent 6min in T2. And I have absolutely no flipping idea HOW I managed to stay that long in the zone!
Granted it&amp;rsquo;s a long one, but there&amp;rsquo;s literally nothing to do!
Do you guys sit in transition? I did. Maybe that&amp;rsquo;s where I also had a nap, redone my hair and adjusted my kit&amp;hellip; I am happy with T1, but T2 was crap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Snack stops&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But hey, there was still a marathon to run so off I went. I was a bit lighter than last year, having chosen not to carry two flasks of coke all the way around the course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a flurry of complaints after last year&amp;rsquo;s race about the complete lack of cola on the run leg, they brought some back this year, but ONLY at aid stations not giving red bull. It tells you a thing or two about the goal of big brands and their monopoly on big events such as this one. It&amp;rsquo;s all a big money making machine, and the organisation doesn&amp;rsquo;t fully care what you as an athlete would prefer or would need. They just go for big $$$ contracts. At least they&amp;rsquo;ve done something this year, but it didn&amp;rsquo;t seem that this was really something they really thought through.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I started my run quite well, hitting my race pace straight away with what seemed ease at the time&amp;hellip; This became harder about 6Km in the run when I reached the airport, where the headwind hit hard until the turnaround. The course had changed this year - possibly to avoid overcrowding of the run course in town due to the increased number of entries - and there was now two long laps instead of a single one. This would prove challenging, especially in the wind and heat along the airport strip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After I reached the first turnaround point, my pace went up again and I was feeling just about ok, pushing myself to stick to my target pace. I have pushed substantially more this year on the bike, but I knew I would need to be stronger mentally to get my run properly done. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t far off my target pace, and I was ticking aid stations alright, thinking about the first special needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once again, my dad was with me on the island this year, and we had agreed that he would be at the special needs aid station. I asked him to hand me some crisps when I was passing by, but what I should have done is to brief him on how to do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t tell him to have a bowl or something from which I could snatch a few crisps. So he did what he thought best: hand over an open packet. That was impractical, and that gave me an excuse to stop. Big tactical mistake: I was now stopping, taking some crisps, talking to him, and basically wasting a long time there. Getting deeper into the run and in the mental state where you should be battling yourself and push on, I had lost the focus I needed. Over the next laps, he wasn&amp;rsquo;t even ready with the salty treats, instead taking photos from the other side of the road first, then only crossing to giving me the precious salt. He did only what I asked for: handing me crisps. At no point did he comment on how I looked or how he think I was doing, he was only following my instructions, and he did real well. This mistake was my fault entirely, and I should have told him to give me a kick in the backside to keep going and not stop for that long a time. I should have asked him to urge me on, and lie to me that I was only 20s behind the guy in front of me or something like this. Hell, next time, I&amp;rsquo;ll ask him to time me if I really have to stop!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But because I now had a reason, I stopped, twice, on each lap. Not even seeing Jo being only about 2km behind me on the way out for the second lap changed this. I can sadly say that I had pretty much given up mentally at this point. And there was absolutely no reason to do so! Legs were a bit tight, but not doing too bad. I could pick up the pace when I wanted (cue the last 5km), and pouring ice everywhere I could on me and in my pants helped to keep me cool. (I blame Chrissie Wellington for the idea, but it works!) A massive ice cube in each hand for a few kilometres is also a fantastic way to feel cooler, and have a little distraction from the airport heat and the sand flying in your face. So my run has been a bit up and down with a few walks and 4 stops.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the last lap, the short one, I walked a couple of aid stations again, but I wasn&amp;rsquo;t feeling too bad. The run course was getting very busy, though, especially coming back into town. But I managed to gradually pick up the pace up to the final 2km, at which point I felt really good. I was and passing guys who were also on their way to the finish, but looked substantially more tired! &amp;ldquo;Blue band scalp, yeah!&amp;rdquo; I was gaining places! As I did so, I heard heavy breathing and fast feet getting close to me. Feeling good, there was NO WAY I was going to let anyone through without a fight at that point!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being around 2km from the line, and having still quite a bit of energy in the legs, I dug deeper, keeping the &amp;ldquo;heavy breather&amp;rdquo; behind me, dodging spectators, other runners (and the idiot from Club la Santa on his bike who was not opening the way but pissing everyone off on the narrow lane). I finished with a 4'17&quot; last Km in order to maintain position. Sadly, because of all my snack stops though, I didn&amp;rsquo;t really improve on last year&amp;rsquo;s run time when I really had the legs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t see dad in the finish chute either, but he was there and took a few shots as I &amp;ldquo;sprinted&amp;rdquo; to the end. For having supported Ellen at a long race in the past (not even a full IM!), I know how hard it is. So thanks to you dad for being there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-06-13-ironman-lanzarote-2014/DSC_1137_r1024.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Keeping him at bay&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2014-06-11]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-06-13-ironman-lanzarote-2014/DSC_1137_r500.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Keeping him at bay&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Finish time: 10h21. PB by 13min, improved last year&amp;rsquo;s time on this course by 16min, mostly on the bike and transitions, even though that&amp;rsquo;s not was I came for. I wanted a sub 1h05 swim, and I&amp;rsquo;m sure I had something a lot closer to 3h20 in my run legs. I could spend an age trying to find excuses, but there are none. I just need to work (a lot) more on my swim, and get stronger mentally for the run and avoid silly mistakes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking at my splits positions in my AG, it&amp;rsquo;s pretty obvious what I need to work on: swim: 110th, bike: 15th, run: 21st. Top 10 was 15min away, top 5 a crazy 29min away! Lanza is hard, but it&amp;rsquo;s equally hard to qualify there.
I&amp;rsquo;ll want to be more careful in the races I chose next year if I want to qualify for Kona. The more I think about it, the less I want to commit to that, but I&amp;rsquo;ll probably make it my goal for next year, and if it doesn&amp;rsquo;t happen, forget about it. There are some fundamentals about WTC that I really start to dislike, but that&amp;rsquo;s for another post&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unlike after any race before, I had a massive post race blues this time. No motivation to do anything at all, and not just training. That&amp;rsquo;s something I never experienced in the past. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if it was because I didn&amp;rsquo;t meet my ambitious goals or because I had completed THE race for 2014, but it has now more or less passed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I finish writing this post almost a month after the race, and 2 days before the next: 70.3 UK, which promises to be a tough one. This time, since I&amp;rsquo;m already qualified for the 70.3 WC, I have no other pressure than completing and have fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks everyone who still supports me despite thinking I&amp;rsquo;m mad. Thanks to Ellen my other half, once more coping with my training until now and caring for my niggles when they appeared. Thanks to the Black Line for the mental strength. Thanks dad&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Results and data&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;table_container&quot;&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;
    &lt;/th&gt;

    &lt;th&gt;
    &lt;/th&gt;

    &lt;th&gt;
      data
    &lt;/th&gt;

    &lt;th&gt;
      overall rank
    &lt;/th&gt;

    &lt;th&gt;
      AG rank
    &lt;/th&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;

  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      Swim (3.8K)
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td&gt;
      1h07'56&quot;
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td&gt;
      &lt;a title=&quot;swim data&quot; href=&quot;http://connect.garmin.com/modern/activity/501286064&quot;&gt;swim data&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td&gt;
      596
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td&gt;
      111
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;

  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      T1
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td&gt;
      5'46&quot;
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td&gt;
      &lt;a title=&quot;T1 data&quot; href=&quot;http://connect.garmin.com/modern/activity/501286065&quot;&gt;T1 data&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;

  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      Bike (180K)
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td&gt;
      5h33'14&quot;
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td&gt;
      &lt;a title=&quot;bike data&quot; href=&quot;http://connect.garmin.com/modern/activity/501286069&quot;&gt;bike data&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td&gt;
      135
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td&gt;
      26
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;

  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      T2
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td&gt;
      6'08&quot;
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td&gt;
      &lt;a title=&quot;T2 data&quot; href=&quot;http://connect.garmin.com/modern/activity/501286090&quot;&gt;T2 data&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;

  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      Run (42.2K)
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td&gt;
      3h28'12&quot;
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td&gt;
      &lt;a title=&quot;run data&quot; href=&quot;http://connect.garmin.com/modern/activity/501286094&quot;&gt;run data&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td&gt;
      121
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td&gt;
      21
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;

  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      Finish
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td&gt;
      10h21'18&quot;
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;In terms of ranks, I finish overall 4 places further down than last year, but since there was a lot more pros this year, and 10 more ahead of me at the finish, I actually moved up overall by 6 places, and by 4 in my age group. It&amp;rsquo;s not what I hoped for, but it&amp;rsquo;s definitely not bad either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I finally broke my PB set in Barcelona 3 years ago on a flat course. Next one will have to be under 10h!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finish Overall position: 121th, 114th male and 21th in my age group.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;gallery&quot;&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-06-13-ironman-lanzarote-2014/DSC_0984_r1024.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC_0984_r300.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2014-06-11]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-06-13-ironman-lanzarote-2014/DSC_0984_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;DSC_0984_r300.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-06-13-ironman-lanzarote-2014/DSC_0990_r1024.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC_0990_r300.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2014-06-11]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-06-13-ironman-lanzarote-2014/DSC_0990_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;DSC_0990_r300.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-06-13-ironman-lanzarote-2014/DSC_1032_r1024.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC_1032_r300.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2014-06-11]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-06-13-ironman-lanzarote-2014/DSC_1032_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;DSC_1032_r300.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-06-13-ironman-lanzarote-2014/DSC_1040_r1024.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC_1040_r300.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2014-06-11]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-06-13-ironman-lanzarote-2014/DSC_1040_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;DSC_1040_r300.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-06-13-ironman-lanzarote-2014/DSC_1042_r1024.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC_1042_r300.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2014-06-11]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-06-13-ironman-lanzarote-2014/DSC_1042_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;DSC_1042_r300.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-06-13-ironman-lanzarote-2014/0702_041166_r1024.jpg&quot; title=&quot;0702_041166_r300.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2014-06-11]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-06-13-ironman-lanzarote-2014/0702_041166_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;0702_041166_r300.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-06-13-ironman-lanzarote-2014/0702_000710_r1024.jpg&quot; title=&quot;0702_000710_r300.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2014-06-11]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-06-13-ironman-lanzarote-2014/0702_000710_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;0702_000710_r300.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-06-13-ironman-lanzarote-2014/0702_000711_r1024.jpg&quot; title=&quot;0702_000711_r300.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2014-06-11]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-06-13-ironman-lanzarote-2014/0702_000711_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;0702_000711_r300.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-06-13-ironman-lanzarote-2014/0702_049403_r1024.jpg&quot; title=&quot;0702_049403_r300.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2014-06-11]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-06-13-ironman-lanzarote-2014/0702_049403_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;0702_049403_r300.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-06-13-ironman-lanzarote-2014/DSC_1083_r1024.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC_1083_r300.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2014-06-11]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-06-13-ironman-lanzarote-2014/DSC_1083_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;DSC_1083_r300.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
           &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-06-13-ironman-lanzarote-2014/IMG_3532_r1024.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Black Line support&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2014-06-11]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-06-13-ironman-lanzarote-2014/IMG_3532_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Black Line support&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-06-13-ironman-lanzarote-2014/0702_004031_r1024.jpg&quot; title=&quot;0702_004031_r300.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2014-06-11]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-06-13-ironman-lanzarote-2014/0702_004031_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;0702_004031_r300.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-06-13-ironman-lanzarote-2014/DSC_1107_r1024.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC_1107_r300.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2014-06-11]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-06-13-ironman-lanzarote-2014/DSC_1107_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;DSC_1107_r300.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-06-13-ironman-lanzarote-2014/DSC_1108_r1024.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC_1108_r300.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2014-06-11]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-06-13-ironman-lanzarote-2014/DSC_1108_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;DSC_1108_r300.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-06-13-ironman-lanzarote-2014/DSC_1109_r1024.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC_1109_r300.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2014-06-11]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-06-13-ironman-lanzarote-2014/DSC_1109_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;DSC_1109_r300.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-06-13-ironman-lanzarote-2014/0702_052630_r1024.jpg&quot; title=&quot;0702_052630_r300.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2014-06-11]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-06-13-ironman-lanzarote-2014/0702_052630_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;0702_052630_r300.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-06-13-ironman-lanzarote-2014/0702_052631_r1024.jpg&quot; title=&quot;0702_052631_r300.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2014-06-11]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-06-13-ironman-lanzarote-2014/0702_052631_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;0702_052631_r300.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-06-13-ironman-lanzarote-2014/DSC_1123_r1024.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC_1123_r300.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2014-06-11]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-06-13-ironman-lanzarote-2014/DSC_1123_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;DSC_1123_r300.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-06-13-ironman-lanzarote-2014/DSC_1124_r1024.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC_1124_r300.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2014-06-11]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-06-13-ironman-lanzarote-2014/DSC_1124_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;DSC_1124_r300.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-06-13-ironman-lanzarote-2014/DSC_1134_r1024.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC_1134_r300.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2014-06-11]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-06-13-ironman-lanzarote-2014/DSC_1134_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;DSC_1134_r300.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-06-13-ironman-lanzarote-2014/DSC_1135_r1024.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC_1135_r300.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2014-06-11]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-06-13-ironman-lanzarote-2014/DSC_1135_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;DSC_1135_r300.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-06-13-ironman-lanzarote-2014/DSC_1136_r1024.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC_1136_r300.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2014-06-11]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-06-13-ironman-lanzarote-2014/DSC_1136_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;DSC_1136_r300.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-06-13-ironman-lanzarote-2014/DSC_1137_r1024.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC_1137_r300.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2014-06-11]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-06-13-ironman-lanzarote-2014/DSC_1137_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;DSC_1137_r300.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-06-13-ironman-lanzarote-2014/0702_026489_r1024.jpg&quot; title=&quot;0702_026489_r300.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2014-06-11]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-06-13-ironman-lanzarote-2014/0702_026489_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;0702_026489_r300.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-06-13-ironman-lanzarote-2014/0702_008741_r1024.jpg&quot; title=&quot;0702_008741_r300.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2014-06-11]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-06-13-ironman-lanzarote-2014/0702_008741_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;0702_008741_r300.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-06-13-ironman-lanzarote-2014/0702_008742_r1024.jpg&quot; title=&quot;0702_008742_r300.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2014-06-11]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-06-13-ironman-lanzarote-2014/0702_008742_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;0702_008742_r300.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-06-13-ironman-lanzarote-2014/0702_019069_r1024.jpg&quot; title=&quot;0702_019069_r300.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2014-06-11]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-06-13-ironman-lanzarote-2014/0702_019069_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;0702_019069_r300.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-06-13-ironman-lanzarote-2014/0702_026490_r1024.jpg&quot; title=&quot;0702_026490_r300.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2014-06-11]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-06-13-ironman-lanzarote-2014/0702_026490_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;0702_026490_r300.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-06-13-ironman-lanzarote-2014/0702_026491_r1024.jpg&quot; title=&quot;0702_026491_r300.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2014-06-11]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-06-13-ironman-lanzarote-2014/0702_026491_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;0702_026491_r300.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-06-13-ironman-lanzarote-2014/0702_026492_r1024.jpg&quot; title=&quot;0702_026492_r300.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2014-06-11]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-06-13-ironman-lanzarote-2014/0702_026492_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;0702_026492_r300.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-06-13-ironman-lanzarote-2014/0702_020076_r1024.jpg&quot; title=&quot;0702_020076_r300.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2014-06-11]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-06-13-ironman-lanzarote-2014/0702_020076_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;0702_020076_r300.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;



</description>
                <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2014 00:21:00 +0100</pubDate>
                <link>http://tri.ekynoxe.com/ironman-lanzarote-2014</link>
                <author>hello@ekynoxe.com (Mathieu Davy)</author>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://tri.ekynoxe.com/ironman-lanzarote-2014</guid>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Every Day Training Camp - Day 6 - Windy, uphill, or both?</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Last day on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.everydaytraining.org.uk/&quot; title=&quot;EDT Camp day six&quot;&gt;EDT&lt;/a&gt; Camp. A bit sad as this has been a fantastic week but today was a big day on another level: riding the full ironman course in conditions that weren&amp;rsquo;t the best!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-14-every-day-training-camp-day-6-windy-uphill-or-both/Mirador_del_Rio_as_ever_impressive.png&quot; title=&quot;Mirador del Rio: as ever impressive&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[014-03-14]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-14-every-day-training-camp-day-6-windy-uphill-or-both/Mirador_del_Rio_as_ever_impressive_r500.png&quot; alt=&quot;Mirador del Rio: as ever impressive&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Three groups were formed, one of them going for an extended loop through Femès and Playa Blanca, while the two others would stick to the ironman route all the way around. By 9am when we had all set-off, the wind had already picked up, and we knew it wasn&amp;rsquo;t going to be an easy day.
Add to this the general fatigue from the 5 previous days of early rising, hard racing and pushing our boundaries, and you get a great cocktail of &amp;ldquo;I may not be able to do this&amp;rdquo;! But that&amp;rsquo;s the spirit of the camp: you will still find more in yourself and with the help of others, you&amp;rsquo;ll get through the last event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The day&amp;rsquo;s ride could have ended prematurely for some, as 10Km in the ride for the fast group, Matthew unfortunately rode over a glass bottle on the side of the road, which exploded and completely shredded his tire. That group had to go back to the hotel for a pit-stop, and resume their ride a little later. They still did their planned long route though, but had to drop the hammer from Orzola, since they passed there only after 5pm! They must have been absolutely flying on the way back to get back on time to get ready for dinner!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was in the &amp;ldquo;medium&amp;rdquo; group and we worked pretty well together all the way around, only splitting for the fast descents to be a bit safer, and for some of the ascents to ride at our own rhythm, before regrouping at the top.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But today was honestly a long struggle. The wind was quite strong, making the ascents north-eastwards harder, and any descent very twitchy and dangerous. I certainly had a few moments on my deep rims which I&amp;rsquo;m happy I handled well, but which were definitely borderline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The initial idea was to get around the course in about 6h30, but it took us 7h15. Still, we were pretty pleased with that given the conditions!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2 months time, I hope to get around in 5h30 max if I want to get close to the 10h mark overall&amp;hellip; This little reminder will always be on my mind:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-14-every-day-training-camp-day-6-windy-uphill-or-both/run_boy_run.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Run boy Run&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2014-03-14]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-14-every-day-training-camp-day-6-windy-uphill-or-both/run_boy_run_r500.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Run boy Run&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone from all groups made it through the course, and it&amp;rsquo;s a pleasure to see that although it&amp;rsquo;s been a long, hard ride at the end of a very busy training week, it&amp;rsquo;s been enjoyable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With each one of us having done more than 30 hours of training this week, EDT Camp has now been completed! We were all very much looking forward to a nice meal out altogether, and proper grilled meat was on most plates tonight!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the performances of the week, and finishing the ride today, it meant that on points I did win the camp. And Jo presented me with my very own winner tee-shirt. A unique one! Fantastic memory for a massive week of training.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-14-every-day-training-camp-day-6-windy-uphill-or-both/camp_winner.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Camp winner!&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2014-03-14]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-14-every-day-training-camp-day-6-windy-uphill-or-both/camp_winner_r500.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Camp winner!&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tired? Yes! Happy? Ecstatic! That was a fantastic week and I&amp;rsquo;m sure I&amp;rsquo;ll be back for more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you want to do a week of great training with like-minded crazy athletes? Contact &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:coaches@everydaytraining.org.uk&quot; title=&quot;Contact Every Day Training&quot;&gt;Steven and Jo&lt;/a&gt; to get the low down on the camps and register your interest for next year&amp;rsquo;s edition! Entries may not be open yet, but enquire before and secure a place when they do. You won&amp;rsquo;t regret it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks a lot to &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/lord_lordy&quot;&gt;Steven&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jo_carritt&quot;&gt;Jo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/waterrat77&quot;&gt;Emma&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/SportsMassageSB&quot;&gt;Sarah&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/millsphysio&quot;&gt;Ali&lt;/a&gt; and to all the campers for making this week an amazing one. It&amp;rsquo;s not been easy sailing for any of us, but the atmosphere and support has carried us all around the activities, races and ice-cream contests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See you next year, I&amp;rsquo;m off for a rest now!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Today&amp;rsquo;s stats for me&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://connect.garmin.com/activity/461866307&quot;&gt;Bike: 182Km, ~2600m ascent&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;My camp stats&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Swim: 6.8Km&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bike: 711Km with about 10.000m ascent&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run: 51.2Km&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Total hours: 34.8h&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;gallery&quot;&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-14-every-day-training-camp-day-6-windy-uphill-or-both/Happy_climbing.png&quot; title=&quot;Happy climbing&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2014-03-14]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-14-every-day-training-camp-day-6-windy-uphill-or-both/Happy_climbing_r300.png&quot; alt=&quot;Happy climbing&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-14-every-day-training-camp-day-6-windy-uphill-or-both/Jo_smiles_despite_hard_work.png&quot; title=&quot;Jo smiles despite hard work&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2014-03-14]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-14-every-day-training-camp-day-6-windy-uphill-or-both/Jo_smiles_despite_hard_work_r300.png&quot; alt=&quot;Jo smiles despite hard work&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-14-every-day-training-camp-day-6-windy-uphill-or-both/Mirador_del_Rio_as_ever_impressive.png&quot; title=&quot;Mirador del Rio: as ever impressive&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2014-03-14]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-14-every-day-training-camp-day-6-windy-uphill-or-both/Mirador_del_Rio_as_ever_impressive_r300.png&quot; alt=&quot;Mirador del Rio: as ever impressive&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-14-every-day-training-camp-day-6-windy-uphill-or-both/run_boy_run.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Run boy Run&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2014-03-14]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-14-every-day-training-camp-day-6-windy-uphill-or-both/run_boy_run_r500.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Run boy Run&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-14-every-day-training-camp-day-6-windy-uphill-or-both/camp_winner.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Camp winner!&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2014-03-14]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-14-every-day-training-camp-day-6-windy-uphill-or-both/camp_winner_r500.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Camp winner!&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2014 19:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tri.ekynoxe.com/every-day-training-camp-day-6-windy-uphill-or-both</link>
                <author>hello@ekynoxe.com (Mathieu Davy)</author>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://tri.ekynoxe.com/every-day-training-camp-day-6-windy-uphill-or-both</guid>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Every Day Training Camp - Day 5 - A tale of two races</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Today everyone is pretty much cream-crackered after yesterday&amp;rsquo;s hard work up Tabayesco. Nonetheless, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.everydaytraining.org.uk/&quot; title=&quot;EDT Camp day five&quot;&gt;EDT&lt;/a&gt; Camp has no respite, and this is the business end of the week, with not one, but two handicapped races to get done: a swim in the morning, and a 10K run after the day&amp;rsquo;s ride.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;




&lt;h3&gt;Swim&lt;/h3&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The swim race was a two lap event, around the channel where the ironman starts. But unlike yesterday&amp;rsquo;s bike TT where campers were set off at regular 30s intervals, the starts were done on handicaps calculated down to seconds. Given that Simon swam almost twice the distance than anyone else in the aquathlon, following the wrong course, he had a huge lead on everyone, Mel even starting her race only after Simon had started his second lap! The handicap system was probably not really made for this kind of situations so results at either end were probably not most representative. With this handicap, Simon actually won the race, but as a gent he declined the prize on the basis that the handicap wasn&amp;rsquo;t really fair.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I&amp;rsquo;m not a particularly great swimmer, I finished mid-pack in the aquathlon swim, and therefore started mid-pack in the swim race. And being in this position allowed for quite a bit of action around the 2 laps course. I was 2 seconds behind Linda and maybe 5 behind Rob at the start, which I quickly made up, but as I found out, it was a bit too much for me to handle and I tired quickly towards the end of the first lap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Follow that with a little run on the beach between the two laps to get your hear rate through the roof, and I was caught by Rob and James before the first buoy on the second lap. In true racing spirit James tried to push me straight onto the buoy but a good old shove from me managed to get the inside line&amp;hellip; before being dunked in heavily on the turn itself. Rob, in the mean time, kept clear of all the action and passed both of us. I had nothing left in the tank for the final sprint, but that was great, great fun!
I absolutely loved it, and given the number of huffing and puffing rubber-clad bodies lying in the sand after the swim, it looks like everyone had given it their all!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although I felt like I blew up, I certainly had a great swim as I managed 1'29&quot; / 100m on average, which is the fastest pace I&amp;rsquo;ve ever swam either in a wetsuit in any race or in any training session doing reps. Good times!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Bike&lt;/h3&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The day&amp;rsquo;s ride was going to be fairly short, but still include some hard work: the climb from Playa Blanca to Femès, all in a headwind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-13-every-day-training-camp-day-5-a-tale-of-two-races/femes_the_not_so_steep_bit.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Femes: The not so steep bit&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2014-03-13]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-13-every-day-training-camp-day-5-a-tale-of-two-races/femes_the_not_so_steep_bit_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Femes: The not so steep bit&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;And to make up for an early navigation blunder that saw us take a short route, most of the group did some reps of the last bit of the climb: 1km of gut busting gradients with an average of 13% and passages at more than 22%! I had to push above 300W for more than 4'30&quot; and move at only 10.5 kph! Those figures for me a way above what I can sustain for a long period of time, so that climb really earns its fierce reputation!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was such a challenge that Matthew had a 20&amp;euro; bet with both James and Mel that he&amp;rsquo;d climb the whole thing from Playa Blanca in the big ring&amp;hellip; And he did! His quads were still twitching at the cafe afterwards, but he really earned that!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-13-every-day-training-camp-day-5-a-tale-of-two-races/a_20_euro_bet.jpg&quot; title=&quot;A 20 EURO bet&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2014-03-13]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-13-every-day-training-camp-day-5-a-tale-of-two-races/a_20_euro_bet_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A 20 EURO bet&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;We managed to trick David into doing 4 reps of the steep part, telling him that Jo went for a 4th while she was hiding around the back of the cafe, which earned him the camp record. And on a TT bike with deep rims, that&amp;rsquo;s quite a feat too!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Run&lt;/h3&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The run was a &amp;ldquo;no watches&amp;rdquo; 10K race. Given how I hurt last time I did one, fresh, round the corner from home, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t too optimistic about the result on the 5th day of an overloaded week of training and without any idea of pace. The basic race was designed to be like the swim this morning: the slowest time from the aquathlon would start first, then every athlete would set off at intervals calculated from their run times in the aquathlon. Mix it all with a secret formula Steven&amp;rsquo;s been brewing for the last few camps, and it&amp;rsquo;s supposed to be a close finish with everyone.
Having ran the fastest time in the aquathlon, I therefore started last, which gave me targets to pick, much like during the TT on Tabayesco.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But to add a little more fun to the race, Jo and Steven asked each one of us to predict their times. The goal being to see how confident people feel they can run fast on the back of such a training week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not really optimistic by nature (see &lt;a href=&quot;/every-day-training-camp-pre-camp/&quot;&gt;my post before the camp&amp;hellip;&lt;/a&gt;), so I predicted something in the region of 3min slower than my all time PB of 38'15&quot;. Also, the lack of pacing could be problematic (or not).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I saw everyone set off one after the other, and as Jo and Steven predicted: it was quite hard not to get disheartened at the seemingly huge lead they were getting, but when my turn finally came, I just went for it. My first target was already 37s ahead of me, and barely visible, but I wanted to catch as many people as I could, the cherry on the cake would have been to catch Jo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started to reel people in and I knew I was pushing hard, but that was the exercise: keep pushing without pace indication. I apologies for the amount of swearing I did around the course when I was passing people: I could barely see Jo in the distance, and only got an idea of how far I was at the turnaround points. I did get closer, but she must have found an extra gear because I certainly didn&amp;rsquo;t feel that I was slowing down at the time. Checking the data from my taped watch after the race, I actually went faster in the last 2K, so Jo had the afterburners turned well on at the right time and despite catching everyone else, I never caught her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taping my watch was probably the best thing to have been asked to do. And I was shocked to see that I had ran close to a PB in 38'34&quot;, getting the fastest time of the day and a camp record! What a result!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What was a lot less impressive however was my prediction of my finish time&amp;hellip; At 2'36&quot; slower than what I actually ran, I had one of the most pessimistic guesses, and that really shows that I need to work on my belief in myself for the next races. That should come handy in 2 months when I race the ironman here!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That race was concluding the day for most, but as I had not done the extended swim in the morning, and to avoid having to swim right before the ironman bike ride tomorrow, I decided to swim the way back. I never thought I&amp;rsquo;d say &amp;ldquo;I swam back home from a 10K race&amp;rdquo;, but I did! Nice and easy, warm in the shallows, taking my time and enjoying the relaxation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Today's stats for me&lt;/h3&gt;


&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Swim: 2.32Km&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://connect.garmin.com/activity/461239665&quot;&gt;Bike: 63Km, 1110m ascent&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run: 16.84Km (including a 38'34&quot; 10K)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
                <pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2014 21:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tri.ekynoxe.com/every-day-training-camp-day-5-a-tale-of-two-races</link>
                <author>hello@ekynoxe.com (Mathieu Davy)</author>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://tri.ekynoxe.com/every-day-training-camp-day-5-a-tale-of-two-races</guid>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Every Day Training Camp - Day 4 - High flying</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Today&amp;rsquo;s feature on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.everydaytraining.org.uk/&quot; title=&quot;EDT Camp day four&quot;&gt;EDT&lt;/a&gt; Camp was the Tabayesco time trial. With about 500m of ascent over 10Km, that was the first of the three handicapped races, where riders were set off in an order determined from the previous timed events.
After winning the TT on the first day, needless to say that expectations were high, and not just from myself! Thanks to everyone in the group for that! I had a target to beat!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-12-every-day-training-camp-day-4-high-flying/time_keeping_and_cheering.png&quot; title=&quot;Time keeping and cheering&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2014-03-12]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-12-every-day-training-camp-day-4-high-flying/time_keeping_and_cheering_r500.png&quot; alt=&quot;Time keeping and cheering&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;!--more--&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Prior to this, the morning swim saw us do a nice bay-to-beach-and-back swim. That was a welcome change from the standard loops, with a few more things to see underwater as well! I had the camera with me, so that should make it through the camp film later on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;gallery&quot;&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-12-every-day-training-camp-day-4-high-flying/after_swim.jpg&quot; title=&quot;After the swim&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2014-03-12]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-12-every-day-training-camp-day-4-high-flying/after_swim_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;After the swim&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-12-every-day-training-camp-day-4-high-flying/rubber_legs.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Rubber legs&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2014-03-12]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-12-every-day-training-camp-day-4-high-flying/rubber_legs_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Rubber legs&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-12-every-day-training-camp-day-4-high-flying/underwater.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Steven under water&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2014-03-12]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-12-every-day-training-camp-day-4-high-flying/underwater_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Steven under water&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;After raiding the buffet breakfast once more, we rode 40 km in a strong headwind to get to the bottom of the climb, where riders were then set-off at 30s or 1min intervals. From two synchronised watches, the times were expertly taken at the top by &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/SportsMassageSB&quot;&gt;Sarah&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/millsphysio&quot;&gt;Ali&lt;/a&gt;, handicapped results being worked-out later-on by Steven at the Mirador de Haria cafe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I did a good time on the El Golfo TT on Sunday, I was the last one to start before Steven, and the expectation put on me by pretty much everyone was that I&amp;rsquo;d catch most of them&amp;hellip; Easier said than done!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the wind blowing down the valley, and having lead legs from having started last, it was tough at first. But the heavy legs soon went away and I could just put my head down and concentrate on keeping the power up with a good leg turnover.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted to try and not get caught by Steven, who was the course record holder, so I really pushed hard at the start, averaging close to 290-300W for several minutes, then had to slow down a bit to not completely explode. With my best ever turbo 20min effort being 289W, and a climb that should take around 30min to get over at speed, it was the right thing to do!
I stayed on the tri bars most of the way as this is how I train on the turbo, but had to sit-up in a few passages where I couldn&amp;rsquo;t push the pedals hard enough in that position.
I reached the left turn, before the switchbacks, in around 18:30, so it was game-on to get under 30min at the top if I could maintain the effort. Having the others of the group ahead of me was a fantastic help though, as I had targets to chase all the time. It must be a lot harder to start at the front and keep motivated all the way.
With two corners to go after the windy switchbacks, I threw everything I had left and I couldn&amp;rsquo;t believe that my watch was showing 28'59&quot; when I crossed the line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was properly gut busting and everyone was feeling it well at the top, but there wasn&amp;rsquo;t really any time to rest, as half of the group went for a hilly trail run around the observatory. I had never seen that side, and it&amp;rsquo;s simply gorgeous!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-12-every-day-training-camp-day-4-high-flying/top_of_haria.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Running at the top of Mirador de Haria&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2014-03-12]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-12-every-day-training-camp-day-4-high-flying/top_of_haria_r500.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Running at the top of Mirador de Haria&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Results of TT where announced when everyone was back at the cafe and eaten their bodyweight in cake, ice cream and cheese. I had won it on pure time, setting a new course record, but Ellen had also done just above 41min!! The initial goal for here being around 50min, that was a fantastic time! Get in missy! What a way to get up the &amp;ldquo;hill&amp;rdquo;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;attachement iframe_wrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;//player.vimeo.com/video/89182544?portrait=0&amp;amp;color=ff9933&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Combined with her initial El-Golfo TT, it also meant she pipped everyone to the handicapped win by a mile! Unfortunately the conditions of the camp competitions are such that she couldn&amp;rsquo;t claim the prize, but well done for winning it! That must boost your confidence big time!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the prize of a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.freespeed.co.uk/&quot;&gt;Freespeed bike fit&lt;/a&gt; stayed &amp;ldquo;in the family&amp;rdquo; as Steven put it, as I was the second camper behind Ellen on handicap, which was pretty handy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There have been a few surprises on this climb, but I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure everyone enjoyed it, even if it is secretly. We&amp;rsquo;re nutters enough to do 6 days of overload in one of the most unfriendly bike environments, so I&amp;rsquo;m sure we&amp;rsquo;re all enjoying those little races!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you wonder how to run races for small groups and make them fun while giving everyone a chance: use handicaps! That&amp;rsquo;s a fantastic way to keep everyone involved and guessing for results, as the fastest doesn&amp;rsquo;t always win! There are numerous ways to do it and I need to grill Steven about his methods, but it&amp;rsquo;s always entertaining.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After this, I took the long way back to the hotel with a few others, riding through Fire Mountain the other way: downhill! Views are again exceptional over there, and since we had already gone up the other side 3 times this week, it was only fair to get to do it this way at least once.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the runs to and from swimming, the run at the top of the climb validated my run quota for today, so I could put my feet up a little tonight, which was most welcome!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Today's stats for me&lt;/h3&gt;


&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Swim: 1.34Km&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bike: 117.63Km, 1544m ascent &lt;a href=&quot;http://connect.garmin.com/activity/461239822&quot;&gt;part1&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://connect.garmin.com/activity/461239760&quot;&gt;part2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run: 4.76Km&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;gallery&quot;&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-12-every-day-training-camp-day-4-high-flying/Brian.png&quot; title=&quot;Brian&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2014-03-12]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-12-every-day-training-camp-day-4-high-flying/Brian_r300.png&quot; alt=&quot;Brian&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-12-every-day-training-camp-day-4-high-flying/David.png&quot; title=&quot;David&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2014-03-12]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-12-every-day-training-camp-day-4-high-flying/David_r300.png&quot; alt=&quot;David&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-12-every-day-training-camp-day-4-high-flying/Heather.png&quot; title=&quot;Heather&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2014-03-12]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-12-every-day-training-camp-day-4-high-flying/Heather_r300.png&quot; alt=&quot;Heather&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-12-every-day-training-camp-day-4-high-flying/James.png&quot; title=&quot;James&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2014-03-12]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-12-every-day-training-camp-day-4-high-flying/James_r300.png&quot; alt=&quot;James&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-12-every-day-training-camp-day-4-high-flying/Matthew.png&quot; title=&quot;Matthew&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2014-03-12]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-12-every-day-training-camp-day-4-high-flying/Matthew_r300.png&quot; alt=&quot;Matthew&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-12-every-day-training-camp-day-4-high-flying/Mel.png&quot; title=&quot;Mel&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2014-03-12]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-12-every-day-training-camp-day-4-high-flying/Mel_r300.png&quot; alt=&quot;Mel&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-12-every-day-training-camp-day-4-high-flying/Rob.png&quot; title=&quot;Rob&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2014-03-12]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-12-every-day-training-camp-day-4-high-flying/Rob_r300.png&quot; alt=&quot;Rob&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-12-every-day-training-camp-day-4-high-flying/roz_waved.png&quot; title=&quot;As promised, Roz did wave!&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2014-03-12]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-12-every-day-training-camp-day-4-high-flying/roz_waved_r300.png&quot; alt=&quot;As promised, Roz did wave!&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-12-every-day-training-camp-day-4-high-flying/Sarah_chief_time_keeper.png&quot; title=&quot;Sarah was chief time keeper at the top&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2014-03-12]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-12-every-day-training-camp-day-4-high-flying/Sarah_chief_time_keeper_r300.png&quot; alt=&quot;Sarah was chief time keeper at the top&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-12-every-day-training-camp-day-4-high-flying/Simon.png&quot; title=&quot;Simon&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2014-03-12]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-12-every-day-training-camp-day-4-high-flying/Simon_r300.png&quot; alt=&quot;Simon&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-12-every-day-training-camp-day-4-high-flying/Steve.png&quot; title=&quot;Steve&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2014-03-12]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-12-every-day-training-camp-day-4-high-flying/Steve_r300.png&quot; alt=&quot;Steve&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-12-every-day-training-camp-day-4-high-flying/Steven.png&quot; title=&quot;Steven&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2014-03-12]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-12-every-day-training-camp-day-4-high-flying/Steven_r300.png&quot; alt=&quot;Steven&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-12-every-day-training-camp-day-4-high-flying/time_keeping_and_cheering.png&quot; title=&quot;Time keeping and cheering&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2014-03-12]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-12-every-day-training-camp-day-4-high-flying/time_keeping_and_cheering_r300.png&quot; alt=&quot;Time keeping and cheering&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
                <pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2014 16:57:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tri.ekynoxe.com/every-day-training-camp-day-4-high-flying</link>
                <author>hello@ekynoxe.com (Mathieu Davy)</author>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://tri.ekynoxe.com/every-day-training-camp-day-4-high-flying</guid>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Every Day Training Camp - Day 3 - Wind, rain and an early race</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Today on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.everydaytraining.org.uk/&quot; title=&quot;EDT Camp day three&quot;&gt;EDT&lt;/a&gt; camp, it was all about the early morning race: an aquathlon on the sea front of Puerto del Carmen. Then a simple ride just above 100K to make things right!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-11-every-day-training-camp-day-3-wind-rain-and-an-early-race/Aquathlon_transition.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Aquathlon transition&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[20140311]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-11-every-day-training-camp-day-3-wind-rain-and-an-early-race/Aquathlon_transition_r500.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Aquathlon transition&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;!--more--&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The aquathlon was held on the seafront of Puerto del Carmen, very close to the ironman finish line. The swim was 2 out-and-back loops from the beach to the line of permanent yellow buoys, and the run was on the undulating seafront. With a &amp;ldquo;mass&amp;rdquo; start, it was a great format: whoever is ahead&amp;hellip; is ahead!
The transition area was up at road level, on a children&amp;rsquo;s playground.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unlike yesterday, the mass start wasn&amp;rsquo;t feisty, mostly because the target for the turnaround wasn&amp;rsquo;t a single, small buoy, but a line of buoys out at sea. This meant everyone fanned out quickly, with a few working together. I found myself pretty isolated to the right of it all, and got tangled in the ropes of a buoy &amp;frac34; of the way to the turnaround. That, and getting it again on the way back, didn&amp;rsquo;t help, but I had a normal swim, despite really feeling my ribs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got caught big time by swimmers who didn&amp;rsquo;t start too fast and didn&amp;rsquo;t half blow-up in the middle of their swim, but I managed to exit transition in about 7th or 8th place, being speedy through the zone, even with putting socks on. That&amp;rsquo;s a welcome change for me!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also had an interesting target to try and catch in Jo, my coach, who shot out of transition slightly ahead of me. I passed her right at the end of the first lap, but she&amp;rsquo;s a racer, and I didn&amp;rsquo;t want her to be able to stick around, so had to dig deeper to not be caught. That worked well since I finished 5th, with the fastest run split of the day. I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure Jo&amp;rsquo;s having fun though. Aren&amp;rsquo;t you, coach? :-)
Gut-busting action for everyone, and well done to Greg for winning it, cracking run there! He managed to catch Mel who was out on the run first, almost 5 minutes ahead of me! I&amp;rsquo;m definitely not a front-pack swimmer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Running back to the hotel validated our &amp;ldquo;wildcard&amp;rdquo; to not have to do an extra run in the afternoon after the ride, which was welcome since tomorrow, there is another bike TT, uphill this time, on Tabayesco. Discussions have been going on fiercely about me winning it, but I&amp;rsquo;m yet to be convinced some are going full blast. Tomorrow will be fun regardless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today&amp;rsquo;s ride was a long loop through Playa Blanca, Fire Mountain and Famara, and it was pretty windy. Great test of the legs doing some work at the front (but not all of it, there&amp;rsquo;s a TT tomorrow after all ;-) ), and of bike handling in cross winds around the island. Wheels are fine, legs seem to work al-right, so all is good on this front.
Some of the group on the long ride today decided to ride up to Teguise, and I&amp;rsquo;m yet to hear the stories, but apparently they&amp;rsquo;ve got offered a full cake (as in the WHOLE thing!) and, well, gobbled it up. After the few ice creams of those last few days, I&amp;rsquo;m not sure how this is going to end!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It also rained today. Clouds come just like this and disappear after 1h after having drenched everything. On the way back with Frankie, we managed to miss them. Lucky this time!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not many photos today: I didn&amp;rsquo;t take my camera with me, and the wind was so strong it would have been a bad idea to try and take the phone out of my pocket. I&amp;rsquo;m sure the official blog will have more later on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Today's stats for me&lt;/h3&gt;


&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Swim: 1.4K as part of the aquathlon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://connect.garmin.com/activity/459285098&quot;&gt;Bike: 107Km, 2000m ascent&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run: 4.3K as part of the aquathlon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
                <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2014 21:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tri.ekynoxe.com/every-day-training-camp-day-3-wind-rain-and-an-early-race</link>
                <author>hello@ekynoxe.com (Mathieu Davy)</author>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://tri.ekynoxe.com/every-day-training-camp-day-3-wind-rain-and-an-early-race</guid>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Every Day Training Camp - Day 2 - Ice creams and mountain goats</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.everydaytraining.org.uk/&quot; title=&quot;EDT Camp day two&quot;&gt;Every Day Training&lt;/a&gt; camp, day two:
A swim session with entering/leaving the water drills (and a race!), a long day in the saddle with a lot of climbing, and a nice steady run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-10-every-day-training-camp-day-2-ice-creams-and-mountain-goats/mirador_del_rio.jpg&quot; title=&quot;At the top of Mirador del Rio&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[20140310]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-10-every-day-training-camp-day-2-ice-creams-and-mountain-goats/mirador_del_rio_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;At the top of Mirador del Rio&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;!--more--&gt;


&lt;p&gt;We all started by a fun little session from the beach. The idea was to do a 25m out and back around a buoy by teams of two, paired after an initial flat out test from a mass start on the beach. It was close to reproduce and ironman start! Lots of pushing and shoving! Not on the same scale of course, but a nice washing machine around the buoy.
Although some didn&amp;rsquo;t get the rules fully, and therefore had to do an extra lap, everyone had a ball, much to the bemusement of passers by, who had no idea what our group of rubber clad athletes was doing. Sweet and short, but quite funny. The run back up to the hotel didn&amp;rsquo;t feel as hard today, which was nice. There should be some good footage of this race later on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.everydaytraining.org.uk/&quot;&gt;Every Day Training blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As mentioned in the briefing this evening, the ride today was the second hardest after the ful IM course we&amp;rsquo;ll do on Thursday. And we all felt it! 2000m of ascent in 140Km, The donkey track out of Puerto del Carmen, the climb to Teguise, the meaty bit: Orzola to Mirador del Rio, Haria to its mirador through the switchbacks, and then the return from La Santa. Some stiff legs on the way back, and a fair bit of wind as well. Perfect Lanzarote. Some did feel it more than others today, but they&amp;rsquo;ll be back for more tomorrow I&amp;rsquo;m sure. That&amp;rsquo;s what camp is about: getting to and over your limits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had my go pro with me all day and filmed a few things along the way. I think I must have looked like a right goof with the camera on my head and my helmet completely sideways but hey, we&amp;rsquo;re here for some fun too!
The hotel wifi is so rubbish that I&amp;rsquo;ll have to upload them when I&amp;rsquo;m back, which should give me a it of time to edit them as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &amp;ldquo;fast&amp;rdquo; group today didn&amp;rsquo;t manage to catch the supposedly &amp;ldquo;slower&amp;rdquo; one before the top og Haria, which meant there was also a lot of good riding done up front!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have to admit, the brick-sized sugar cake and coffee at the top of Haria was very welcome. Buzzing like crazy after that, but lovely stop. I also kept half my sandwich to eat at La Santa while some of the others had their bikes repaired, some quite extensively!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The return after La Santa was a little bit less enjoyeable as it was basically a long climb all the way back to and then a relatively short climb through Conil and the donkey track.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Top all that action packed day with 1h run along the seafront (and the dreaded climb back up afterwards), and you&amp;rsquo;ve got all the ingredients for a tired VERY hungry athletes who hapily raided the hotel restaurant :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks Sarah for massage and the nudge about &amp;ldquo;getting acquaitned with my foam roller&amp;rdquo;. I&amp;rsquo;ll try to get on it more often. I don&amp;rsquo;t like knots either!!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tired now, I need some sleep: tomorrow, there&amp;rsquo;s an aqauthlon and that one will hurt!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Today's stats for me&lt;/h3&gt;


&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Swim: 800m (only, but crazy sprinting)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://connect.garmin.com/activity/458826817&quot;&gt;Bike: 140Km, 2000m ascent&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run: 1h, 12.3Km.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;gallery&quot;&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-10-every-day-training-camp-day-2-ice-creams-and-mountain-goats/to_arieta.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Going towards Arieta&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[20140310]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-10-every-day-training-camp-day-2-ice-creams-and-mountain-goats/to_arieta_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Going towards Arieta&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-10-every-day-training-camp-day-2-ice-creams-and-mountain-goats/mirador_del_rio.jpg&quot; title=&quot;At the top of Mirador del Rio&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[20140310]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-10-every-day-training-camp-day-2-ice-creams-and-mountain-goats/mirador_del_rio_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;At the top of Mirador del Rio&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-10-every-day-training-camp-day-2-ice-creams-and-mountain-goats/coffee_stop_haria.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Coffee stop at Mirador de Haria&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[20140310]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-10-every-day-training-camp-day-2-ice-creams-and-mountain-goats/coffee_stop_haria_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Coffee stop at Mirador de Haria&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class='gallery-item'&gt;
        &lt;dt class='gallery-icon attachement'&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-10-every-day-training-camp-day-2-ice-creams-and-mountain-goats/ice_creams_while_u_wait.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Ice creams while u wait&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[20140310]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-10-every-day-training-camp-day-2-ice-creams-and-mountain-goats/ice_creams_while_u_wait_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ice creams while u wait&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
                <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2014 22:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tri.ekynoxe.com/every-day-training-camp-day-2-ice-creams-and-mountain-goats</link>
                <author>hello@ekynoxe.com (Mathieu Davy)</author>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://tri.ekynoxe.com/every-day-training-camp-day-2-ice-creams-and-mountain-goats</guid>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Every Day Training Camp - Day 1</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;After a nice introductory briefing by the pool yesterday night where we got to know each other, the general plan for the camp was outlined, and we go our first taste of the little competition running: today, first day of the camp, would include a 10 miles TT around the El Golfo loop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-09-every-day-training-camp-day-1/edt.png&quot; alt=&quot;70.3 California medal&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;!--more--&gt;


&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve been spoilt by the camp sponsors: PowerBar — well, if you like gels (I do) — but we also got a nice pair of goggles from Blue Seventy, an offer for some weird recovery device from Firefly, and some Nuun tabs which should come in handy this week ask I&amp;rsquo;ll sweat a lot! We also have some amazing sport massage from The Tri Touch that will for sure become very handy!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-09-every-day-training-camp-day-1/goodies.jpg&quot; title=&quot;goodies_r300.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[20140309]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-09-every-day-training-camp-day-1/goodies_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;goodies_r300.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;But before the bike action, it was &amp;ldquo;up and at &amp;lsquo;em&amp;rdquo; early, to get a swim at 6:30 and be for the opening of the breakfast doors at the hotel by 8:30. A bit frantic, but that sure gets you going!
The water wasn&amp;rsquo;t as warm as I expected but after a couple of minutes it all warmed up nicely. I had to stop on the way out to get a grasp of the sunshine! I haven&amp;rsquo;t seen much of it in the UK for some time, and with my first open water swim of the season, that was picture perfect.
Pretty much everyone was ahead in the sun, but the 20-strong group all gathered for a short rest towards at the end of line of buoys before heading back&amp;hellip; In the current. No wonder the way out felt easy!
I still felt my arm and right ribs from the crash last Friday, but it wasn&amp;rsquo;t getting worse in the swim, so all was more or less OK. I think the end of the swim transformed itself in a bit of a race, with everyone surging around, but some of us got tangled in the ropes of the channel going out from the beach. Great fun though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Running back up to the hotel (and I really mean &amp;ldquo;up&amp;rdquo;!!), felt OK as well, so the day started quite good for everyone, as I learnt afterwards that no-one took the minibus back to the hotel. Still lots of energy in everyone at this point!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Breakfast was quickly gobbled-up before we all set off on the day&amp;rsquo;s ride: a long loop around the south west, up through the donkey track, then through the back roads to Yaiza. (I&amp;rsquo;ve never been that way so it was a welcome change, albeit all in a headwind which is unusual here.) Then we&amp;rsquo;ve done two laps of the El Golfo loop from the Yaiza roundabout, the second one being a 10mi time trial with everyone being set-off at at 30s intervals, and return through Fire Mountain and that infamous long, uphill, stretch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 10mi TT was a flyer. I&amp;rsquo;ve never done a pure TT before, so even in the middle of a ride, that was a first. The route was the loop from the ironman course, so I knew it well, except that I didn&amp;rsquo;t know where the end was. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t back where we started, but about 500m before, so I went straight past Jo through what was the finish line, and carried on until the starting point (Know the course, muppet!).
But even with that, I picked up quite a few people, and finished in under 25min, which interestingly gave me the fastest time of the day and the course record (gasp!). The cafe stop afterwards was welcome for everyone to chill out a bit before the rolling way back through the lunar landscape of Timanfaya National Park and fire mountain. Interesting refuelling strategies from some as well with ice-cream on one end of the spectrum, and avocados on the other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything was a little bit rushed after that since I forgot to bring a pump and I tried to find a shop opened in town but I got lost getting there (duuhh), and as it was Sunday, they were all closed.
Follow that with a 35min run down to the sea-front, along the shore and back, and in no time I was in the hands of Sarah for a much overdue massage that left me pretty stiff&amp;hellip; It&amp;rsquo;s all for my own good, I know!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that camp started with a bang, and hopefully I&amp;rsquo;ll have some energy in the next few days to keep going! Well done everyone today, and especially to my other half who&amp;rsquo;s done brilliantly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Find also the official &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.everydaytraining.org.uk/&quot;&gt;Every Day Training blog&lt;/a&gt; online where the coaches Steven and Jo will be blogging every day as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully I&amp;rsquo;ll take more photos for tomorrow&amp;rsquo;s post. Today was a bit of a blur.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lanzarote - Over and out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Today's stats for me&lt;/h3&gt;


&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Swim: 2.1Km (one lap of the IM course + extra at start)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://connect.garmin.com/activity/458041343&quot;&gt;Bike: 103Km, 1500m ascent&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run: 35min, 7.3Km&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
                <pubDate>Sun, 09 Mar 2014 21:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tri.ekynoxe.com/every-day-training-camp-day-1</link>
                <author>hello@ekynoxe.com (Mathieu Davy)</author>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://tri.ekynoxe.com/every-day-training-camp-day-1</guid>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Every Day Training Camp - Pre-camp</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re on the eve of going away with Ellen to what should be an awesome week of riding, running and swimming in the sunshine of Lanzarote.
However, there&amp;rsquo;s been a few little hicups in the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-07-every-day-training-camp-pre-camp/travelling.jpg&quot; title=&quot;travelling&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[20140307]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2014-03-07-every-day-training-camp-pre-camp/travelling_r500.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;travelling&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;A month ago, I managed to get tonsillitis, which lingered on and on and on until I finally managed to get some antibiotics from my GP&amp;hellip; Last Wednesday. Training has therefore been ridiculously minimal for the last 3 weeks&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week, Ellen found out that she&amp;rsquo;s got a stress fracture in her right foot, and is now walking around in an air cast. Not that this will discourage her from riding the hills on the volcano island!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this morning I managed to crash heavily, all on my own, going to work, and my right ribs are now painful&amp;hellip; Nothing is broken, I can still move, lift and do most things, but we&amp;rsquo;ll see tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So instead of two healthy and strong athletes going for a week of proper training camp, we&amp;rsquo;re now two cripples going for rehab!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully we&amp;rsquo;ll manage to do a few of the activities planned. It seems that there&amp;rsquo;s some sunshine at least!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2014 21:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tri.ekynoxe.com/every-day-training-camp-pre-camp</link>
                <author>hello@ekynoxe.com (Mathieu Davy)</author>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://tri.ekynoxe.com/every-day-training-camp-pre-camp</guid>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>It's YOUR race</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The triathlon race season will start again soon here in the UK, and with the plethora of winter running races and other duathlons available — not to mention overseas racing — I can see a lot of my friends and twitter buddies getting in some fast action over the week-ends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, I noticed a trend lately: this also comes with plenty of them doubting themselves for the goals they have set a long way back. For most, they&amp;rsquo;ve been reasonable in setting those up, so it&amp;rsquo;s all about confidence and re-adjustment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;


&lt;p&gt;In one of his &lt;a href=&quot;http://triathlete-europe.competitor.com/tag/steven-lord&quot;&gt;latest columns in Triathlete Europe&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://triathlete-europe.competitor.com/2014/02/19/steven-lord-blog-challenges&quot;&gt;Steven Lord described the &amp;ldquo;challenges&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; that plenty of us hop-on during our athletic life, and ultimately, draws on the conclusion that those challenges are useful only if they bring a purpose to a training / racing season, and more importantly, not injure ourselves in the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe it should be the same for setting up — and reviewing — your next goals:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set them up as well as you can, based on known ability and a reasonable outcome from your training programme. You must set them high enough so that there is a chance you could not quite make them, but low enough so that the chance of failure is only that: a chance. If you can put in the correct work, you WILL achieve them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You don&amp;rsquo;t have to kill yourself to finish an event (or a training session for that matter!). Chances are that if you&amp;rsquo;re not an elite or a pro, you are in the racing to have a target to aim for and enjoy the journey. Not prize money. If your aim is to qualify for some world championship events or similar, then that qualification should carry a tag reading &amp;ldquo;possibility of not achieving&amp;rdquo;, and you should be fine with that.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t compare yourself to other, much faster athletes. Unless you compare yourself with your training buddies who you know are quite evenly matched to you. There&amp;rsquo;s no point dwelling on the fact that you&amp;rsquo;ll never be a sub 9h ironman, or a 3h marathon runner etc etc&amp;hellip; Know where you stand, and be happy with what you can achieve. Whether it&amp;rsquo;s running a 5K or finishing an ironman, you&amp;rsquo;ll be an achiever, and identical on this point.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t be afraid of changing those goals. Ever. Again: not an elite? Then complete before compete. If life or injury comes in the mix of your training, you can adjust your results prospects to something more manageable and / or more achievable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be definitely prepared for not achieving those goals. But please don&amp;rsquo;t see that as a failure. You don&amp;rsquo;t fail when you train your butt off as close to the plan as possible. You don&amp;rsquo;t fail when you miss a training session. You don&amp;rsquo;t fail when you don&amp;rsquo;t quite get under the fictitious time bar you set yourself either. You may be disappointed a little bit, but you should never be disheartened, or dejected at the sport. If you are, then it&amp;rsquo;s a sign that you&amp;rsquo;re not enjoying it any-more and you need to re-focus and dial it down. Think about the journey and what that brings you. The end goal is a mere pretext to be on the journey.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m frequently told that what I do is fast and furious, top level stuff. No. It&amp;rsquo;s not. My personal goals may not be the same than yours or other people out there, but I&amp;rsquo;m still sticking to the above points. I am a bit disappointed with myself when I can&amp;rsquo;t do a training session, but all in all I reflect on past experiences and shrug it out: because it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter! I have not reached some goals in the past, and will definitely not reach many more in the future. It&amp;rsquo;s part of the training / racing process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not convinced? Here are some personal examples:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learn lessons:&lt;/strong&gt; In July 2011, I &lt;a href=&quot;http://tri.ekynoxe.com/hillingdon-sprint-or-my-first-dnf/&quot;&gt;DNF'ed at a local race&lt;/a&gt; because my rear mech went through my rear wheel on the last lap of the bike, a mile from the finish line (Hillingdon sprint is ran in a strange swim-run-bike format). I didn&amp;rsquo;t fall, I only skidded with a locked back wheel and stopped. I obviously couldn&amp;rsquo;t ride the bike any-more, but instead of walking that remaining mile to the finish, I made the mistake to take a lift from one of the marshals. That&amp;rsquo;s my biggest mistake to date and it won&amp;rsquo;t happen again.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Revise goals:&lt;/strong&gt; In 2012 &lt;a href=&quot;/the-outlaw-triathlon-2012-the-long-walk/&quot;&gt;I raced the Outlaw&lt;/a&gt;. I had a knee injury entering the race and I knew it full well. My very initial goal before injury was to go sub 10h overall. This couldn&amp;rsquo;t happen any-more. I thought I&amp;rsquo;d then try smash the bike in a proper long time trial before checking what would be left in the tank on the &amp;ldquo;run&amp;rdquo;. The conditions on the day, and my knee, didn&amp;rsquo;t let it happen either. Then I shuffled / walked the whole marathon. Some medics and volunteers at aid stations on the run course were drawing me to ambulances as I had been walking for ages, telling me the end of the lap wasn&amp;rsquo;t far if I needed to pull out. I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to, and I didn&amp;rsquo;t. My end time wasn&amp;rsquo;t too bad, although almost 2h slower than initially planned, but that didn&amp;rsquo;t matter. I had revised my goals, and I finished!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have a plan:&lt;/strong&gt; In 2013, &lt;a href=&quot;/ironman-lanzarote-2013-race-report/&quot;&gt;I did Ironman Lanzarote&lt;/a&gt;. I didn&amp;rsquo;t have other goals than to complete in the first place, but still, I injured my left ankle in training, and I simply couldn&amp;rsquo;t run, at all, for about 7 weeks. I only resumed some running with just about month before the race. The strategy therefore had to change, and after a great bike ride, I ran / walked the marathon. Definitely not what I wanted to do, and definitely not doing well for me not wanting to look like &amp;ldquo;another one who smashed the bike and blew up on the run&amp;rdquo;. But it was the plan! The hardest bit was to explain to people on course that I was absolutely fine and walking was intentional to relieve my ankle. I ran / walked and I still finished strong.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;At the end of the day, you are probably your hardest judge and critic. I live with someone who&amp;rsquo;s the harshest on herself I have ever seen anyone be, and I know very well that it&amp;rsquo;s hard not to be like this when you&amp;rsquo;re as determined as we all are in the sport. Talk to your fellow athletes friends and club-mates, let it all out there and listen to the feedback and advice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you can compete, that&amp;rsquo;s great, but before all, make sure you complete YOUR race with what you have at the time. And be happy with the result whatever it is, because you will know you have planned to do just that.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2014 18:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tri.ekynoxe.com/its-your-race</link>
                <author>hello@ekynoxe.com (Mathieu Davy)</author>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://tri.ekynoxe.com/its-your-race</guid>
            </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>