<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Ekynoxe - Mathieu Davy's triathlon ramblings</title>
        <description>Mathieu Davy's triathlon ramblings</description>
        <link>http://tri.ekynoxe.com</link>
        <atom:link href="http://tri.ekynoxe.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <language>en-gb</language>
        <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2017 15:19:41 +0000</pubDate>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2017 15:19:41 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        
            <item>
                <title>ironman World Championship - Kona - Hawaii</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The icing on the cake? The pinnacle of the sport? Or just another race?
See it as you please, but the Ironman World Championship in Kona is by far the most well known and iconic event on the calendar.
A place of myths, race &amp;ldquo;wars&amp;rdquo; and many a disappointment, it is THE one, the holy grail to achieve for many.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-10-30-ironman-world-championship-kona-hawaii/12.JPG&quot; title=&quot;'enjoying' the lava fields...&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[kona-wc-2016]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-10-30-ironman-world-championship-kona-hawaii/12_r500.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;'enjoying' the lava fields...&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;After an amazing result last year at IM UK, the goal was to keep going a little bit longer, and I qualified in &lt;a href=&quot;/ironman-south-africa/&quot;&gt;South Africa&lt;/a&gt; earlier this year. For me, that&amp;rsquo;s where the hard work was done, and I went to the the big island with no expectations, and no pressure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;


&lt;p&gt;So you think you know hot? Then think again! It&amp;rsquo;s not just the heat, but the humidity. And having done 4 very sweaty sessions in a heat chamber to get used to it right before going to the big island didn&amp;rsquo;t really do much to prepare me for the constant suffocating feeling you get as you get off the plane.
No getting out of the heat chamber for cool air in here&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thankfully, I arrived on the island 9 days before the race - after close to 24h traveling, urgh&amp;hellip; - so I had a fair bit of time to get used to the heat and get rid of the jet-lag.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But instead of taking it easy the first couple of days, I went racing! Nothing crazy, but I followed the excellent suggestion from a few people, I registered for the O'hana swim practice race on Saturday morning, exactly a week before the big one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Crystal clear waters, no wetsuit, feeling like I was lining up for the ironman itself, a few jitters, and some swell to look forward to. Interesting breakfast!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Far from my usual disappointing swims, however, this one went great, reaching half way in 32min and feeling strong!
The return was a bit slower, possibly due to currents, and a bit longer (or so I&amp;rsquo;ve been told), as we finished on the beach of the King K Marriott hotel.
But to my surprise, I finished in 72min! Faster than Wales or SA, non wetsuit&amp;hellip; Happy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First tee shirt and finisher medal in the bag. That was a nice start before a week of recces in the heat, registration, last preps and a bit of relaxation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On race morning, the transition entry was mega faff, and even having arrived close to 2h ahead of the start, there was still a massively slow queue. Everything was dead slow. Body marking with water tattoos was a joke, then there was a queue to be weighed, then a queue to get into transition to put stuff on bikes, then we had to get out again to leave our street wear bag, then queue for the loos. For crying out loud, how hard is it to plan a bit for crowds at those races?! Water tattoos were completely pointless as they shredded as soon as we got in the water.
I was barely putting stuff on my bike when the pro men canon fired&amp;hellip; Utter waste of time everywhere!
Anyway, I still had a few minutes before we were allowed to get in the water, but it wasn&amp;rsquo;t particularly nice to stress about how much time was left when that place should really be a well oiled machine!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tried to enter the water as early as I could to warm up enough, but there is only so much you can do. At least the start line is some way from digme beach, so I could put a few efforts in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having swam 72 on the practice swim which was said to be long, I was confident I could do a similar time on race day. I put myself what I though was about &amp;frac14; to 1/3 from the left, but I now think I was more in the middle, about 5-6 rows back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The canon went and it was all a bit of a blur with a mega emotional rush to be starting THAT race!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I followed feet as well as I could, had to give a few kicks in some arms being fed up with the feet-tapping, took a pretty big elbow in the rib-cage that winded me for a few seconds at some point, but other than that it was quite civilised, although in close-pack groups.
Swimming in a diagonal line aiming for a far buoy, I found myself in the no-mans-land zone between the two lanes of buoys and had to adjust my course to avoid canoes. Whoops! I did swim in a straight line! But that line went past the buoy I initially sighted, and forgot to alter course.
I didn&amp;rsquo;t have my watch, so no idea how fast I was going, or stroke rate etc. I was feeling good and reminded myself to keep pushing and not take it too easy.
I passed all other buoys literally touching them, and only saw two super fast pink hats pass me just before the pier.
Getting up THOSE steps I saw the clock at 8:04 and was super happy with that! Fastest swim in years! Non-wetsuit with some swell and current.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really took my time in T1. I could have done up my suit while walking/running to my bike but I didn&amp;rsquo;t think about it at the time. I just wanted to make sure everything was perfect, and rolling up a tight sleeved suit on wet arms is just impossible! But hey, I eventually reached my bike and was on my way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not sure I managed to put my feet in my shoes by the time I was climbing Palani, but I eventually got everything sorted and was keeping an eye on my distances to others and the power. No wind was to be felt at that point and I settled in a nice rhythm up and down the out and back while some big legs were sprinting off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Palani was fun that time around. I kept a cap on power and tried to keep distances again on the Queen K. Rollin rollin rollin! Cheats cheats cheats&amp;hellip; draft fest passing, trying to find gaps and passing some others. Usual IM dance where marshals are non existent and guys blatantly suck your wheel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After reaching Waikoloa, the wind went from not being really worth a mention to &amp;ldquo;FUXK WHAT??&amp;rdquo; Level. In a matter of 2/3K, it was &amp;ldquo;head down&amp;rdquo; and speed down for the same power cap.
I kept an eye on power and HR, and kept eating and drinking, picking up people and generally feeling ok.
At one point, I sat up and took a good old look at an Italian guy who was blatantly trying to stay on my wheel. I pointed at him and called him a cheat. All he did was move past and went to suck another wheel&amp;hellip; Twat.
Same with a German a little later. Those guys have no shame, and no marshal was to be seen anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like many, I know there is a simple space problem at the start of the race, and if you want to ride legally, you either have to be at the front, push way over your FTP to overtake constantly until you reach the front, or let everyone go&amp;hellip; You&amp;rsquo;d be on roadside for a while for that one!
But further up the road, 70Km in, there&amp;rsquo;s no excuse for this behaviour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From Kawaihae to the bottom of the climb I kept a lid on things, but went to work on the climb and got past quite  a few large groups. Climbing is my game, and I knew that I would not be able to pedal fast on the descent with my lack of gears (I thought I&amp;rsquo;d have needed a 54). We were still in a headwind and progress wasn&amp;rsquo;t particularly fast, but steady and feeling strong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thought, like everyone else, that we&amp;rsquo;d have a tailwind on the way back, but nope! After the little rise when coming back out of Hawi, the wind was a headwind again&amp;hellip; Ugh!! It would be like this and getting stronger all the way back!
I didn&amp;rsquo;t really notice any bad crosswinds. Sure, the bike was moving a bit in between the rocks, but seriously, nothing major like the horror stories I&amp;rsquo;ve heard of past years, and I stayed aero for pretty much the entire ride, including the climb up Hawi.
I stupidly managed to finish all my gels by 140K, and shot blocks were getting tedious, but that&amp;rsquo;s all I had. I should have packed a BLT somewhere!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I followed the pro race from the inside and saw the men pack on the bike thinking &amp;ldquo;it&amp;rsquo;s all to play for&amp;rdquo;, while the mega gap for the women was more &amp;ldquo;it&amp;rsquo;s all over!&amp;rdquo;, specially Rinny being so far behind solo leader Ryf.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The headwind on the way back was very strong. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if that&amp;rsquo;s visible on the Garmin files but the return was looooooong!! There weren&amp;rsquo;t many riders left around me anymore and it was nice to have space and be able to put my head down properly without having to look too much where I was going.
I finally reached the airport, the energy lab, then saw Frodeno with Kienle in town, a few kms before I turned on Makala Bvd, thinking &amp;ldquo;show time&amp;rdquo;. I was happy, smiling, feeling great, and couldn&amp;rsquo;t wait to get off that damn saddle! As usual in an IM ride&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bike was a lot slower than I expected, but although I can now say that I could have pushed more, at the time I thought that I had done rather well to keep a lid on everything in the wind.
Doing a bit of maths, it looks like I&amp;rsquo;ve got a good VI of 1.024 with NP 207W and AVG 202W, with a moderately low intensity factor of 0.75, and a TSS of just over 300. So numbers do prove that while it was well executed and stable, setting me up for a good run, I could have definitely pushed a bit more!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;T2 was the whole &amp;ldquo;hairdo / have a natter / take your time / laugh at stressed people&amp;rdquo; shebang, and I really, really took my time. It was all about enjoying the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;rsquo;t remember thinking too much about pace on the run, only looking at my HR and noticing it was pretty low, so I kept going!
Not crazy fast, but maybe a bit too hard given the heat an humidity.
Trying to maintain this over the first inclines did need some effort, but I was only going by HR and all was good! I was high-fiving kids as usual, and also some good friends that were there in the first mile, and it was all a bit surreal. I kept on the coke, sponges and ice all the way around, with a couple of gels and a couple of nutella pods (yum!!!) as treats for each 8km completed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, I still kept a bit of a lid on the initial few Kms, remembered that there are a couple of long climbs on the out-and-back (as I discovered in training!) so HR was my measure.
I&amp;rsquo;m pleased to say that I ran up Palani all the way, at my rhythm, but feeling good and not tight at all!
I had a nice chat at the top with the guys giving away salt tubes (yes, still running and chatting :p ), but the Queen K quickly felt boring. Not very hard as the surface is really smooth, but just boring in between the amazing volunteers cheers at the aid stations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I saw the solar panels and thought &amp;ldquo;YES!&amp;rdquo;, while smiling to myself.
Crazy people everywhere, a great DJ at the bottom of the road with those CLIF iced sponges, and special needs to look forward to. Having ran the energy lab section in training, there was no surprise other than it turning back shorter than what I did during the week. I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel hot, kept my HR in check, and had a good time.
I took my special needs stuff, but I ended up carrying it home. My stomach had had enough, so water and coke were the name of the day for the last Kms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s only after being back on the Queen K that I started to feel a bit tired, and my run started to be laboured. But I was still passing people, and that kept me going.
My watch was telling me I could get close to 3h15, but sadly, the rollers back into town were a lot steeper than I remembered, and the pace slowly drifted away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had to stop a few seconds at the top of Palani to stretch my hamstrings and avoid hobbling down the hill, which worked a treat.
That&amp;rsquo;s the only place I got passed on the whole run, but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t care less as this was the end of a brilliant day!
I passed early race leader Meredith Kessler on Kuakini, before reaching the bottom of Hualalai, and turn right this time! Not far now! High five people. Turn around see if anyone is coming behind (I wanted a good photo!!) and run down THAT finish chute and cross THAT line!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end this was an IM marathon PB for me by over 2 minutes, so even if I tired in the end, it was well paced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was hoping some of the BLL gang back in London were still awake and not too drunk, still thanking the amazing people coming out to cheer at the finish, then getting helped away from the line by two very nice volunteers. Not that I needed help, but it was a nice touch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Collect medal, bag of goodies, find a free spot on the grass and&amp;hellip; And that&amp;rsquo;s it! WC done!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a real shame one can&amp;rsquo;t simply register for this race, as it&amp;rsquo;s a well balanced course and a great setting. If not for the qualification, I&amp;rsquo;d do it again happily!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But this was my last branded IM race so this was special to do it in style. Thanks &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/smernicki&quot;&gt;Paul&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/troymaloy&quot;&gt;Troy&lt;/a&gt; for the amazing BLL kit! The end of two years of proper chase and mental strain, so that was a mixed bag of emotions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not going to do more than one iron distance a year now, but I&amp;rsquo;m moving onto sillier ones in cold water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See you out there!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;table_container&quot;&gt;
    &lt;table&gt;
        &lt;thead&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
                &lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
                &lt;th&gt;time&lt;/th&gt;
                &lt;th&gt;GPS data&lt;/th&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;/thead&gt;
        &lt;tbody&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;Swim (3.8Km)&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;1h09'42&quot;&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;T1&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;5'08&quot;&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;Bike (180km)&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;5h20'29&quot;&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;bike data&quot; href=&quot;https://connect.garmin.com/modern/activity/1397410634&quot;&gt;data&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;T2&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;6'35&quot;&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;Run (42.2Km)&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;3h17'56&quot;&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;run data&quot; href=&quot;https://connect.garmin.com/modern/activity/1397413382&quot;&gt;data&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;Finish&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;9h59'50&quot;&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;450th overall, 102nd in M35-39&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;/tbody&gt;
    &lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;gallery&quot;&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-10-30-ironman-world-championship-kona-hawaii/01.JPG&quot; title=&quot;01_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[kona-wc-2016]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-10-30-ironman-world-championship-kona-hawaii/01_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;01_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-10-30-ironman-world-championship-kona-hawaii/02.JPG&quot; title=&quot;02_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[kona-wc-2016]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-10-30-ironman-world-championship-kona-hawaii/02_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;02_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-10-30-ironman-world-championship-kona-hawaii/03.JPG&quot; title=&quot;03_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[kona-wc-2016]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-10-30-ironman-world-championship-kona-hawaii/03_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;03_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-10-30-ironman-world-championship-kona-hawaii/04.JPG&quot; title=&quot;04_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[kona-wc-2016]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-10-30-ironman-world-championship-kona-hawaii/04_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;04_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-10-30-ironman-world-championship-kona-hawaii/05.JPG&quot; title=&quot;05_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[kona-wc-2016]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-10-30-ironman-world-championship-kona-hawaii/05_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;05_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-10-30-ironman-world-championship-kona-hawaii/06.JPG&quot; title=&quot;06_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[kona-wc-2016]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-10-30-ironman-world-championship-kona-hawaii/06_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;06_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-10-30-ironman-world-championship-kona-hawaii/07.JPG&quot; title=&quot;07_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[kona-wc-2016]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-10-30-ironman-world-championship-kona-hawaii/07_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;07_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-10-30-ironman-world-championship-kona-hawaii/08.JPG&quot; title=&quot;08_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[kona-wc-2016]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-10-30-ironman-world-championship-kona-hawaii/08_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;08_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-10-30-ironman-world-championship-kona-hawaii/09.JPG&quot; title=&quot;09_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[kona-wc-2016]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-10-30-ironman-world-championship-kona-hawaii/09_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;09_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-10-30-ironman-world-championship-kona-hawaii/10.JPG&quot; title=&quot;10_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[kona-wc-2016]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-10-30-ironman-world-championship-kona-hawaii/10_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;10_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-10-30-ironman-world-championship-kona-hawaii/11.JPG&quot; title=&quot;11_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[kona-wc-2016]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-10-30-ironman-world-championship-kona-hawaii/11_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;11_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-10-30-ironman-world-championship-kona-hawaii/12.JPG&quot; title=&quot;12_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[kona-wc-2016]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-10-30-ironman-world-championship-kona-hawaii/12_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;12_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-10-30-ironman-world-championship-kona-hawaii/13.JPG&quot; title=&quot;13_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[kona-wc-2016]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-10-30-ironman-world-championship-kona-hawaii/13_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;13_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-10-30-ironman-world-championship-kona-hawaii/14.JPG&quot; title=&quot;14_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[kona-wc-2016]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-10-30-ironman-world-championship-kona-hawaii/14_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;14_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-10-30-ironman-world-championship-kona-hawaii/15.JPG&quot; title=&quot;15_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[kona-wc-2016]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-10-30-ironman-world-championship-kona-hawaii/15_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;15_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-10-30-ironman-world-championship-kona-hawaii/17.JPG&quot; title=&quot;17_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[kona-wc-2016]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-10-30-ironman-world-championship-kona-hawaii/17_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;17_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-10-30-ironman-world-championship-kona-hawaii/18.JPG&quot; title=&quot;18_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[kona-wc-2016]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-10-30-ironman-world-championship-kona-hawaii/18_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;18_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-10-30-ironman-world-championship-kona-hawaii/19.JPG&quot; title=&quot;19_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[kona-wc-2016]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-10-30-ironman-world-championship-kona-hawaii/19_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;19_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-10-30-ironman-world-championship-kona-hawaii/20.JPG&quot; title=&quot;20_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[kona-wc-2016]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-10-30-ironman-world-championship-kona-hawaii/20_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;20_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-10-30-ironman-world-championship-kona-hawaii/21.JPG&quot; title=&quot;21_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[kona-wc-2016]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-10-30-ironman-world-championship-kona-hawaii/21_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;21_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-10-30-ironman-world-championship-kona-hawaii/22.JPG&quot; title=&quot;22_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[kona-wc-2016]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-10-30-ironman-world-championship-kona-hawaii/22_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;22_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-10-30-ironman-world-championship-kona-hawaii/23.JPG&quot; title=&quot;23_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[kona-wc-2016]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-10-30-ironman-world-championship-kona-hawaii/23_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;23_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-10-30-ironman-world-championship-kona-hawaii/24.JPG&quot; title=&quot;24_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[kona-wc-2016]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-10-30-ironman-world-championship-kona-hawaii/24_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;24_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-10-30-ironman-world-championship-kona-hawaii/25.JPG&quot; title=&quot;25_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[kona-wc-2016]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-10-30-ironman-world-championship-kona-hawaii/25_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;25_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-10-30-ironman-world-championship-kona-hawaii/26.JPG&quot; title=&quot;26_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[kona-wc-2016]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-10-30-ironman-world-championship-kona-hawaii/26_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;26_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-10-30-ironman-world-championship-kona-hawaii/27.JPG&quot; title=&quot;27_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[kona-wc-2016]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-10-30-ironman-world-championship-kona-hawaii/27_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;27_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-10-30-ironman-world-championship-kona-hawaii/kona.png&quot; title=&quot;kona_r300.png&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[kona-wc-2016]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-10-30-ironman-world-championship-kona-hawaii/kona_r300.png&quot; alt=&quot;kona_r300.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
                <pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2016 22:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tri.ekynoxe.com/ironman-world-championship-kona-hawaii</link>
                <author>hello@ekynoxe.com (Mathieu Davy)</author>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://tri.ekynoxe.com/ironman-world-championship-kona-hawaii</guid>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Stryd: A first run with power</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;At the Ironman World Championship in Kona, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.stryd.com/&quot;&gt;Stryd&lt;/a&gt; was running a data-gathering trial to help them improve their product, a running power meter in foot-pod.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a data geek, I liked the idea of collecting more data for my run. At least as a curiosity.
I collected a foot-pod - kindly lent for the race by Stryd for free - a couple of days before the event. I was only going to let it record data, and not attempt to change any settings on my watch to display any field that would confuse me during my race.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-10-26-stryd-a-first-run-with-power/pod.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Stryd foot-pod&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2016-10-26-stryd-a-first-run-with-power]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-10-26-stryd-a-first-run-with-power/pod_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Stryd foot-pod&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-10-26-stryd-a-first-run-with-power/MD-1-Race.png&quot; title=&quot;Race power, pace and elevation&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2016-10-26-stryd-a-first-run-with-power]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-10-26-stryd-a-first-run-with-power/MD-1-Race.png&quot; alt=&quot;Race power, pace and elevation&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;!--more--&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The pod wasn&amp;rsquo;t perceivable at all on my shoe, and that unobtrusiveness is what convinced me to try it. I don&amp;rsquo;t think I would have tried with the chest strap. It was only a case of clipping the pod on my laces and forgetting about it until giving it back for later data analysis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I felt pretty good going out of transition, and I settled quickly in my run. All &amp;ldquo;reasonable targets&amp;rdquo; went out of the window straight away and instead of starting slowly, I started at my target pace from other flatter races. Not crazy fast, but probably a bit too hard given the heat an humidity. Trying to maintain this over the first inclines did need some effort, and that&amp;rsquo;s clearly visible on the power curve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, this happened all the way around the course on the inclines, and the biggest surge was to run up Palani, which is clearly visible on the power data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5&gt;Power and pace on Palani&lt;/h5&gt;


&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-10-26-stryd-a-first-run-with-power/MD-2-Palani.png&quot; title=&quot;Power and pace on Palani&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2016-10-26-stryd-a-first-run-with-power]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-10-26-stryd-a-first-run-with-power/MD-2-Palani.png&quot; alt=&quot;Power and pace on Palani&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Overall - based on how I felt on the day - I can break down my run in three parts: transition to the downhill after Huggo&amp;rsquo;s, Huggo&amp;rsquo;s to the exit of the energy lab, and the return into town. I remember having to tell myself to keep a lid on the pace after the first few kms. Then settling in a nice rhythm all the way around the Queen K, including the energy lab. And only starting to feel it once I rejoined the Highway, and on the rollers back into town.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking at the data, those three stages are roughly visible, especially the drop after the energy lab. Cadence and Leg Spring Stiffness show this better than pace, while power was slowly going down on average.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5&gt;Leg Spring Stiffness&lt;/h5&gt;


&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-10-26-stryd-a-first-run-with-power/MD-3-LSS.png&quot; title=&quot;Leg Spring Stiffness&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2016-10-26-stryd-a-first-run-with-power]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-10-26-stryd-a-first-run-with-power/MD-3-LSS.png&quot; alt=&quot;Leg Spring Stiffness&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;h5&gt;Cadence&lt;/h5&gt;


&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-10-26-stryd-a-first-run-with-power/MD-4-Cadence.png&quot; title=&quot;Cadence&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2016-10-26-stryd-a-first-run-with-power]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-10-26-stryd-a-first-run-with-power/MD-4-Cadence.png&quot; alt=&quot;Cadence&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;h5&gt;Power&lt;/h5&gt;


&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-10-26-stryd-a-first-run-with-power/MD-5-Power.png&quot; title=&quot;Power&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2016-10-26-stryd-a-first-run-with-power]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-10-26-stryd-a-first-run-with-power/MD-5-Power.png&quot; alt=&quot;Power&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Looking at some of the pros files, it&amp;rsquo;s clear that although a lot slower, I had a much more even run, so variations are not easy to spot. It felt great and well paced all the way around, and the data clearly shows this. This was an IM marathon PB for me by over 2 minutes, so even if I tired in the end, it was well paced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The power curve seems to be tracking rather well to the efforts I felt during the run, so this is for me very comparable to working with power on the bike. I am not yet sure how I would use leg spring stiffness as this is a new metric for me. It seems that it would be initially a constant monitoring tool for running improvements, and perhaps fatigue monitoring along the season.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of people are skeptical about it, including me to some extent, but I will refuse to label it as &amp;ldquo;utter nonsense&amp;rdquo; as some people I know called it!
After all, didn&amp;rsquo;t the same thing happen when SRM created their first bike power meter in the 80s?
I&amp;rsquo;ll be keen to review it and the data when it is fully mature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having benefited tremendously from using my bike power meter. If the metrics collected by the foot-pod are reliable and consistent, I can&amp;rsquo;t see any reason why it would be any worse than a power meter on a bike.
The interpretation of the results will need tweaking and refining, but much like for a bike ride, there are plenty of variables that can affect it, and a good dose of pragmatism is needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully, taking part in this trial will help Stryd perfect their product and analysis tools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I do not work, nor am I sponsored by Stryd. The foot-pod I used during the Ironman World Championship was a prototype lent to me for the day, and I returned it right after the race. The data shown on the graphs was the result of the Stryd team doing some data crunching that their systems will eventually do automatically&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2016 21:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
                <link>http://tri.ekynoxe.com/stryd-a-first-run-with-power</link>
                <author>hello@ekynoxe.com (Mathieu Davy)</author>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://tri.ekynoxe.com/stryd-a-first-run-with-power</guid>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Thorpe park olympic triathlon</title>
                <description>&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-07-17-thorpe-park-olympic-triathlon/05.jpg&quot; title=&quot;POWER!!&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[thorpe-park-olympic-triathlon]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-07-17-thorpe-park-olympic-triathlon/05_r500.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;POWER!!&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been a long time since my last olympic tri around Eton Dorney back in 2012.
This time, though, it was a massive PB around a theme park!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;gallery&quot;&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-07-17-thorpe-park-olympic-triathlon/01.jpg&quot; title=&quot;01_r300.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[thorpe-park-olympic-triathlon]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-07-17-thorpe-park-olympic-triathlon/01_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;01_r300.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-07-17-thorpe-park-olympic-triathlon/02.jpg&quot; title=&quot;02_r300.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[thorpe-park-olympic-triathlon]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-07-17-thorpe-park-olympic-triathlon/02_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;02_r300.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-07-17-thorpe-park-olympic-triathlon/03.jpg&quot; title=&quot;03_r300.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[thorpe-park-olympic-triathlon]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-07-17-thorpe-park-olympic-triathlon/03_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;03_r300.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-07-17-thorpe-park-olympic-triathlon/04.jpg&quot; title=&quot;04_r300.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[thorpe-park-olympic-triathlon]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-07-17-thorpe-park-olympic-triathlon/04_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;04_r300.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-07-17-thorpe-park-olympic-triathlon/05.jpg&quot; title=&quot;POWER!!&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[thorpe-park-olympic-triathlon]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-07-17-thorpe-park-olympic-triathlon/05_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;POWER!!&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-07-17-thorpe-park-olympic-triathlon/06.jpg&quot; title=&quot;06_r300.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[thorpe-park-olympic-triathlon]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-07-17-thorpe-park-olympic-triathlon/06_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;06_r300.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-07-17-thorpe-park-olympic-triathlon/07.jpg&quot; title=&quot;07_r300.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[thorpe-park-olympic-triathlon]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-07-17-thorpe-park-olympic-triathlon/07_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;07_r300.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-07-17-thorpe-park-olympic-triathlon/08.jpg&quot; title=&quot;08_r300.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[thorpe-park-olympic-triathlon]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-07-17-thorpe-park-olympic-triathlon/08_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;08_r300.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-07-17-thorpe-park-olympic-triathlon/09.jpg&quot; title=&quot;09_r300.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[thorpe-park-olympic-triathlon]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-07-17-thorpe-park-olympic-triathlon/09_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;09_r300.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
                <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2016 21:12:00 +0100</pubDate>
                <link>http://tri.ekynoxe.com/thorpe-park-olympic-triathlon</link>
                <author>hello@ekynoxe.com (Mathieu Davy)</author>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://tri.ekynoxe.com/thorpe-park-olympic-triathlon</guid>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Dorset gravel dash 100 - Harder than you think!</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s the end of a long off-season break, bruised ribs from an MTB crash 5 weeks ago have just about healed, yet, I’m standing at the start of a 100 miles “gravel dash” in Swanage, Dorset.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;100 miles doesn’t seem too much, right? After all, I race longer and train close to that distance regularly.
Small detail, though: that’s on paved roads…
While driving to Swanage where the event starts and finishes, I already started to realise what I was letting myself into. Hill, hills, and more hills. Chalky cliffs. Some flooded fields… I could already picture crashes, a mud bath and walking a lot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was going to be a long day either way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-05-30-dorset-gravel-dash-100-harder-than-you-think/17.jpg&quot; title=&quot;It's not a bloody race!&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2016-05-30-dorset-gravel-dash]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-05-30-dorset-gravel-dash-100-harder-than-you-think/17_r500.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;It's not a bloody race!&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;!--more--&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The extraordinary 2 minutes race briefing went something like “don’t be a dick”, and “it’s not a bloody race”. The rest was up to us all riders, with our navigation devices fully charged (hopefully), and almost a full day ahead to clear the course.
At least the weather was perfect, albeit with a bit of a breeze.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-05-30-dorset-gravel-dash-100-harder-than-you-think/1.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Emma &amp;quot;grammin'&amp;quot;&quot; The calm before the dash&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2016-05-30-dorset-gravel-dash]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-05-30-dorset-gravel-dash-100-harder-than-you-think/1_r500.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Emma &amp;quot;grammin'&amp;quot;&quot; The calm before the dash&quot; /&gt;&lt;span&gt;Emma &quot;grammin'&quot;. The calm before the dash&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The atmosphere at the start was humorous, people checking one another’s choice of steed for the day and the various amounts of kit everyone transported. Cross bikes, MTBs of all sorts, a few fat bikes and a few single speed (!!). Everybody laughing, no one looking apprehensive, really, before we all set off through the streets of Swanage, straight up the hills and the first chalky bits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was here because I’ve got supposedly the best bike for the job (a Kinesys ATR Tripster), and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/waterrat77&quot;&gt;Emma Osenton&lt;/a&gt; has been raising my FOMO levels to 11 to try this kind of ride for a long time. She’s lives in the Yorkshire Dales, and does this sort of stuff all the time! I managed to follow her for about 4 miles until the first hill where she disappeared in the distance! My legs were already on fire. See you at the finish!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5&gt;Tip #1:&lt;/h5&gt;


&lt;blockquote&gt;This is not the right event to kick-start a new race season after 6 weeks off!&lt;/blockquote&gt;


&lt;p&gt;It was a bit chilly at the start, but we all warmed up quickly on that first climb: I was already out of gears and already feeling my legs. Uh oh! What’s that? Turns out CX gearing with 36x28 was still too big for this! This would be repeated over and over and over again for the next 94 miles… A CX bike is a good option for this event. Gearing choice, however, is not to be overlooked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5&gt;Tip #2:&lt;/h5&gt;


&lt;blockquote&gt;The best option is probably a 1x drivetrain with a super small gear to go up steep bits, or at the very least a 32 at the back!&lt;/blockquote&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Everything that goes up must……. come back down! On the road: YAY!!! On big chalky gravel paths: a lot less “yay”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hanging on for dear life, I thank the gods of disc brakes and their amazing modulation, but I was still locking front and back wheel now and again and cursing my roadie up-bringing. &amp;ldquo;More REAR brake, less chances of stacking it down those hills!&amp;rdquo; was what I was repeating myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent most of the day alone, my nose stuck to my Garmin screen checking that I was on the correct route, passing some people from time to time, but mostly getting overtaken by people with proper skills. I caught up plenty of riders when back on the black stuff, but I wasn’t there for that. I was here to get my ass handed over to me by some punishing countryside trails. And I haven’t been disappointed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5&gt;Tip #3:&lt;/h5&gt;


&lt;blockquote&gt;There’s no quick fix for lack of skills.&lt;/blockquote&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I’m RUBBISH downhill off-road, and have no confidence at all on the trails. I walked a fair bit!
To be fair, bruising my ribs on an MTB a few weeks ago probably did dent my confidence. But lack of skills still shows!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At some point, there’s a nice long sweeping road descent. Nice! I liked that! What I didn’t like, though, was my front tire skidding and only avoiding a crash at 50kph around a downhill bend because of some tire/road grip miracle. Turns out my front wheel was losing pressure a lot quicker than I thought. I could feel it being a bit bouncy prior to that, but I put that down to the general low pressure I run on those nice 40mm tubeless tires. Muppet!
I also had my headset come loose at the top of a gravel descent, front and back skewers getting undone (the magic is strong on the trails!) and my shiny brand new pedals refuse to let me unclip before finishing in a hedge with a perfect prat-fall. No biggie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-05-30-dorset-gravel-dash-100-harder-than-you-think/10.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Loose headset&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2016-05-30-dorset-gravel-dash]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-05-30-dorset-gravel-dash-100-harder-than-you-think/10_r500.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Loose headset&quot; /&gt;&lt;span&gt;On course repairs...&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;h5&gt;Tip #4:&lt;/h5&gt;


&lt;blockquote&gt;Don’t ignore warning signs from your kit.&lt;/blockquote&gt;


&lt;h5&gt;Tip #5:&lt;/h5&gt;


&lt;blockquote&gt;Don’t try anything new on event (this is not a race!) day!&lt;/blockquote&gt;


&lt;p&gt;After this, I spent the rest of my day checking (and pumping) my front tire back up regularly. That was a good excuse to stop and admire the scenery which was beautiful with the day&amp;rsquo;s weather.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;gallery&quot;&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-05-30-dorset-gravel-dash-100-harder-than-you-think/2.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Lush countryside&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2016-05-30-dorset-gravel-dash]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-05-30-dorset-gravel-dash-100-harder-than-you-think/2_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Lush countryside&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-05-30-dorset-gravel-dash-100-harder-than-you-think/6.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Spot for lunch?&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2016-05-30-dorset-gravel-dash]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-05-30-dorset-gravel-dash-100-harder-than-you-think/6_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Spot for lunch?&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-05-30-dorset-gravel-dash-100-harder-than-you-think/9.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Rolling&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2016-05-30-dorset-gravel-dash]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-05-30-dorset-gravel-dash-100-harder-than-you-think/9_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Rolling&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Mind, there were a lot of other stops along the way. The first few field gates are no big deal. “Entering a field of sheep”. “Entering a field of bulls”. All fun! “Look, ma: I’m off-road!!”.
By mile 50, I had lost count of how many field gates I had to open and close, how many had swung back and smashed my hands and the back wheel. By mile 80, this was far from fun anymore. I wanted to go home, not open and close gates.
My arse was sore. My hands had blisters because of the rattling on the “gravel” and hanging on the bars like a madman to manage the brakes, I had almost no water left, and my shiny new bike was caked in mud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5&gt;Tip #6:&lt;/h5&gt;


&lt;blockquote&gt;This is not the Thames path “gravel”. This is proper punishing stuff!&lt;/blockquote&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The Dorset dash is organised by locals who know their off-road stuff pretty well. And that showed regularly around the route. Like the proper downhill trail that I couldn’t even contemplate riding. Or the single track descent on chalk gravel, with no grip, and a large tree trunk at head high slap bang in the middle where you’re supposed to be at speed. (I avoided that one, thankfully) Or the last decent 5Km from the finish that was so steep hikers had to stop to take a breather. Not ridden down this one either!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-05-30-dorset-gravel-dash-100-harder-than-you-think/13.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Finish line in sight&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2016-05-30-dorset-gravel-dash]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-05-30-dorset-gravel-dash-100-harder-than-you-think/13.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Finish line in sight&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-05-30-dorset-gravel-dash-100-harder-than-you-think/12.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Touristy spots&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2016-05-30-dorset-gravel-dash]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-05-30-dorset-gravel-dash-100-harder-than-you-think/12_r500.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Touristy spots&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;But aside from those technical bits which I hated mostly because of my appalling ability off-road, the rest of the route was great. Challenging up some steep hills, beautiful through green fields and forest trails. I even liked the mud! The scenery was fantastic. Being mostly off-road, there was almost no traffic all day, other than a few sheep and bulls, and a flock of bank holiday tourists on the beach at the finish. But there was a lot less “gravel” than I thought there would be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;gallery&quot;&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-05-30-dorset-gravel-dash-100-harder-than-you-think/11.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Gravel at last!!&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2016-05-30-dorset-gravel-dash]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-05-30-dorset-gravel-dash-100-harder-than-you-think/11_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Gravel at last!!&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-05-30-dorset-gravel-dash-100-harder-than-you-think/3.jpg&quot; title=&quot;A bit damp in places&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2016-05-30-dorset-gravel-dash]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-05-30-dorset-gravel-dash-100-harder-than-you-think/3_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A bit damp in places&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-05-30-dorset-gravel-dash-100-harder-than-you-think/4.jpg&quot; title=&quot;First dirt. It's all downhill from here!&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2016-05-30-dorset-gravel-dash]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-05-30-dorset-gravel-dash-100-harder-than-you-think/4_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;First dirt. It's all downhill from here!&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-05-30-dorset-gravel-dash-100-harder-than-you-think/5.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Rumble strip in a field?&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2016-05-30-dorset-gravel-dash]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-05-30-dorset-gravel-dash-100-harder-than-you-think/5_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Rumble strip in a field?&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-05-30-dorset-gravel-dash-100-harder-than-you-think/7.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Now you're talking!! Sluuuuuurp!!&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2016-05-30-dorset-gravel-dash]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-05-30-dorset-gravel-dash-100-harder-than-you-think/7_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Now you're talking!! Sluuuuuurp!!&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;This is not a bloody race. There are no results. Just the joy of having conquered a pretty tough event that was supposed to be “just gravel” in around 10h…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Riding under the checkered flag (still not a race!!), cheering the other riders coming home, the beers, fish and chips and friendliness of everyone rounded up an awesome day out in the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So like everything that’s challenging, there were bits I loved, bits I hated. I wanted to go home about &amp;frac34; in, but the camaraderie and the general fun nature of the event will make me go back for more “gravel” fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5&gt;Tip #7:&lt;/h5&gt;


&lt;blockquote&gt;If you fancy this kind of stuff but have never done it before, just do yourself one big favour: chose a shorter one!&lt;/blockquote&gt;


&lt;p&gt;More please!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to do it yourself in your own time, &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-05-30-dorset-gravel-dash-100-harder-than-you-think/DorsetGravelDash100-2016-V2.gpx&quot;&gt;here’s the GPX file&lt;/a&gt;. You’ll ask yourself a few times “Really? Through here?”. The answers are both “Yes”. Just follow the route!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good luck!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;gallery&quot;&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-05-30-dorset-gravel-dash-100-harder-than-you-think/14.jpg&quot; title=&quot;10h of Dorset's finest back country!&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2016-05-30-dorset-gravel-dash]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-05-30-dorset-gravel-dash-100-harder-than-you-think/14_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;10h of Dorset's finest back country!&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-05-30-dorset-gravel-dash-100-harder-than-you-think/15.jpg&quot; title=&quot;The mechanic has his job cut-out!&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2016-05-30-dorset-gravel-dash]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-05-30-dorset-gravel-dash-100-harder-than-you-think/15_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The mechanic has his job cut-out!&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-05-30-dorset-gravel-dash-100-harder-than-you-think/16.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Yes, this is beer...&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2016-05-30-dorset-gravel-dash]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-05-30-dorset-gravel-dash-100-harder-than-you-think/16_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Yes, this is beer...&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-05-30-dorset-gravel-dash-100-harder-than-you-think/18.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Looks like Emma had a good day too!&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2016-05-30-dorset-gravel-dash]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-05-30-dorset-gravel-dash-100-harder-than-you-think/18_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Looks like Emma had a good day too!&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-05-30-dorset-gravel-dash-100-harder-than-you-think/19.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Sharing a beer with the first lady.&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2016-05-30-dorset-gravel-dash]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-05-30-dorset-gravel-dash-100-harder-than-you-think/19_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sharing a beer with the first lady.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-05-30-dorset-gravel-dash-100-harder-than-you-think/bib.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Don't be a dick!&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2016-05-30-dorset-gravel-dash]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-05-30-dorset-gravel-dash-100-harder-than-you-think/bib_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Don't be a dick!&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
                <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2016 13:44:00 +0100</pubDate>
                <link>http://tri.ekynoxe.com/dorset-gravel-dash-100-harder-than-you-think</link>
                <author>hello@ekynoxe.com (Mathieu Davy)</author>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://tri.ekynoxe.com/dorset-gravel-dash-100-harder-than-you-think</guid>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Ironman South Africa</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Coming close to qualification last year in &lt;a href=&quot;/ironman-uk-bolton/&quot;&gt;Bolton&lt;/a&gt;, and after the disappointment of &lt;a href=&quot;/ironman-wales-tenby/&quot;&gt;IM Wales&lt;/a&gt;, I was ready to pack it all up. But being so close, and keeping improving, I followed friends' advice, and I &amp;ldquo;followed the slots&amp;rdquo; with my ticket to South Africa. At a championship race with 75 slots on offer, and ageing up for one of the largest age groups, I hoped I could get close to the top like at IM UK, and if not in the slots directly, get myself a roll-down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/25.JPG&quot; title=&quot;25.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[IM_SA_2016]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/25.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;25.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;!--more--&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Winter training was pretty tough, with only 3 rides done outside before flying for Port Elizabeth, and the rest done on the the turbo. But running was going well, and swimming kept improving slowly too, albeit in the pool. Everything was indicating I could have a fantastic day. The unknown being the elements and the heat, but that was one of the uncontrollable things that everyone would have to deal with anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The few days before the race spent reccing the course, which included a checkup of the full bike loop. It was so windy that it took me over 2h to get to the turnaround point, and I easily broke my 25mi PB on the way back&amp;hellip; I was really hoping this would not be race conditions!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/windy.jpg&quot; title=&quot;windy&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[IM_SA_2016]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/windy_r500.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;windy&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;On the swim, I seeded myself just at the beginning of the 60-90min pen, but given the mess the rolling start was, I&amp;rsquo;m not sure I was actually swimming with fast-ish athletes. However, I had clear water pretty much all the way around, and unlike Bolton and Wales, I was dead on every single buoy around the course. The swell was pretty big, but &amp;ldquo;long&amp;rdquo;. Not as choppy, short and sharp as in Wales. I felt strong all round, and it really did feel fast. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t. But at least this time, I didn&amp;rsquo;t know. I intentionally swam without a watch so I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t know my swim time and therefore would not be tempted to absolutely hammer the bike like I did in Wales. In fact, I didn&amp;rsquo;t have any indication of overall time as I used my watch only for the run, and my Garmin edge for the bike. This was intentional so I would concentrate on only one thing at a time, and not faff about with buttons, modes, transitions in between legs etc&amp;hellip; I quite liked that and I&amp;rsquo;ll do that from now on for middle and long distance events.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I turns out I had one of my slowest ever swims in 1h13' :/ Not a great start, really!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/06.JPG&quot; title=&quot;06_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[IM_SA_2016]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/06.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;06_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;On the bike, there was almost no wind, or very little, to start with. So it was pretty fast on the first lap. I started with my target power of 220W but could not hold that for very long without my legs screaming and my HR going through the roof. 220W felt like I was working very, very hard, but without signs of feeling bad. So I think this was a power-meter issue, because at 151 BPM average for the whole ride, I should well be able to hold this power. I also had my Garmin vectors on the bike in case my main PM would pack up like in Bolton with readings all over the shop, but I chose not to switch to them because readings were still stable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The wind picked up a little bit on the way back of the second lap, but it was pretty low, hence the slower 2nd lap, but still a fast ride. The NP slowly went down, but stabilised to 204W and I&amp;rsquo;ll take that. My new hydration system worked perfectly well, allowing me to get out of aero position very few times on the whole ride, and put my head down properly. I was pushing hard and it was relatively hot, though, as I could feel that my stomach was on the limit of accepting food. I&amp;rsquo;ll have to experiment with more savoury gels like peanut butter this summer. In hot climates, the passion fruit and caffeinated apple are a bit nauseating! The garmin recorded 32C max during the ride. Hotter than I ever did before, but other than a couple of twinges in my calves, it was mostly ok. I had a pretty tight right hip though. Not sure why, but that translated into a bad right foot position (or maybe the other way around?), and blisters on my right foot from soaked feet on the bike, which didn&amp;rsquo;t help on the run&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was on for sub 5h for most of the ride, so I&amp;rsquo;m a bit gutted about the leg and hip problems and flailing towards the end. But still, I&amp;rsquo;m pretty happy with that one. I have finally beaten all those records set at my first IM on the pancake flat course that Barcelona is. (I did 5h05 back then, singing to myself on the bike because I was bored&amp;hellip; But hobbled a 4h04 run :-p)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other than one loo break at the start (I stupidly forgot to go in T2&amp;hellip; argh!) and the special needs mess shortly after half way, I ran the whole bloody marathon! First time ever! It was over 30C to start with, and I was amazed to see how many people were already walking on their first lap. They may well have overcooked the bike (literally!). But I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel too hot, and was ticking Kms nicely, trying to keep as close as possible to my target pace. For some reason, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t quite match it. Maybe the heat, or the combination with the fast bike? I was looking forward to my nutella treat every lap (individual nutella pouch every 8-10Km, YUM!) and use coke + water all the time + a couple of gels over the first 25K.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The special needs facilities were very poor to dispose of bags, with nowhere to leave them from 20m after the station. I didn&amp;rsquo;t fancy a DQ for littering further down the road, so I had to take time to get the contents out. That was the first time I used the special needs, but it worked as a carrot for me to get more food and drive me forward. Next time I&amp;rsquo;ll plan it better to be a lot quicker through it, though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My foot blisters were pestering me, running a bit crooked, and I had a bit of low time between 25Km to 35Km (HR data seems to confirm this), but managed to pick it up a bit more after that. The only guy that passed me was at 41km, but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t follow him. I tried, but immediately started to cramp, and had to stretch my legs 100m before the finishing chute to avoid doing a pirate walk down the red carpet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some mental calculations towards the end spurred me on, knowing I was well under 10h, which would give me a massive PB, and be close to my target of 9h45. I was elated to find out that I was exactly on that mark! Would it be enough to achieve the dream goal of getting my ticket to the big island, though?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a nail biting night and morning before the slots allocation ceremony, it turned out it was enough to get the 10th slot in my AG! No roll-downs needed! Win!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all, I&amp;rsquo;m happy with the result, and this race seemed strikingly similar to my 703WC qualifying race at Lanzarote 70.3 back in 2013: fast, hot, cramping, feeling utterly rubbish at some points along the way, so not the best race ever. But a top 10 in AG, and this time directly in the slots!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kona baby!! Happy days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;table_container&quot;&gt;
    &lt;table&gt;
        &lt;thead&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
                &lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
                &lt;th&gt;time&lt;/th&gt;
                &lt;th&gt;GPS data&lt;/th&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;/thead&gt;
        &lt;tbody&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;Swim (3.8Km)&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;1h13'28&quot;&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;T1&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;2'53&quot;&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;Bike (180km)&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;5h03'23&quot;&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;bike data&quot; href=&quot;https://connect.garmin.com/modern/activity/1122284686&quot;&gt;data&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;T2&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;3'11&quot;&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;Run (42.2Km)&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;3h22'57&quot;&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;run data&quot; href=&quot;https://connect.garmin.com/modern/activity/1121490137&quot;&gt;data&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;Finish&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;9h45'52&quot;&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;65th overall, 10th in M35-39&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;/tbody&gt;
    &lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;gallery&quot;&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
       &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
           &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/windy.jpg&quot; title=&quot;windy_r300.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[IM_SA_2016]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/windy_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;windy_r300.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
       &lt;/dt&gt;
   &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/01.JPG&quot; title=&quot;01_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[IM_SA_2016]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/01_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;01_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/02.JPG&quot; title=&quot;02_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[IM_SA_2016]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/02_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;02_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/03.JPG&quot; title=&quot;03_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[IM_SA_2016]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/03_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;03_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/04.JPG&quot; title=&quot;04_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[IM_SA_2016]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/04_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;04_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/05.JPG&quot; title=&quot;05_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[IM_SA_2016]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/05_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;05_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/06.JPG&quot; title=&quot;06_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[IM_SA_2016]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/06_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;06_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/07.JPG&quot; title=&quot;07_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[IM_SA_2016]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/07_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;07_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/08.JPG&quot; title=&quot;08_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[IM_SA_2016]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/08_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;08_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/09.JPG&quot; title=&quot;09_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[IM_SA_2016]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/09_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;09_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/10.JPG&quot; title=&quot;10_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[IM_SA_2016]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/10_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;10_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/11.JPG&quot; title=&quot;11_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[IM_SA_2016]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/11_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;11_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/12.JPG&quot; title=&quot;12_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[IM_SA_2016]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/12_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;12_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/13.JPG&quot; title=&quot;13_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[IM_SA_2016]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/13_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;13_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/14.JPG&quot; title=&quot;14_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[IM_SA_2016]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/14_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;14_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/15.JPG&quot; title=&quot;15_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[IM_SA_2016]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/15_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;15_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/16.JPG&quot; title=&quot;16_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[IM_SA_2016]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/16_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;16_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/17.JPG&quot; title=&quot;17_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[IM_SA_2016]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/17_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;17_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/18.JPG&quot; title=&quot;18_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[IM_SA_2016]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/18_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;18_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/19.JPG&quot; title=&quot;19_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[IM_SA_2016]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/19_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;19_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/20.JPG&quot; title=&quot;20_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[IM_SA_2016]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/20_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;20_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/21.JPG&quot; title=&quot;21_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[IM_SA_2016]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/21_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;21_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/22.JPG&quot; title=&quot;22_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[IM_SA_2016]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/22_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;22_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/23.JPG&quot; title=&quot;23_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[IM_SA_2016]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/23_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;23_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/24.JPG&quot; title=&quot;24_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[IM_SA_2016]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/24_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;24_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/25.JPG&quot; title=&quot;25_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[IM_SA_2016]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/25_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;25_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/26.JPG&quot; title=&quot;26_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[IM_SA_2016]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/26_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;26_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/27.JPG&quot; title=&quot;27_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[IM_SA_2016]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/27_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;27_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/28.JPG&quot; title=&quot;28_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[IM_SA_2016]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/28_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;28_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/29.JPG&quot; title=&quot;29_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[IM_SA_2016]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/29_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;29_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/30.JPG&quot; title=&quot;30_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[IM_SA_2016]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/30_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;30_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/31.JPG&quot; title=&quot;31_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[IM_SA_2016]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/31_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;31_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/32.JPG&quot; title=&quot;32_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[IM_SA_2016]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/32_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;32_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/33.JPG&quot; title=&quot;33_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[IM_SA_2016]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/33_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;33_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/34.JPG&quot; title=&quot;34_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[IM_SA_2016]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/34_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;34_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/35.JPG&quot; title=&quot;35_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[IM_SA_2016]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/35_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;35_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/36.JPG&quot; title=&quot;36_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[IM_SA_2016]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/36_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;36_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/37.JPG&quot; title=&quot;37_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[IM_SA_2016]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/37_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;37_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/38.JPG&quot; title=&quot;38_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[IM_SA_2016]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/38_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;38_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/39.JPG&quot; title=&quot;39_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[IM_SA_2016]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/39_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;39_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/40.JPG&quot; title=&quot;40_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[IM_SA_2016]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/40_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;40_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/41.JPG&quot; title=&quot;41_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[IM_SA_2016]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/41_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;41_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/42.JPG&quot; title=&quot;42_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[IM_SA_2016]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/42_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;42_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/43.JPG&quot; title=&quot;43_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[IM_SA_2016]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/43_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;43_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/44.JPG&quot; title=&quot;44_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[IM_SA_2016]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/44_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;44_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/45.JPG&quot; title=&quot;45_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[IM_SA_2016]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/45_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;45_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/46.JPG&quot; title=&quot;46_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[IM_SA_2016]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/46_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;46_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/47.JPG&quot; title=&quot;47_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[IM_SA_2016]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/47_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;47_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/48.jpg&quot; title=&quot;48_r300.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[IM_SA_2016]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/48_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;48_r300.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/sa.png&quot; title=&quot;sa_r300.png&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[IM_SA_2016]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2016-04-12-ironman-south-africa/sa_r300.png&quot; alt=&quot;sa_r300.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
                <pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2016 21:15:00 +0100</pubDate>
                <link>http://tri.ekynoxe.com/ironman-south-africa</link>
                <author>hello@ekynoxe.com (Mathieu Davy)</author>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://tri.ekynoxe.com/ironman-south-africa</guid>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Ironman Wales - Tenby</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;One that has been on my list for a long time, because it looked awesomely hard. Sadly, the day didn&amp;rsquo;t go to plan&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-09-17-ironman-wales-tenby/IMG_4724.png&quot; title=&quot;Tenby - Goscar rock&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[ironman-wales-tenby]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-09-17-ironman-wales-tenby/IMG_4724_r500.png&quot; alt=&quot;Tenby - Goscar rock&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;!--more--&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I had a couple of weeks of rest post &lt;a href=&quot;/ironman-uk-bolton&quot;&gt;IM UK&lt;/a&gt;, but then re-focused quickly on my Kona qualification goal. I felt fantastic until about 10 days to go, where I caught a bug someone nicely brought to work with them&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;ve been there in the past (a bit ran down right before a race), and resting it up always worked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, this time, nothing did it. No amount of rest, meds or layers did anything, and I reached race morning feeling like I had swallowed razor blades, with tight and sore throat from inflamed glands, and feeling cold and weak. Basically, exactly the opposite of what you&amp;rsquo;d want before the start of a crazy long race.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The weather was not helping either. It had been perfect until the day before the race, but in typical Wales fashion, the wind was up AND blowing in the bay, raising a rather large swell. It was now cold, it rained overnight, and the forecast was for rain at some point in the day too&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still decided to start because I wasn’t completely dead, I had trained hard, and Wales was on my bucket list of races to complete some day. With rumours of it not being here next year, I wanted to tickle the monster regardless. And whatever happens, happens!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tried to seed myself appropriately for the swim, but for some reason the barriers in place were hampering everyone, and no one really knew where the pens were. I guess I was towards the middle of the 1:00-1:10 pen, but given the weather, it didn&amp;rsquo;t make much of a difference.
The rousing Welsh anthem I saw so many times on the previous years videos got straight through to my bones, and although feeling a little bit like in a rugby stadium for a 6-nations match, I just loved the feeling and got the goose bumps alright! Paul Kaye kept echoing what I’ve been told many times: “there are ironmans, hard Ironmans, then, there’s ironman Wales”.
The hooter went, and after what felt like an eternity, it was my turn to go through the rolling start pen, and commence my journey around the hills of Pembrokeshire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are no two ways around it: it’s hilly everywhere. Even in the swim. Period. I’m not the best of swimmers, but this swim was brutal. The swell was so big that I felt worse than a boat in a storm: not seeing a thing when in the through, and being launched forward when on the crest. I landed twice on lifeguards canoes as I simply didn’t see them until I was ON them, and I managed to be so close to all the buoys that I got dunked under because of how much they moved in the wind and swell.
The sea being so low on the day, we didn’t have to swim and run around Goscar rock in between the laps, and that made sighting a little more difficult. On the other hand, it meant less running on deep sand at the end of lap one.
This was a relief too, as exiting the water half way, I knew I wasn’t in a good shape. Feeling tight chested and a bit nauseous, the only relief of that swim was that the salt acted as a good analgesic for my sore throat!
The second lap was getting progressively worse weather wise, with bigger swell, and the long length of the triangular loop became extremely slow.
1h13 out of the water wasn’t what I was after, but given the conditions, I wasn’t too disappointed. That however, spurred me on to push for the rest of the race.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-09-17-ironman-wales-tenby/01.JPG&quot; title=&quot;Swim out&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[ironman-wales-tenby]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-09-17-ironman-wales-tenby/01_r500.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Swim out&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Wales has this funky twist after the swim that you have to run to T1 for about 1Km, after climbing the steep ramp from beach level to street level. This calls for a second pair of shoes left at the bottom of the ramp, and a spectacle run, where everyone is carrying a heavy wet suit towards the T1 tents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My legs felt surprisingly ok at that point, and I was encouraged by Steven Lord shouting at me from the top of his voice from the other end of the street! For the second time this year, he&amp;rsquo;d have to stop early in the race because it wasn’t his day. Still, he was there supporting after an amazing swim where he was out of the water 15th overall!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-09-17-ironman-wales-tenby/05.JPG&quot; title=&quot;cold at the start of the bike&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[ironman-wales-tenby]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-09-17-ironman-wales-tenby/05_r500.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;cold at the start of the bike&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Given I had a cold and it was Wales, I had packed a pair of thin full finger gloves and a long sleeved fusion speed top. Those were a saviour for the first half of the bike where I was feeling the cold. Nevertheless, I felt all right, and subconsciously pushed the paced to make up for lost ground in the swim. I was feeling good despite the cold, passed some friends from my old tri club. To my surprise, passed Emma Pooley, and was on my way to one of my craziest come-back rides to date.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Bolton was a strange ride, mostly lonely bar a few hotspots, the people of Tenby and the area go completely nuts on race day. There were people absolutely everywhere along the bike loop! Up or down, open road or twisty back country lanes:, the weather didn’t matter,  there were people everywhere!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really had a load of fun out there and although it’s a tough course, I absolutely loved it. In fact, I loved it so much that nothing felt too hard, and I really thought at the time that the reputation of some of those hills was way over-exaggerated. Others, however, weren’t on the map, but are a lot harder! The climb out of Wiseman’s Bridge for example, is on another level than the supposedly hard heartbreak hill that I barely noticed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unknown to me at the time, I had made a massive amount of ground on the top of my AG, and I came off the bike in 4th place, and 33rd overall!! And there’s only one way I could do this: by pushing too hard! I loved the bike course, and knowing my time in the swim and what I wanted out of the day, I had to try and push a little bit to see if I could hang on. I had an amazing run in bolton, so I was clinging to the thought that I could push through and hang in there.
However, being ill didn’t help, and after about 6-7km on my target pace and managing the first hill, it was game over to be in the slots. Every lap, I heard Steven shout before I could see him and that helped me speed up a bit while in town, but on the uphills at the far end of the course, there was much walking happening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Resigned to my fate, I still tried to take on the cheers, and give some encouragement to whom I recognised on course: a lot of my fellow Ealing D3 Triathletes friends, Andy Greenleaf for the few times I saw him smash the run in 2h55, and of course, the famous &lt;a href=&quot;http://blacklinelondon.com/ironman-wales-report/&quot;&gt;Alan Grove on his epic conquest&lt;/a&gt;.
I wish I had not been ill, and had the foresight to not push too hard on the bike to give the run the respect it deserves, but I didn’t, so I managed with what I had left in the tank which wasn’t pretty.
For the second half of my last lap, I clawed back a bit of energy to finish in 10:50 with a dreadful 3h50 marathon.
Still a decent performance in the grand scheme of things, of course, being 71 overall. But only 13th in my AG, far from the slots, and a poorly executed race indeed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Roll on 2016 and IM South Africa!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IM Wales has to be the hardest race I’ve ever done by far. I doubt I’ll do it again to try and qualify given how hard the swim is, and it’s just a shame my health didn’t allow me to be in the right place. But this is also the most awesome race I’ve ever done. If want to do it: go for it! The people on course, and the sense of achievement at the end will surpass anything you’ve experienced until now!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are ironmans. There are hard ironmans. Then there is ironman Wales…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;table_container&quot;&gt;
    &lt;table&gt;
        &lt;thead&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
                &lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
                &lt;th&gt;time&lt;/th&gt;
                &lt;th&gt;GPS data&lt;/th&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;/thead&gt;
        &lt;tbody&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;Swim (3.8Km)&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;1h13'39&quot;&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;swim data&quot; href=&quot;https://connect.garmin.com/modern/activity/898718055/1&quot;&gt;data&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;T1&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;8'29&quot;&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;T1 data&quot; href=&quot;https://connect.garmin.com/modern/activity/898718055/2&quot;&gt;data&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;Bike (180km)&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;5h34'54&quot;&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;bike data&quot; href=&quot;https://connect.garmin.com/modern/activity/898747893/3&quot;&gt;data&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;T2&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;3'26&quot;&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;Run (42.2Km)&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;3h50'12&quot;&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;run data&quot; href=&quot;https://connect.garmin.com/modern/activity/898747893/5&quot;&gt;data&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;Finish&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;10h50'50&quot;&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;71st overall, 13th in M30-34&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;/tbody&gt;
    &lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;gallery&quot;&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-09-17-ironman-wales-tenby/IMG_4724.png&quot; title=&quot;IMG_4724_r300.png&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[ironman-wales-tenby]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-09-17-ironman-wales-tenby/IMG_4724_r300.png&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_4724_r300.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-09-17-ironman-wales-tenby/01.JPG&quot; title=&quot;01_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[ironman-wales-tenby]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-09-17-ironman-wales-tenby/01_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;01_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-09-17-ironman-wales-tenby/02.JPG&quot; title=&quot;02_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[ironman-wales-tenby]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-09-17-ironman-wales-tenby/02_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;02_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-09-17-ironman-wales-tenby/03.JPG&quot; title=&quot;03_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[ironman-wales-tenby]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-09-17-ironman-wales-tenby/03_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;03_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-09-17-ironman-wales-tenby/04.JPG&quot; title=&quot;04_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[ironman-wales-tenby]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-09-17-ironman-wales-tenby/04_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;04_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-09-17-ironman-wales-tenby/05.JPG&quot; title=&quot;05_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[ironman-wales-tenby]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-09-17-ironman-wales-tenby/05_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;05_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-09-17-ironman-wales-tenby/06.JPG&quot; title=&quot;06_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[ironman-wales-tenby]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-09-17-ironman-wales-tenby/06_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;06_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-09-17-ironman-wales-tenby/07.JPG&quot; title=&quot;07_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[ironman-wales-tenby]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-09-17-ironman-wales-tenby/07_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;07_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-09-17-ironman-wales-tenby/08.JPG&quot; title=&quot;08_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[ironman-wales-tenby]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-09-17-ironman-wales-tenby/08_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;08_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-09-17-ironman-wales-tenby/09.JPG&quot; title=&quot;09_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[ironman-wales-tenby]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-09-17-ironman-wales-tenby/09_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;09_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-09-17-ironman-wales-tenby/10.JPG&quot; title=&quot;10_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[ironman-wales-tenby]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-09-17-ironman-wales-tenby/10_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;10_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-09-17-ironman-wales-tenby/11.JPG&quot; title=&quot;11_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[ironman-wales-tenby]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-09-17-ironman-wales-tenby/11_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;11_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-09-17-ironman-wales-tenby/12.JPG&quot; title=&quot;12_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[ironman-wales-tenby]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-09-17-ironman-wales-tenby/12_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;12_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-09-17-ironman-wales-tenby/13.JPG&quot; title=&quot;13_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[ironman-wales-tenby]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-09-17-ironman-wales-tenby/13_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;13_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-09-17-ironman-wales-tenby/14.JPG&quot; title=&quot;14_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[ironman-wales-tenby]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-09-17-ironman-wales-tenby/14_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;14_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-09-17-ironman-wales-tenby/15.JPG&quot; title=&quot;15_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[ironman-wales-tenby]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-09-17-ironman-wales-tenby/15_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;15_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-09-17-ironman-wales-tenby/16.JPG&quot; title=&quot;16_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[ironman-wales-tenby]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-09-17-ironman-wales-tenby/16_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;16_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-09-17-ironman-wales-tenby/17.JPG&quot; title=&quot;17_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[ironman-wales-tenby]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-09-17-ironman-wales-tenby/17_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;17_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-09-17-ironman-wales-tenby/18.JPG&quot; title=&quot;18_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[ironman-wales-tenby]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-09-17-ironman-wales-tenby/18_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;18_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-09-17-ironman-wales-tenby/19.JPG&quot; title=&quot;19_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[ironman-wales-tenby]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-09-17-ironman-wales-tenby/19_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;19_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-09-17-ironman-wales-tenby/20.JPG&quot; title=&quot;20_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[ironman-wales-tenby]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-09-17-ironman-wales-tenby/20_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;20_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-09-17-ironman-wales-tenby/21.JPG&quot; title=&quot;21_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[ironman-wales-tenby]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-09-17-ironman-wales-tenby/21_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;21_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-09-17-ironman-wales-tenby/22.JPG&quot; title=&quot;22_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[ironman-wales-tenby]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-09-17-ironman-wales-tenby/22_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;22_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-09-17-ironman-wales-tenby/23.JPG&quot; title=&quot;23_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[ironman-wales-tenby]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-09-17-ironman-wales-tenby/23_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;23_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-09-17-ironman-wales-tenby/24.JPG&quot; title=&quot;24_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[ironman-wales-tenby]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-09-17-ironman-wales-tenby/24_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;24_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-09-17-ironman-wales-tenby/25.JPG&quot; title=&quot;25_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[ironman-wales-tenby]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-09-17-ironman-wales-tenby/25_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;25_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-09-17-ironman-wales-tenby/26.JPG&quot; title=&quot;26_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[ironman-wales-tenby]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-09-17-ironman-wales-tenby/26_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;26_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-09-17-ironman-wales-tenby/28.JPG&quot; title=&quot;28_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[ironman-wales-tenby]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-09-17-ironman-wales-tenby/28_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;28_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-09-17-ironman-wales-tenby/29.JPG&quot; title=&quot;29_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[ironman-wales-tenby]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-09-17-ironman-wales-tenby/29_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;29_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-09-17-ironman-wales-tenby/30.JPG&quot; title=&quot;30_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[ironman-wales-tenby]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-09-17-ironman-wales-tenby/30_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;30_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-09-17-ironman-wales-tenby/31.JPG&quot; title=&quot;31_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[ironman-wales-tenby]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-09-17-ironman-wales-tenby/31_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;31_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-09-17-ironman-wales-tenby/32.JPG&quot; title=&quot;32_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[ironman-wales-tenby]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-09-17-ironman-wales-tenby/32_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;32_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-09-17-ironman-wales-tenby/tenby.png&quot; title=&quot;tenby_r300.png&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[ironman-wales-tenby]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-09-17-ironman-wales-tenby/tenby_r300.png&quot; alt=&quot;tenby_r300.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
                <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2015 19:43:00 +0100</pubDate>
                <link>http://tri.ekynoxe.com/ironman-wales-tenby</link>
                <author>hello@ekynoxe.com (Mathieu Davy)</author>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://tri.ekynoxe.com/ironman-wales-tenby</guid>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Ironman UK - Bolton</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;After good results in Lanzarote the last two years, I was on the hunt to find the right race to try and qualify for Kona. With a fair amount of travels for my last races, this year&amp;rsquo;s long races were going to be on home soil, especially if I manage to qualify and have to finance a trip to the big island quickly!
With this in mind Bolton was race 1, and IM Wales is going to be the &amp;ldquo;back-up&amp;rdquo; qualifying event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-07-20-ironman-uk-bolton/run_01.JPG&quot; title=&quot;run_01.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[im_uk_2015_1]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-07-20-ironman-uk-bolton/run_01.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;run_01.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;!--more--&gt;


&lt;p&gt;My racking race prep went alright, with the only annoying thing being that the organisation stopped giving bike covers when I racked, because of the weather forecast and the wind announced for the night. This may well be one of the root cause of the problems I experienced on the bike on race day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the swim, I seeded myself somewhere mid-pack in the 1h - 1h10 pen (rolling start from this year on), based on what I believe I could achieve based on training progression: 1h05. But that time bracket was just stupidly big from the organisation: there are a lot of people who will come out of the water between 60 and 70min!
The gun went, and things took some time to get moving. I really didn&amp;rsquo;t see where the timing mat was either, so I had no idea when my race actually started.
I opted to go for a straight line out to the first Orange buoy as the yellow ones were not on a straight line so it was probably a bit shorter that way :-)
But despite not making too many mistakes direction wise, turning bang on all buoys, and feeling really good and strong in the swim, that didn&amp;rsquo;t pay off at all and I exited the water in 1h09.
The rain started to lash down on my second lap, we couldn&amp;rsquo;t see anything on the water anymore, so that may have played a role in my crap swim.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;T1 was uneventful, bar a few slippages on the mud in bare feet, but I&amp;rsquo;m pleased with it and I&amp;rsquo;m definitely pleased I used my arm warmers. Even wet, they helped a lot. For the first time, I used the &amp;ldquo;donuts&amp;rdquo; technique, and that worked really, really well!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-07-20-ironman-uk-bolton/bike_02.JPG&quot; title=&quot;bike_02.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[im_uk_2015_1]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-07-20-ironman-uk-bolton/bike_02.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;bike_02.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I couldn&amp;rsquo;t see anything on the bike to start with, with my sunglasses being too dark under the dark clouds, and completely steamed up with the rain, so I removed them until I reach Chorley new road in Bolton!
By that time, I already had time to realise my rear brake was rubbing, and my power meter wasn&amp;rsquo;t working.
I tried everything with the brakes, but couldn&amp;rsquo;t release the cable more than it was, so I guess something&amp;rsquo;s banged the rear wheel in transition and whacked the wheel bearings. Looking at it now, my rear wheel is still true, but there&amp;rsquo;s a fair amount of play in the axle, which wasn&amp;rsquo;t there before the race.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My power meter was also completely on crack! It seems that I did the whole ride at 164W NP and 147W average!! I tried to zero and calibrate it mid ride, but to no avail. Since that was also working fine on Saturday, I now think the rain overnight didn&amp;rsquo;t help, and that&amp;rsquo;s why I&amp;rsquo;m not best pleased with rain covers not being given and being removed from the bikes overnight!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ride itself was interesting, a bit more like swimming for an extra 2 hours. I was cold, and with much teeth rattling, I bit my tongue twice in the first hour. I SERIOUSLY thought about calling it a day when I was in Bolton on my way to the laps. The hotel was right there, on the right at the roundabout, and a hot shower was very tempting!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rest of the ride was quite uneventful, really. Windy and rainy to start with, but having recced the route a few weeks before, there weren&amp;rsquo;t any surprises. I was keeping nutrition going in and concentrating on RPE and doing mathematics to judge my average speed. My HR was also pretty low, so I don&amp;rsquo;t think it was reliable either in the cold&amp;hellip;
It turned out I should / could have pushed more on the second lap as it was about 3min slower than on the first, while I was still feeling very good. Looking at HR and power now, I&amp;rsquo;m sure having those working alright would have helped identify that I was taking it a bit too easy as I was feeling really good after the sun came out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the course and the crap roads, it&amp;rsquo;s probably the first time I&amp;rsquo;ve been comfortable for pretty much the whole ride!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;T2 was possibly a bit slow, but that allowed me to setup alright for the run. I didn&amp;rsquo;t even realise at the time, but I kept my arm warmers for the first 5K, and gave them to Ellen at the first special needs, 16Ks in!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started the run very, very lonely! I&amp;rsquo;ve never been in that position before and it was quite strange to see no one in town and for the first 16Ks!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was feeling good and not looking much at my watch and pace, especially with those nasty little climbs after the run along the river. In retrospect, I probably could have pushed a bit more on the first lap, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t know the course (big mistake!). Something clicked on the second lap, in the long descent towards town, and I felt like I could really open it up. That felt great! I&amp;rsquo;ve had to walk a couple of aid stations and once on the steep incline of Chorley Street, but I&amp;rsquo;m very pleased with that run overall. 3h19 on that course is a fantastic achievement and an IM PB by over 6 minutes.
Obviously, not working as hard on the bike has helped a fair bit to set me up for that run!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-07-20-ironman-uk-bolton/run_18.JPG&quot; title=&quot;run_18.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[im_uk_2015_1]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-07-20-ironman-uk-bolton/run_18.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;run_18.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;However, with the start format, it was pretty much impossible to know who was ahead or behind, and I didn&amp;rsquo;t really realise I was that close to the pointy end either. Crossing the line in 10h06 didn&amp;rsquo;t surprise me too much, as I though I could get under 10 before the race, and if I had, I would have qualified, but it wasn&amp;rsquo;t to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It turns out that being 26th overall including all pros, I was still 9th in my age group, which turned out some ridiculously competitive times. I&amp;rsquo;d have qualified out-right in 25-29 or in 35-39, but in 30-24, slots rolled down only to 7th.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Obviously, I&amp;rsquo;m gutted I missed out on qualification, being so far up the race on the day, but it highlights again that my swim is poor.
Again, something to work on in the summer, but I&amp;rsquo;ll remember that race as my best executed race to date.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Roll on Ironman Wales!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;table_container&quot;&gt;
    &lt;table&gt;
        &lt;thead&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
                &lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
                &lt;th&gt;time&lt;/th&gt;
                &lt;th&gt;GPS data&lt;/th&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;/thead&gt;
        &lt;tbody&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;Swim (3.8Km)&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;1h09'20&quot;&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;swim data&quot; href=&quot;https://connect.garmin.com/modern/activity/838183928/1&quot;&gt;data&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;T1&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;4'20&quot;&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;t1 data&quot; href=&quot;https://connect.garmin.com/modern/activity/838183928/2&quot;&gt;data&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;Bike (180km)&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;5h29'05&quot;&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;bike data&quot; href=&quot;https://connect.garmin.com/modern/activity/838183928/3&quot;&gt;data&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;T2&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;3'41&quot;&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;t2 data&quot; href=&quot;https://connect.garmin.com/modern/activity/838183928/4&quot;&gt;data&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;Run (42.2Km)&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;3h19'36&quot;&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;run data&quot; href=&quot;https://connect.garmin.com/modern/activity/838183928/5&quot;&gt;data&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;Finish&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;10h06'02&quot;&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;26th overall, 9th in M30-34&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;/tbody&gt;
    &lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;gallery&quot;&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-07-20-ironman-uk-bolton/swim_1.JPG&quot; title=&quot;swim_1_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[im_uk_2015]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-07-20-ironman-uk-bolton/swim_1_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;swim_1_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-07-20-ironman-uk-bolton/swim_2.JPG&quot; title=&quot;swim_2_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[im_uk_2015]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-07-20-ironman-uk-bolton/swim_2_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;swim_2_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-07-20-ironman-uk-bolton/swim_3.JPG&quot; title=&quot;swim_3_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[im_uk_2015]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-07-20-ironman-uk-bolton/swim_3_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;swim_3_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-07-20-ironman-uk-bolton/bike_01.JPG&quot; title=&quot;bike_01_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[im_uk_2015]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-07-20-ironman-uk-bolton/bike_01_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;bike_01_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-07-20-ironman-uk-bolton/bike_02.JPG&quot; title=&quot;bike_02_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[im_uk_2015]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-07-20-ironman-uk-bolton/bike_02_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;bike_02_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-07-20-ironman-uk-bolton/bike_03.JPG&quot; title=&quot;bike_03_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[im_uk_2015]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-07-20-ironman-uk-bolton/bike_03_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;bike_03_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-07-20-ironman-uk-bolton/bike_04.JPG&quot; title=&quot;bike_04_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[im_uk_2015]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-07-20-ironman-uk-bolton/bike_04_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;bike_04_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-07-20-ironman-uk-bolton/bike_05.JPG&quot; title=&quot;bike_05_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[im_uk_2015]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-07-20-ironman-uk-bolton/bike_05_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;bike_05_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-07-20-ironman-uk-bolton/bike_06.JPG&quot; title=&quot;bike_06_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[im_uk_2015]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-07-20-ironman-uk-bolton/bike_06_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;bike_06_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-07-20-ironman-uk-bolton/bike_07.JPG&quot; title=&quot;bike_07_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[im_uk_2015]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-07-20-ironman-uk-bolton/bike_07_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;bike_07_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-07-20-ironman-uk-bolton/bike_08.JPG&quot; title=&quot;bike_08_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[im_uk_2015]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-07-20-ironman-uk-bolton/bike_08_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;bike_08_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-07-20-ironman-uk-bolton/bike_09.JPG&quot; title=&quot;bike_09_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[im_uk_2015]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-07-20-ironman-uk-bolton/bike_09_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;bike_09_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-07-20-ironman-uk-bolton/bike_10.JPG&quot; title=&quot;bike_10_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[im_uk_2015]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-07-20-ironman-uk-bolton/bike_10_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;bike_10_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-07-20-ironman-uk-bolton/bike_11.JPG&quot; title=&quot;bike_11_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[im_uk_2015]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-07-20-ironman-uk-bolton/bike_11_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;bike_11_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-07-20-ironman-uk-bolton/bike_12.JPG&quot; title=&quot;bike_12_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[im_uk_2015]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-07-20-ironman-uk-bolton/bike_12_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;bike_12_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-07-20-ironman-uk-bolton/bike_13.JPG&quot; title=&quot;bike_13_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[im_uk_2015]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-07-20-ironman-uk-bolton/bike_13_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;bike_13_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-07-20-ironman-uk-bolton/bike_14.JPG&quot; title=&quot;bike_14_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[im_uk_2015]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-07-20-ironman-uk-bolton/bike_14_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;bike_14_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-07-20-ironman-uk-bolton/bike_15.JPG&quot; title=&quot;bike_15_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[im_uk_2015]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-07-20-ironman-uk-bolton/bike_15_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;bike_15_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-07-20-ironman-uk-bolton/bike_16.JPG&quot; title=&quot;bike_16_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[im_uk_2015]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-07-20-ironman-uk-bolton/bike_16_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;bike_16_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-07-20-ironman-uk-bolton/bike_17.JPG&quot; title=&quot;bike_17_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[im_uk_2015]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-07-20-ironman-uk-bolton/bike_17_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;bike_17_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-07-20-ironman-uk-bolton/bike_18.JPG&quot; title=&quot;bike_18_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[im_uk_2015]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-07-20-ironman-uk-bolton/bike_18_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;bike_18_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-07-20-ironman-uk-bolton/run_01.JPG&quot; title=&quot;run_01_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[im_uk_2015]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-07-20-ironman-uk-bolton/run_01_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;run_01_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-07-20-ironman-uk-bolton/run_02.JPG&quot; title=&quot;run_02_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[im_uk_2015]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-07-20-ironman-uk-bolton/run_02_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;run_02_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-07-20-ironman-uk-bolton/run_03.JPG&quot; title=&quot;run_03_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[im_uk_2015]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-07-20-ironman-uk-bolton/run_03_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;run_03_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-07-20-ironman-uk-bolton/run_04.JPG&quot; title=&quot;run_04_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[im_uk_2015]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-07-20-ironman-uk-bolton/run_04_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;run_04_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-07-20-ironman-uk-bolton/run_05.JPG&quot; title=&quot;run_05_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[im_uk_2015]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-07-20-ironman-uk-bolton/run_05_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;run_05_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-07-20-ironman-uk-bolton/run_06.JPG&quot; title=&quot;run_06_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[im_uk_2015]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-07-20-ironman-uk-bolton/run_06_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;run_06_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-07-20-ironman-uk-bolton/run_07.JPG&quot; title=&quot;run_07_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[im_uk_2015]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-07-20-ironman-uk-bolton/run_07_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;run_07_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-07-20-ironman-uk-bolton/run_08.JPG&quot; title=&quot;run_08_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[im_uk_2015]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-07-20-ironman-uk-bolton/run_08_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;run_08_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-07-20-ironman-uk-bolton/run_09.JPG&quot; title=&quot;run_09_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[im_uk_2015]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-07-20-ironman-uk-bolton/run_09_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;run_09_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-07-20-ironman-uk-bolton/run_10.JPG&quot; title=&quot;run_10_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[im_uk_2015]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-07-20-ironman-uk-bolton/run_10_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;run_10_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-07-20-ironman-uk-bolton/run_11.JPG&quot; title=&quot;run_11_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[im_uk_2015]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-07-20-ironman-uk-bolton/run_11_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;run_11_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-07-20-ironman-uk-bolton/run_12.JPG&quot; title=&quot;run_12_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[im_uk_2015]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-07-20-ironman-uk-bolton/run_12_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;run_12_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-07-20-ironman-uk-bolton/run_13.JPG&quot; title=&quot;run_13_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[im_uk_2015]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-07-20-ironman-uk-bolton/run_13_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;run_13_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-07-20-ironman-uk-bolton/run_14.JPG&quot; title=&quot;run_14_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[im_uk_2015]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-07-20-ironman-uk-bolton/run_14_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;run_14_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-07-20-ironman-uk-bolton/run_15.JPG&quot; title=&quot;run_15_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[im_uk_2015]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-07-20-ironman-uk-bolton/run_15_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;run_15_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-07-20-ironman-uk-bolton/run_16.JPG&quot; title=&quot;run_16_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[im_uk_2015]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-07-20-ironman-uk-bolton/run_16_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;run_16_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-07-20-ironman-uk-bolton/run_17.JPG&quot; title=&quot;run_17_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[im_uk_2015]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-07-20-ironman-uk-bolton/run_17_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;run_17_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-07-20-ironman-uk-bolton/run_18.JPG&quot; title=&quot;run_18_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[im_uk_2015]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-07-20-ironman-uk-bolton/run_18_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;run_18_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-07-20-ironman-uk-bolton/run_19.JPG&quot; title=&quot;run_19_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[im_uk_2015]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-07-20-ironman-uk-bolton/run_19_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;run_19_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-07-20-ironman-uk-bolton/run_20.JPG&quot; title=&quot;run_20_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[im_uk_2015]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-07-20-ironman-uk-bolton/run_20_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;run_20_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-07-20-ironman-uk-bolton/run_21.JPG&quot; title=&quot;run_21_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[im_uk_2015]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-07-20-ironman-uk-bolton/run_21_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;run_21_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-07-20-ironman-uk-bolton/run_22.JPG&quot; title=&quot;run_22_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[im_uk_2015]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-07-20-ironman-uk-bolton/run_22_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;run_22_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-07-20-ironman-uk-bolton/run_23.JPG&quot; title=&quot;run_23_r300.JPG&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[im_uk_2015]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-07-20-ironman-uk-bolton/run_23_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;run_23_r300.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-07-20-ironman-uk-bolton/bolton.png&quot; title=&quot;bolton_r300.png&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[im_uk_2015]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-07-20-ironman-uk-bolton/bolton_r300.png&quot; alt=&quot;bolton_r300.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
                <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2015 14:05:00 +0100</pubDate>
                <link>http://tri.ekynoxe.com/ironman-uk-bolton</link>
                <author>hello@ekynoxe.com (Mathieu Davy)</author>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://tri.ekynoxe.com/ironman-uk-bolton</guid>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Ironman 70.3 Mallorca</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I registered last year to be part of the Black Line London &amp;ldquo;special place in the sun&amp;rdquo; - its birthplace on the island of Mallorca - and have a nice warm race before concentrating on the final preparations for Ironman UK in July.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-05-09-ironman-70-dot-3-mallorca/bike5.JPG&quot; title=&quot;Bike 5&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[mallorca_70.3_2015]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-05-09-ironman-70-dot-3-mallorca/bike5_r500.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Bike 5&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;!--more--&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Having raced the &lt;a href=&quot;/triathlon-internacional-portocolom-111-2015/&quot;&gt;Portocolom 111 triathlon&lt;/a&gt; 4 weeks ago, with a very good result, I was expecting to do reasonably well for the 70.3, but being realistic that this race is usually pretty fast, and with a massive field. Realistically, the top spots were out of reach (with top 10 in 30-34 last year all being faster than 4h30') but recent swim tests and a reasonable progression through the winter in the other two disciplines also indicated that I shouldn&amp;rsquo;t do too badly, if I could muster the hot run with little heat adaptation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting to transition for 6:30 am wasn&amp;rsquo;t too bad, and the usual butterflies made me smile. That&amp;rsquo;s race morning for me: a bit of apprehension, a lot of excitement and the general calm before the storm.
After the usual bike final prep with shoes, nutrition and wishing a great race to the few I saw in the biggest transition zone on earth, I headed to the beach for a bit of a warmup, then watch the pros and ladies get on their way before joining the start pen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found myself very close to the front of my wave, right on the left, on the second row. That&amp;rsquo;s now more by habit than a very conscious decision, but it&amp;rsquo;s the best thing to do for me. Still being an &amp;ldquo;average&amp;rdquo; swimmer (relative to my overall results), the first 200m sprint was painful to get into my stroke, but to my surprise, I got clear water pretty much from the start. Waves starts, and dividing some AGs in halves, probably helped. A few taps on the toes here and there, and a few athletes swimming into me (or the other way around!) were really the biggest troubles I had through a swim that I was expecting to be a lot harder.
I rounded the buoys feeling strong, swimming straight, and catching up people from the previous waves. The way back to shore was completed pretty much alone, except for one crazy fast swimmer on whose feet I tried to jump on. But the speed difference was so great that in two strokes, he was gone&amp;hellip; I still have some work to do!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The very shallow water made the exit fun with a bit of dolphin diving.
30'59&quot; at my watch over the timing mat. Feck. Really! I had swum twice at almost 30' dead in the pool over the two previous weeks, so I was hoping to go sub 30 in salty water with a wetsuit&amp;hellip; I still have to convert pool speed to OWS speed, but I&amp;rsquo;ll take that!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On my way to T1, I got massive cheers from Guillem&amp;rsquo;s girlfriend (a local friend) and other supporters recognising the Black Line London kit which was great to push through the long transition.
Long in distance, but well managed. It&amp;rsquo;s impressive to realise how far I&amp;rsquo;ve come from the first races I did back in 2008, where I had a crazy amount of stuff in my T1 bag&amp;hellip; Now: glasses, helmet, run to get the bike, done!
I was blocked a little bit by some slow-pokes skating around on their shoes cleats, but nothing major and I was soon in my element, starting my come-back towards the front.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The flat way to Pollenca was fast and furious, and all I could think off was to pass as many people as I could before the climb and subsequent descent, to not get blocked there. The very calm conditions in the morning helped the pace and quite quickly, there were very few red bibs left to be seen (faster swimmers in my wave). In fact I had made up almost 40 places in the first 15.5K where the climbing really started!
I pushed on over the climb, and felt really good - albeit a little hot in the speed suit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I caught &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/supergal007&quot;&gt;Tarsh&lt;/a&gt; &amp;frac34; of the way into the climb just as her gears were playing up, and told her to relax and get through it, which she seems to have done.
I kept passing people all the way up, and down before the last little bit of climbing to get to the petrol station.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having recced the course last month with &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/_danielmoll&quot;&gt;Dan&lt;/a&gt; and gone over that descent several times, I knew exactly what to expect. A TT bike isn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily the best handling machine for switchbacks, but that didn&amp;rsquo;t deter me from pushing hard on the descent, and flying past many less confident cyclists.
I don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;ve ever shouted that much on a bike ride before: pretty much all the way from T1 to the top of the climb, I was telling riders to keep right. No prisoners taken, but it paid off and I had almost a clear road through the descent and the rest of the ride.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although appearing mostly flat on the profile, the last 40K are actually not easy. First, there&amp;rsquo;s this nasty little climb and the bad roads before Campanet. I knew they were coming, but that little climb was harder than I remembered it!
Then, the long drags along the back roads were energy sapping, with the headwind that had now lifted, and I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel my best. Power numbers were down, so I think I may have overdone the climb a little bit ;-)
Still, a 2h32' bike split was better than I expected, so I&amp;rsquo;m quite pleased with it. However, given that I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel that great on the second half of the bike, the question was now: &amp;ldquo;Will I be able to run?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like at the Portocolom 111 triathlon last month, T2 was delayed by having to tape my bad toe, and the heat had melted the tape so much I could barely unroll it! I probably lost about a minute faffing around with it. Too bad, but it had to be done, and at least my HR got down before attacking what I was expecting to be an absolute struggle with the heat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shooting of transition at sub 4min/Km I felt really good. Small steps, good cadence, and letting a couple of guys who passed me in T2 go on their way. I could (and I did) catch them later!
The pace was pretty fast for what I usually run, and at some point I even thought that I could get close to my straight half marathon PB. It didn&amp;rsquo;t happen as the pace gradually slowed down, but it was still well beyond my expectations.
Having eaten and drank properly on the bike, going through my 6 gels and one pack of chews, plus a couple bottles of water, I never felt hungry or uneasy on the run. I managed to grab a few cups of coke and water, plus a lot of sponges to cool down, and I have to say that this worked a treat!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest lift was from milking the atmosphere. I caught &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/janehansom&quot;&gt;Jane&lt;/a&gt; pretty early on the run, which did surprise me, but she still went on to win her AG&amp;hellip; What an amazing athlete she is!
I also managed to high-five kids all the way around the first lap while it wasn&amp;rsquo;t too congested. It&amp;rsquo;s always fun, and something I like doing. Hopefully that bit of interaction will help them understand that it&amp;rsquo;s not all about beating the others, but also enjoying the day and having fun!
Then came the &amp;ldquo;Black Line&amp;rdquo; cheers. Racing in the custom kit is fantastic, as you get support all around the course. Some people, I recognised vaguely, some others I had no idea who they were. But hearing &amp;ldquo;go blackline&amp;rdquo; several times a lap certainly helped a lot. Thanks to you all!
Then, on each lap, right before the finish line, were Gary and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/rogerbarr&quot;&gt;Roger&lt;/a&gt;. I don&amp;rsquo;t know how many beers they had before my first passage, if any, but they certainly were shouting louder than anyone else! I felt a boost of energy every time I went through there there, and was very much looking forward to this part of the lap, which was conveniently placed right before the finish chute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last lap got really packed. Very cramped at aid stations and close to impossible to get water or coke. I resorted to only grab sponges and I kept pushing as there was only under 5K to go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s strange, but I distinctly remember thinking &amp;ldquo;Is it really over already?&amp;rdquo;. Is that the sign of a great race? I don&amp;rsquo;t know, but this one will certainly stay a long time in my memory as my best half ironman yet. Not my fastest one, but the best executed one. A 1h27'40&quot; run is about 3min faster than I have ever run on a half IM. And THAT makes me super happy, because I really count on my run to make the difference at IM UK in 10 weeks time!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well done to everyone who raced in Mallorca. And specially to &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/sophie_biggs&quot;&gt;Sophie Biggs&lt;/a&gt; and Tanya Barr for their first triathlon and first 70.3 respectively. Well done to &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/alastairmaher&quot;&gt;Al Maher&lt;/a&gt; for finishing the race in a &amp;ldquo;really not shit&amp;rdquo; time, despite having been taken down by a fellow, out-of-control, competitor on a descent. Well done to the &amp;ldquo;Leister brothers&amp;rdquo; to achieving their goal while flying fluoro yellow cap-flaps around the run!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &amp;ldquo;never again&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;why on earth would anyone want to double the distance&amp;rdquo; thoughts have now subsided. It&amp;rsquo;s time to get back in training for the big one. 10 weeks before a proper, clearly stated, assault at qualifying for the big dance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until then, keep smiling, keep inspiring me and be inspired. Keep cheering your athletes, and go support others if you can. Be part of a team of friends. It&amp;rsquo;s worth it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;table_container&quot;&gt;
    &lt;table&gt;
        &lt;thead&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
                &lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
                &lt;th&gt;time&lt;/th&gt;
                &lt;th&gt;GPS data&lt;/th&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;/thead&gt;
        &lt;tbody&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;Swim (1.9Km)&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;31'06&quot;&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;swim data&quot; href=&quot;https://connect.garmin.com/modern/activity/770043319/1&quot;&gt;data&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;T1&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;4'19&quot;&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;t1 data&quot; href=&quot;https://connect.garmin.com/modern/activity/770043319/2&quot;&gt;data&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;Bike (100km)&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;2h41'43&quot;&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;bike data&quot; href=&quot;https://connect.garmin.com/modern/activity/770043319/3&quot;&gt;data&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;T2&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;3'03&quot;&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;t2 data&quot; href=&quot;https://connect.garmin.com/modern/activity/770043319/4&quot;&gt;data&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;Run (long, 10.44Km)&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;1h27'37&quot;&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;run data&quot; href=&quot;https://connect.garmin.com/modern/activity/770043319/5&quot;&gt;data&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;Finish&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;4h38'09&quot;&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;91th overall, 12th in M30-34&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;/tbody&gt;
    &lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;




&lt;div class=&quot;gallery&quot;&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-05-09-ironman-70-dot-3-mallorca/0_swim_out.JPG&quot; title=&quot;Swim out&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[mallorca_70.3_2015]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-05-09-ironman-70-dot-3-mallorca/0_swim_out_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Swim out.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-05-09-ironman-70-dot-3-mallorca/bike1.JPG&quot; title=&quot;Bike 1&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[mallorca_70.3_2015]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-05-09-ironman-70-dot-3-mallorca/bike1_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Bike 1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-05-09-ironman-70-dot-3-mallorca/bike2.JPG&quot; title=&quot;Bike 2&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[mallorca_70.3_2015]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-05-09-ironman-70-dot-3-mallorca/bike2_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Bike 2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-05-09-ironman-70-dot-3-mallorca/bike3.JPG&quot; title=&quot;Bike 3&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[mallorca_70.3_2015]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-05-09-ironman-70-dot-3-mallorca/bike3_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Bike 3&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-05-09-ironman-70-dot-3-mallorca/bike4.JPG&quot; title=&quot;Bike 4&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[mallorca_70.3_2015]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-05-09-ironman-70-dot-3-mallorca/bike4_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Bike 4&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-05-09-ironman-70-dot-3-mallorca/bike5.JPG&quot; title=&quot;Bike 5&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[mallorca_70.3_2015]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-05-09-ironman-70-dot-3-mallorca/bike5_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Bike 5&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-05-09-ironman-70-dot-3-mallorca/bike6.JPG&quot; title=&quot;Bike 6&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[mallorca_70.3_2015]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-05-09-ironman-70-dot-3-mallorca/bike6_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Bike 6&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-05-09-ironman-70-dot-3-mallorca/run1.JPG&quot; title=&quot;Run 1&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[mallorca_70.3_2015]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-05-09-ironman-70-dot-3-mallorca/run1_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Run 1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-05-09-ironman-70-dot-3-mallorca/run2.JPG&quot; title=&quot;Run 2&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[mallorca_70.3_2015]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-05-09-ironman-70-dot-3-mallorca/run2_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Run2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-05-09-ironman-70-dot-3-mallorca/run3.JPG&quot; title=&quot;Run 3&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[mallorca_70.3_2015]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-05-09-ironman-70-dot-3-mallorca/run3_r300.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Run 3&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
                <pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2015 07:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
                <link>http://tri.ekynoxe.com/ironman-70-dot-3-mallorca</link>
                <author>hello@ekynoxe.com (Mathieu Davy)</author>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://tri.ekynoxe.com/ironman-70-dot-3-mallorca</guid>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Triathlon Internacional Portocolom 111 2015</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Having never been to Mallorca, but knowing that it&amp;rsquo;s the spiritual birth place of &lt;a href=&quot;http://blackline.london&quot; title=&quot;Blackline London&quot;&gt;Black Line London&lt;/a&gt;, I had in mind to go check it out at some point, and I had registered for the 70.3 later in the year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But prior to this, in April, is held what use to be the Tristar race, now known again as the Portocolom triathlon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-04-12-triathlon-internacional-portocolom-111-2015/san-salvador.jpg&quot; title=&quot;san-salvador_r500.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[20150412-portocolom]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-04-12-triathlon-internacional-portocolom-111-2015/san-salvador_r500.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;san-salvador_r500.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;!--more--&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/_danielmoll&quot;&gt;Dan&lt;/a&gt; was going for a trip and racing, and having booked a large accommodation, he invited me to come along.
That was the perfect gig to test the legs early in the season, while spending the previous week enjoying a bit of warmer weather than in the UK!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That week was spent in a gorgeous little village called Campanet, very close to Caimari and the foothills of the climb to Lluc. Conveniently, this is part of the 2015 bike course for the 70.3, so going up and down Lluc from either side a few times during the week would prove invaluable for the 70.3.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Protocolm race has been going on since 1998 under the Triathlon Protocolom name, before it became Tristar Mallorca in 2011, then back to its original name after 2013. Limited to 1000 participants, it is held on fully closed roads, with (if you do the 111) two ascents of the Sant Salvador climb. This has been by far the best race I&amp;rsquo;ve done outside the UK for it&amp;rsquo;s friendliness, relatively low key, easy, and relaxed attitude. Forget M-dot branding all over the place, this race is about making sure everyone has a blast, and with support like there was in town for the run and the small villages around the bike course, it&amp;rsquo;s a fantastic race I&amp;rsquo;d recommend anyone who would want to kick start their season early.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The swim start is in deep water, but you first have to jump of the jetty. That&amp;rsquo;s a pretty high jump and I even managed to touch the bottom, before heading out to the &amp;ldquo;start&amp;rdquo;.
The relaxed attitude meant that everyone started to swim their race right after they jumped in, without a care in the world for the guys behind not being in the water yet. Cue quite a lot of hopeless shouting from the RD in a boat, a bit of confusion here and there, and eventually letting everyone go&amp;hellip;
I managed to bump into the RD&amp;rsquo;s boat as it had also drifted in everyone&amp;rsquo;s path, but the rest of the swim was pretty easy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t think I swam too bad at the time. 17min for 1K is what I can do in the pool so I was pleased for one of my first open water swims this year. I have no idea what my Garmin did, recording around 800m, but I was bang on the buoys and feeling good all the way.
The finish and exit was mayhem again as everyone ignored the last buoy and the left turn towards the pontoon, instead heading straight to shore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;T1 was probably quite long by any Olympic distance standard, having to run all the way around one bit of the marina, but pretty easy to navigate! I&amp;rsquo;m used to separate bags for T1 and T2, so having everything in the tiniest boxes you&amp;rsquo;ll find anywhere was a challenge for me. Other than that: nothing to report.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the bike I went straight to work. Having ridden the route with Dan a few days before, I knew where I could lift a bit, and the start was certainly not one of those places! You have to climb out of town first thing out of T1, so that keeps you heart rate up until the right turn going North East.
Then for a few twisty, snappy, bits before reaching one of the danger places of the course: a small village called San Marcià. In tehre, you are essentially going full speed, and have to take a deceivingly tight right-hander, with a few drain covers on the inside and gravel all around. I almost came off at this point, and I lifted heavily on the second lap to avoid it. Some other guys weren&amp;rsquo;t as lucky.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you&amp;rsquo;re over the north east part of the loop, you head back south-west towards THE climb. but before you reach it, you&amp;rsquo;ve got to deal with the very open wide roads, and the strong headwind that will sap your energy just enough to kill your legs right before they matter the most: the Sant Salvador monastery gradients. Categorised as a CAT2 climb, it&amp;rsquo;s not very long at around 5-6K counting the lower parts, but it&amp;rsquo;s a proper mountain in the middle of an otherwise relatively flat (okay, undulating&amp;hellip;) 50K TT loop. I settled into a nice rhythm on the way up, and managed to be on my way down before an ambulance clogged to road for people behind.
Sadly someone pushing hard at the front had an off at one of the hairpins and wasn&amp;rsquo;t in a great shape.
After the first ascent and descent, I had to lift a bit on the power as I was well over my 220W target (NP of 241 at this point, with a max 20min of 256W&amp;hellip; Whoops!).
As expected, having pushed hard on the first lap, the second one was a little slower, but on the second ascent, I counted that I was in 18th position and catching the front runners.
That gave me an amazing boost, as I wasn&amp;rsquo;t expecting at all to be that far up the rankings on a fast course!
The headwind was even stronger on the way back that second time, but the fully closed roads meant that I was riding completely on my own, on empty roads, and able to chose my line like the pros do on TTs. No one to get in the way, and no drafting idiots!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The dismount line for T2 was way more forward than I expected, and I almost didn&amp;rsquo;t make it! That will teach me not to check everything before the race. My rear tire remembers it, having locked the wheel and skidded the end!
I lost a couple of places in transition due to having to tape my injured toe, but that was planned, and I was soon on my way for, I hoped, fast 10K.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was April, but it was already very hot, and I was feeling like I was overheating in the speed suit. I got told off by an official on a bike for having it open, so I reluctantly closed it again, and kept dousing myself in water at every aid station.
The run course has a nasty sting in the tail at the far end. The little climb over there is steep indeed, but I kept going and kept to my ~4'/km pace.
I was passed only twice. The first guy was the eventual winner of the other race, the 55, that had started after us, and the second one was Andrew Woodroffe who&amp;rsquo;s an U23 ITU racer and more used to that distance. I could hear him coming, but I had nothing left to answer his move with 500m to go. The speed difference was big though, as he ran the equivalent of 36'46&quot; for a 10K. Had the run been the right distance (My Garmin said 10.44Km), maybe I&amp;rsquo;d have been able to dig and hold him off. I still ran under 40' for 10K, off a 235W NP 100K ride, so that&amp;rsquo;s pretty cool!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was elated to finish 16th overall in a very early season race, which is a great setup for the next one, in just under a month, again in Mallorca, for the 70.3.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;table_container&quot;&gt;
    &lt;table&gt;
        &lt;thead&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
                &lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
                &lt;th&gt;time&lt;/th&gt;
                &lt;th&gt;GPS data&lt;/th&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;/thead&gt;
        &lt;tbody&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;Swim (1Km)&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;16'54&quot;&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;swim data&quot; href=&quot;https://connect.garmin.com/modern/activity/744547067/1&quot;&gt;data&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;T1&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;1'55&quot;&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;t1 data&quot; href=&quot;https://connect.garmin.com/modern/activity/744547067/2&quot;&gt;data&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;Bike (100km)&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;3h04'55&quot;&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;bike data&quot; href=&quot;https://connect.garmin.com/modern/activity/744547067/3&quot;&gt;data-1&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a title=&quot;bike data&quot; href=&quot;https://connect.garmin.com/modern/activity/744552544/3&quot;&gt;data-2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;T2&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;2'02&quot;&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;t2 data&quot; href=&quot;https://connect.garmin.com/modern/activity/744552544/4&quot;&gt;data&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;Run (long, 10.44Km)&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;41'30&quot;&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;run data&quot; href=&quot;https://connect.garmin.com/modern/activity/744552544/5&quot;&gt;data&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;Finish&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;4h08'39&quot;&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;16th overall, 14th in M30&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;/tbody&gt;
    &lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;




&lt;div class=&quot;gallery&quot;&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-04-12-triathlon-internacional-portocolom-111-2015/attencion.jpg&quot; title=&quot;attencion_r300.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[20150412-portocolom]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-04-12-triathlon-internacional-portocolom-111-2015/attencion_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;attencion_r300.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-04-12-triathlon-internacional-portocolom-111-2015/corner.jpg&quot; title=&quot;corner_r300.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[20150412-portocolom]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-04-12-triathlon-internacional-portocolom-111-2015/corner_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;corner_r300.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-04-12-triathlon-internacional-portocolom-111-2015/end-of-descent.jpg&quot; title=&quot;end-of-descent_r300.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[20150412-portocolom]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-04-12-triathlon-internacional-portocolom-111-2015/end-of-descent_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;end-of-descent_r300.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-04-12-triathlon-internacional-portocolom-111-2015/race-start.jpg&quot; title=&quot;race-start_r300.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[20150412-portocolom]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-04-12-triathlon-internacional-portocolom-111-2015/race-start_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;race-start_r300.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-04-12-triathlon-internacional-portocolom-111-2015/run.jpg&quot; title=&quot;run_r300.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[20150412-portocolom]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-04-12-triathlon-internacional-portocolom-111-2015/run_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;run_r300.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-04-12-triathlon-internacional-portocolom-111-2015/san-salvador-start.jpg&quot; title=&quot;san-salvador-start_r300.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[20150412-portocolom]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-04-12-triathlon-internacional-portocolom-111-2015/san-salvador-start_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;san-salvador-start_r300.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-04-12-triathlon-internacional-portocolom-111-2015/san-salvador.jpg&quot; title=&quot;san-salvador_r300.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[20150412-portocolom]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-04-12-triathlon-internacional-portocolom-111-2015/san-salvador_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;san-salvador_r300.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
    &lt;dl class=&quot;gallery-item&quot;&gt;
        &lt;dt class=&quot;gallery-icon attachement&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-04-12-triathlon-internacional-portocolom-111-2015/start-climb.jpg&quot; title=&quot;start-climb_r300.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[20150412-portocolom]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-04-12-triathlon-internacional-portocolom-111-2015/start-climb_r300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;start-climb_r300.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/dt&gt;
    &lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;



</description>
                <pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2015 08:28:00 +0100</pubDate>
                <link>http://tri.ekynoxe.com/triathlon-internacional-portocolom-111-2015</link>
                <author>hello@ekynoxe.com (Mathieu Davy)</author>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://tri.ekynoxe.com/triathlon-internacional-portocolom-111-2015</guid>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>No toe: no Mudman!</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Accident at home! I don&amp;rsquo;t even have a fun story of dropping a fridge or other heavy equipment on my toe. I just walked straight into a door frame.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not broken, but given how it looks, that means no running for a while, and that means no Mudman next week-end. :-(&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;attachement&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-03-01-no-toe-no-mudman/toe.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Toe&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[2015-03-01_toe]&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.ekynoxe.com/content/2015-03-01-no-toe-no-mudman/toe_r500.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Toe&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
                <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
                <link>http://tri.ekynoxe.com/no-toe-no-mudman</link>
                <author>hello@ekynoxe.com (Mathieu Davy)</author>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://tri.ekynoxe.com/no-toe-no-mudman</guid>
            </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>